<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"><channel><title>WPLG Local 10</title><link>https://www.local10.com</link><atom:link href="https://www.local10.com/arcio/rss/category/news/politics/?size=10" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>WPLG Local 10 News Feed</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:57:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><ttl>1</ttl><sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod><sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency><item><title>US Rep Horn easily captures Democratic nod in 5th District</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/oklahoma-city-voters-to-pare-down-crowded-5th-district-field/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/oklahoma-city-voters-to-pare-down-crowded-5th-district-field/</guid><dc:creator>Associated Press, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:47:48 +0000</pubDate><description>Voters in Oklahoma will pare down a crowded field of congressional hopefuls seeking to represent the state's 5th District in Washington.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. Rep. Kendra Horn easily dispatched her lone opponent Tuesday to capture the Democratic nomination in Oklahoma's 5th Congressional District, while Republicans were paring down a crowded field of congressional hopefuls looking to replace her.</p><p>In the race for Oklahoma’s U.S. Senate seat, incumbent U.S. Sen. Jim Inhofe defeated three GOP challengers and will face Democrat Abby Broyles, an attorney and former television reporter from Oklahoma City who also bested three primary challengers. </p><p>The real challenge for Horn, the only Democrat in Oklahoma's congressional delegation, comes in November. Nine Republicans are vying to replace her. The 44-year-old attorney pulled one of the nation’s biggest congressional upsets in 2018 when she won a seat that had been in Republican hands for four decades. Tuesday she defeated perennial candidate Tom Guild, a retired college professor from Edmond</p><p>Horn is considered one of the most vulnerable Democratic incumbents in the nation because she represents a district President Donald Trump won by nearly 14 points in 2016.</p><p>“I like her and think she's doing a great job," said Darla Ryan, 59, a Democrat who cast her ballot for Horn Tuesday at Life Church in Edmond, Oklahoma. “I voted for her last time, too."</p><p>Four of the GOP challengers have raised more than $500,000, including businesswoman Terry Neese, state Sen. Stephanie Bice, former state education superintendent Janet Barresi and businessman David Hill. The crowded field makes a primary runoff likely.</p><p>Horn has raised more than $3.3 million this cycle, the most of anyone in the state’s delegation.</p><p>While a record number of Oklahomans cast absentee ballots by mail this year, turnout was steady Tuesday at several polling places in the Oklahoma City metro area. At Life Church, most voters were wearing masks and maintaining social distancing in a line that stretched into the parking lot.</p><p>Savannah Steele, 19, a college student from Edmond who was voting for the first time, said the coronavirus pandemic made her uneasy.</p><p>“In Oklahoma, with (the number of reported cases) spiking, that was a concern, but with people staying six feet apart and wearing masks, it was fine," Steele said.</p><p>Two other Republican incumbents, U.S. Reps. Markwayne Mullin and Tom Cole, also won their primaries Tuesday. Republican U.S. Reps. Kevin Hern and Frank Lucas do not have primary opponents. </p><p>Also on the ballot Tuesday is a proposal to amend the Oklahoma Constitution to extend Medicaid health coverage to tens of thousands of low-income residents. Oklahoma is one of 14 states that have not expanded Medicaid — along with neighboring states Texas and Kansas—as part of the 2010 federal Affordable Care Act.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/bryJaTVxu8PudcLhL8kL3GiiK2o=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/MB3BBURLYNG4RDFFFM2FN5XAZQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[File-This May 10, 2018, file photo shows Kendra Horn speaking during a forum for Oklahoma 5th congressional district seat Democratic candidates for the group Edmond Democratic Women in Edmond, Okla. Nine Republicans are vying for the seat held by first-term U.S. Rep. Horn, the only Democrat in the states delegation. The 44-year-old attorney pulled one of the nations biggest congressional upsets in 2018 when she won a seat that had been in Republican hands for four decades. Horn herself also faces a primary opponent in perennial candidate Tom Guild, a retired professor from Edmond. (AP Photo/Sue Ogrocki, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Sue Ogrocki]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/lV6WE016NQVDl6XROHhRZwDbhEg=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/4MROQ25HW5AQPGVJMNGC525JRA.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Hand cleaner for voters after voting at precinct 61 in Edmond, Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Doug Hoke/The Oklahoman via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Doug Hoke]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/I8ZVUGOUt4nXTtG6rmthwFjHkyw=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/JWLWFBD7CNFDDB5LYW5FS6JRQQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Pole worker Bob Tipton hands a ballot to a voter during voting at precinct 61 in Edmond, Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Doug Hoke/The Oklahoman via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Doug Hoke]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/mR7j8vkHXDHG0VE4FpELFRpMAco=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/7KZ5BOWKTFDZLKJ3IH2O4RCRCY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Social distancing for voting at precinct 61 in Edmond, Okla., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Doug Hoke/The Oklahoman via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Doug Hoke]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/SLHqdfAkQVYe1lQICmvrmo-Ndp8=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/UV3NTQQS2NCCHI44GVUGRBPXGU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Jo Shepard collects her ballot at Bixby North Elementary School in Bixby, Okla., on Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Matt Barnard/Tulsa World via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Matt Barnard]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/IUM7I9B-6kzWzUwZobp6Cimnp5I=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/QQPTJHDSIFFZDHGMNB6EOYD2IQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A voter signs in to cast a voting ballot at Canadian Hills Church of the Nazarene on Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Oklahoma City, Okla. (Chris Landsberger/The Oklahoman, via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Chris Landsberger]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/lDPrm-BKGQxXHXybBPqSxE6GieI=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/X2C4RVGNAVHXRLS3BTUZAKPU6E.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Jame Loe, right, signs in voter John Parker at Canadian Hills Church of the Nazarene on Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Oklahoma City, Okla. (Chris Landsberger/The Oklahoman, via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Chris Landsberger]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/YsRQRHuak9qLdDlYgjL1MnbwfoA=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/SG5THQ6YXZBOPMJDDYIM3PWI54.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Precinct worker Carol Monlux signs in Jennifer Blankenship before voting at Wright Elementary School in Tulsa, Okla., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Stephen Pingry/Tulsa World via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Stephen Pingry]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/fhJ-fphR5El6CUBy0Zv3L51OLvI=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/HFO6RDUTL5FNVMCLQYALSZBRYE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Voters collect their ballots at Bixby North Elementary School in Bixby, Okla., on Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Matt Barnard/Tulsa World/Tulsa World via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Matt Barnard]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Oklahoma voters to decide whether to expand Medicaid</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/oklahoma-voters-to-decide-whether-to-expand-medicaid/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/oklahoma-voters-to-decide-whether-to-expand-medicaid/</guid><dc:creator>Associated Press, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:42:11 +0000</pubDate><description>Oklahoma voters are deciding whether to amend the state Constitution to expand Mediciad health coverage to tens of thousands of low-income residents.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oklahoma voters are deciding Tuesday whether to expand Medicaid to tens of thousands of low-income residents and become the first state to amend their Constitution to do so.</p><p>Though an increasing number of Oklahoma voters took advantage of mail-in voting for Tuesday's primary, polls are open from 7 a.m. to 7 p.m. statewide.</p><p>Idaho, Maine, Nebraska and Utah have all expanded Medicaid through ballot questions, but did so by amending state statutes, according to the nonpartisan Kaiser Family Foundation. </p><p>Amending the Oklahoma Constitution would prevent the Republican-controlled Legislature, which has resisted Medicaid expansion for a decade, from tinkering with the program or rolling back coverage. Missouri voters also will decide on a constitutional amendment on Aug. 4.</p><p>State Question 802 would extend Medicaid health insurance to those earning up to 138% of the federal poverty level, which is about $17,200 for an individual or $35,500 for a family of four.</p><p>Oklahoma is one of 14 states, along with neighboring Texas and Kansas, that have not expanded Medicaid under the 2010 federal Affordable Care Act. Republican Gov. Kevin Stitt and his predecessor, Mary Fallin, have opposed expansion, citing uncertainty about future costs for the state.</p><p>“We have a billion-dollar shortfall next year," Stitt said recently at a forum hosted by Americans for Prosperity, a conservative political advocacy group that opposes the measure. The state would have to “either raise taxes or to cut services somewhere else like education, first responders, or roads and bridges” to cut additional Medicaid costs, he said.</p><p>After years of legislative inaction on health insurance proposals, supporters of Medicaid expansion <a href="https://apnews.com/abb64dda7de84544b66d679852aff8a9">launched an initiative petition</a> last year to get the measure on the ballot, and collected a <a href="https://apnews.com/0c5081af1cc44a2bb6282fdb714bf350">record number</a> of signatures. The plan was endorsed by several politically powerful groups, including chambers of commerce, medical trade groups, the Oklahoma Education Association and the Oklahoma Conference of Churches.</p><p>Some Republican opposition to Medicaid expansion has eroded in recent years, particularly in rural areas where hospitals have suffered financial problems or closed. </p><p>Kevin Penry, a Republican and retired pastor from Edmond, said that before going on Medicare last month he had to buy expensive insurance on the federal marketplace, which “really made me feel for folks who are in a difficult financial situation." He said he voted for the expansion.</p><p>The Oklahoma Health Care Authority has projected that about 215,000 residents would qualify for a Medicaid expansion, for a total annual cost of about $1.3 billion. The estimated state share would be about $164 million. But those numbers could be considerably higher given the number of Oklahomans who have lost their jobs and work-related health insurance because of the economic shutdown amid the coronavirus pandemic.</p><p>If the proposal passes, the Legislature is expected to increase a fee that hospitals pay from 2.5% to 4%, which would generate about $134 million annually. Stitt vetoed such a measure earlier this year.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/HiFzJ9xG9bobLba8V-JXNWCeGzQ=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/MCJP67ET7RA7JN7WX5LVIB6PBY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Oct. 24, 2019, file photo, supporters of Yes on 802 Oklahomans Decide Healthcare, calling for Medicaid expansion to be put on the ballot, carry boxes of petitions into the office of the Oklahoma Secretary of State in Oklahoma City. Oklahoma voters will decide Tuesday, June 30, 2020, whether to expand Medicaid to tens of thousands of low-income residents and become the first state to amend their Constitution to do so. (AP Photo/Sue Ogrocki, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Sue Ogrocki]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/EjhHpy5cWME2L69qZ2BDXYJ8eSw=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/NTUM6D72C5HIFFLCYVEZVDOHU4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Amber England, left, campaign manager, Yes on 802, and Russell Griffin, right, campaign field director, check results online after the polls closed Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Oklahoma City, in a vote in which Oklahoma voters are deciding whether to amend the state Constitution to expand Medicaid health coverage to tens of thousands of low-income residents. (AP Photo/Sue Ogrocki)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Sue Ogrocki]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Jdppsjc87isOv1dQU-yVyK20-1Q=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/PFA7BX47L5FLFEW62HWL4BNNBE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Amber England, campaign manager for Yes on 802, addresses supporters via the internet Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Oklahoma City. Supporter awaited results in a virtual watch party as Oklahoma voters decided whether to amend the state Constitution to expand Medicaid health coverage to tens of thousands of low-income residents. (AP Photo/Sue Ogrocki)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Sue Ogrocki]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/pVeKJtTseG48FkkOVFBCehU3jOo=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/ES4I3PVSGZH4NC6NOYJQUDK36Y.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Amber England, campaign manager, Yes on 802, addresses supporters via the internet Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Oklahoma City, as due to Covid-19 concerns, a virtual watch party replaces the normal watch party, as they await results in a vote in which Oklahoma voters are deciding whether to amend the state Constitution to expand Medicaid health coverage to tens of thousands of low-income residents. (AP Photo/Sue Ogrocki)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Sue Ogrocki]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>The Latest: China reports just 3 new virus cases; no deaths </title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/the-latest-s-korea-baseball-fans-will-have-to-wear-masks/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/the-latest-s-korea-baseball-fans-will-have-to-wear-masks/</guid><dc:creator>The Associated Press, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:46:50 +0000</pubDate><description>South Korea’s professional baseball league says it will require fans to wear masks, sit at least a seat apart and prohibit them from eating food in the stands as it prepares to bring back spectators in the coming weeks amid the coronavirus epidemic.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>BEIJING — China has reported just three new confirmed cases of coronavirus, all in the capital Beijing where an outbreak last month appears to have run its course amid intense testing and case tracing.</p><p>No new deaths were reported Wednesday, leaving the toll at 4,634 among 83,534 cases of COVID-19 recorded since the virus was first detected in the central Chinese city of Wuhan late last year.</p><p>The National Health Commission said 421 people are in treatment with another 108 under monitoring for being possible cases or having tested positive for the virus without showing symptoms.</p><p>Beijing has begun discharging those infected in the recent outbreak tied to the Xinfadi wholesale food market in the southwestern suburbs.</p><p>With 328 cases reported since June 11, Beijing has reinstated some prevention measures, suspended classes for schoolchildren and carried out 8.3 million virus tests among the city’s more than 20 million residents.</p><p>___</p><p>HERE’S WHAT YOU NEED TO KNOW ABOUT THE VIRUS OUTBREAK:</p><p>— Experts say the pandemic is <a href="https://apnews.com/911c9cdb10a0319fb5f36dc5ddff9d40">wreaking havoc in poor and war-torn nations.</a></p><p>— Virus cases worldwide <a href="https://apnews.com/5a06549049a5471d510ddde7188eeae9">hit 10 million and deaths have surpassed 500,000.</a></p><p>— UK PM Boris Johnson says <a href="https://apnews.com/c264bede9442cf8ce15a217d4fc54f92">the pandemic “has been a disaster” for Britain.</a></p><p>— <a href="https://apnews.com/9bd6a6ea032c9cbdc025354290a957cc">Hunger stalks Yemen's children </a> as pandemic hits Arab world's poorest nation.</p><p>— Nurses, doctors feel strain as virus <a>races through Arizona.</a></p><p>— The pandemic means <a href="https://apnews.com/a8c9c486e48f0492c6b56cd2c7992d71">millions of women in Africa</a> and other developing regions could lose years of success in contributing to household incomes and asserting their independence.</p><p>___ </p><p>Follow all of AP’s pandemic coverage at <a href="https://apnews.com/VirusOutbreak">http://apnews.com/VirusOutbreak</a> and <a href="https://apnews.com/UnderstandingtheOutbreak">https://apnews.com/UnderstandingtheOutbreak</a></p><p>___</p><p>HERE’S WHAT ELSE IS HAPPENING:</p><p>SALEM, Oregon - Oregon Gov. Kate Brown has extended the COVID-19 state of emergency for 60 days. </p><p>She said as of Tuesday there have been over 8,600 coronavirus cases in the state, with over a quarter of those cases identified in the past two weeks. The Oregon Health Authority said 207 people in Oregon have died from the disease. </p><p>The state of emergency declaration is the legal underpinning for the executive orders Brown has issued throughout the pandemic, including her orders on reopening Oregon, as well as orders related to childcare, schools, and higher education operations. </p><p>Extending the state of emergency declaration allows those orders to stay in effect. She will review and reevaluate each of her emergency orders every 60 days. Brown said this extension will last through Sept. 4.</p><p>___</p><p>CALEXICO, Calif. -- An official says a farming region on California’s border with Mexico has sent hundreds of patients to hospitals outside the area in recent weeks as leaders accept Gov. Gavin Newsom’s recommendation to backpedal on reopening its battered economy. </p><p>Imperial County unveiled a plan that includes closing businesses deemed non-essential and shuttering county parks. </p><p>The Mexican border city of Mexicali has taken its own measures to combat the virus, including a checkpoint for motorists entering from the U.S. that created a seven-hour backup on the U.S. side on Saturday.</p><p>___</p><p>WASHINGTON — Dr. Anthony Fauci said coronavirus cases could grow to 100,000 a day in the U.S. if Americans don’t start following public health recommendations.</p><p>The nation’s leading infectious disease expert made the remark at a Senate hearing on reopening schools and workplaces.</p><p>Asked to forecast the outcome of recent surges in some states, Fauci said he can’t make an accurate prediction but believes it will be “very disturbing.”</p><p>“We are now having 40-plus-thousand new cases a day. I would not be surprised if we go up to to 100,000 a day if this does not turn around, and so I am very concerned,” said Fauci, infectious disease chief at the National Institutes of Health.</p><p>Fauci said areas seeing recent outbreaks are putting the entire nation at risk, including areas that have made progress in reducing COVID-19 cases. He cited recent video footage of people socializing in crowds, often without masks, and otherwise ignoring safety guidelines.</p><p>___</p><p>ROCKVILLE, Md. — Vice President Mike Pence is stressing the country is in a far better position to battle the coronavirus than it was months ago, even as cases continue to rise, especially across the south.</p><p>Pence put a positive spin on the progress at a briefing by the White House’s coronavirus task force at the U.S. Public Health Service Commissioned Corps headquarters in Maryland on Tuesday.</p><p>He says: “’We want to assure you that we’re ready — more ready than ever before — to meet this coronavirus pandemic.”</p><p>Task force members outlined improvements in testing capacity, the availability of protective gear, and new therapeutics even as the U.S. is now reporting about 40,000 new cases daily.</p><p>The comments came hours after the nation’s top infectious diseases expert warned during a congressional hearing that “we’re going in the wrong direction” and said the country could soon see as many as 100,000 new cases a day.</p><p>Still, Pence said the administration fully supports the decision of some states to-shutter certain business or delay reopening efforts due to rising cases.</p><p>The members also urged Americans to abide by public health recommendation, including wearing masks in public, saying they are key to keeping the country open.</p><p>___</p><p>UNITED NATIONS — The United Nations Security Council is trying again to reach agreement on its first resolution on COVID-19 since the coronavirus started circling the globe in February after a lengthy dispute between the U.S. and China over mentioning the World Health Organization.</p><p>A revised draft resolution by France and Tunisia was submitted for a vote Tuesday, and the result is expected to be announced on Wednesday.</p><p>The draft resolution backs Secretary-General Antonio Guterres’ March 23 call for global cease-fires to tackle the pandemic, and demands an “immediate cessation of hostilities” in all conflicts on the council’s agenda including Syria, Yemen, Libya, South Sudan and Congo.</p><p>It calls on all warring parties “to engage immediately in a durable humanitarian pause for at least 90 consecutive days” to enable the safe and unhindered delivery of humanitarian aid and medical evacuations.</p><p>President Donald Trump suspended funding to the World Health Organization in early April, accusing the U.N. health agency of failing to stop the virus from spreading when it first surfaced in China, and accusing WHO of parroting Beijing.</p><p>China strongly supports the WHO and insisted that its role in calling for global action on COVID-19 be included in any resolution, diplomats said, while the U.S. insisted on a reference to “transparency” on COVID-19 and no mention of the WHO.</p><p>The draft being put to a vote doesn’t mention either the WHO, a U.N. health agency or transparency.</p><p>But it does take note of a resolution adopted April 2 by the 193-member U.N. General Assembly which “calls for intensified international cooperation to contain, mitigate and defeat the pandemic, including ... by applying the relevant guidelines recommended by the World Health Organization.”</p><p>___</p><p>COLUMBIA, Mo. — Missouri reached a grim new milestone in its battle with the coronavirus on Tuesday, surpassing 1,000 deaths amid a resurgence of the disease that has seen cases skyrocket in recent weeks.</p><p>“That’s 1,000 people that lost their lives due to COVID-19,” Gov. Mike Parson said Tuesday. “I think we all need to remember that.”</p><p>The state health department raised the death toll by 17, to 1,015, and added more than 500 confirmed cases to the statewide tally, raising it to 21,551 since the pandemic started. The number of confirmed cases has quickly increased since the state reopened for business on June 16, swelling by 10.9% in just the past seven days, health officials said. </p><p>There are no statewide rules on social distancing currently in place in Missouri. Still, health department Director Randall Williams urged people to continue hand washing and social distancing or wearing masks, especially on July 4. </p><p>“Going into this weekend, even if you’re outside, we really, really would encourage you to practice social distancing,” Williams said. </p><p>Despite the worsening situation, the University of Missouri is preparing to welcome back students for on-campus classes this fall. The university said Monday that it will require students, faculty and staff to wear masks in classrooms when on-campus classes resume in August, though those plans could change depending on the coronavirus situation. Parson said he had no plans to issue a statewide order mandating that people wear masks in some circumstances.</p><p>___</p><p>AUSTIN, Texas — As the Texas GOP presses ahead with plans for a July convention amid skyrocketing coronavirus numbers, doctors are urging the party to reconsider.</p><p>Texas again set a high Tuesday for COVID-19 cases with nearly 7,000 confirmed new infections.</p><p>Texas GOP leaders have maintained their three-day convention in Houston will go forward and that face coverings won’t be mandated. That is despite Republican Gov. Greg Abbott urging the public to wear masks and stay home.</p><p>The Texas Medical Association told GOP leaders that now is “not the time to bring thousands of the party faithful from around the state” together for an indoor meeting. </p><p>The organization represents more than 50,000 physicians in Texas and is a sponsor of the convention, which begins July 16.</p><p>Texas GOP Chairman James Dickey responded by saying the party is taking all input seriously but was noncommittal about whether it would change any minds.</p><p>___</p><p>DENVER — Gov. Jared Polis says Colorado will rein in previously set rules for bars and nightlife because of the potential for spreading coronavirus. </p><p>After speaking with the governors from Texas and Arizona, which have seen spikes in new cases, Polis says they believe bars and nightclubs have been major sources of outbreaks, especially among young people. </p><p>Previous rules announced June 18 under Colorado’s “Protect Our Neighbors” program allowed for reduced capacity at 25 percent or 50 people. Under the new modifications, which Polis says will go into effect under the next 48 hours, bars will be closed for in-person service. </p><p>But those with dining options may continue to serve customers and sell takeout alcohol.</p><p>___</p><p>HARRISBURG, Pa. — Philadelphia is bringing a halt to its plans to allow indoor dining, bars, gyms and fitness centers to reopen, with officials saying Tuesday that the city is seeing rising case COVID-19 counts and could be affected by a growing epidemic elsewhere in the country.</p><p>The city’s health commissioner, Dr. Tom Farley, broke the bad news during a news conference ahead of its Friday target to lift more restrictions. </p><p>Hospitalizations are not seeing a corresponding increase, but Farley said that is a lagging indicator.</p><p>Across the state, Allegheny County recorded another single-day record high of new cases reported Tuesday.</p><p>The county, which includes Pittsburgh and is Pennsylvania’s second-most populous with 1.2 million residents, over the weekend ordered a halt to drinking alcohol in bars and restaurants amid what officials there called an “alarming” spike in COVID-19 cases.</p><p>___</p><p>WILMINGTON, Del. — Joe Biden says he has not been tested for COVID-19 yet but expects to be “relatively soon.”</p><p>The presumptive Democratic presidential nominee, speaking to reporters after a campaign event in Delaware on Tuesday, said he hasn’t yet taken a test because “I have had no symptoms” and “I haven’t wanted to take anyone else’s place in the process.” </p><p>He added, however, “so it doesn’t look like I’m moving to the front of the line,” he expects to be tested “relatively soon.”</p><p>Biden said that the Secret Service stationed around his home and anyone who comes into his home, including staff, are tested. He also noted his daughter, who worked in Florida, was tested twice for the coronavirus.</p><p>___</p><p>OTTAWA — The Canadian government says it has extended rules barring most foreign travelers from entering Canada until the end of July as part of efforts to slow the spread of COVID-19. </p><p>The restrictions covering everyone except Canadian citizens and permanent residents — as well as Americans entering Canada for essential reasons — were set to expire at midnight. </p><p>A spokeswoman for the Canada Border Services Agency says all optional or discretionary travel through all ports of entry is covered. </p><p>But there are exceptions to allow in immediate family of Canadian citizens or permanent residents, as well as to cover cases such as flight crews. </p><p>The closure of the Canada-U.S. border to all but essential workers and trade until at least July 21 is covered by a separate order.</p><p>___</p><p>ROME — Italy is still insisting on coronavirus quarantines for visitors from the 14 countries green-lighted by the European Union to visit.</p><p>Health Minister Roberto Speranza said Italy was taking the “line of caution” given its battle to contain the outbreak in the onetime epicenter of Europe’s COVID-19 emergency.</p><p>The EU said Tuesday it would reopen its borders to travelers from 14 countries — Algeria, Australia, Canada, Georgia, Japan, Montenegro, Morocco, New Zealand, Rwanda, Serbia, South Korea, Thailand, Tunisia and Uruguay. </p><p>Chinese visitors are likely to be readmitted soon, but not most from the U.S., where infections are surging.</p><p>Speranza signed an ordinance Tuesday requiring “fiduciary quarantine” for visitors from the 14 countries. He said in a statement: “The situation at the global level remains very complex. We must avoid that the sacrifices made by Italians in these months are in vain.”</p><p>Italy registered its first positive case Feb. 21 and for weeks had the world’s highest death toll. But after a 10-week lockdown and strict hygiene and social distancing measures that are still in force, Italy has largely brought its outbreak under control. On Tuesday for example, Italy registered 23 new victims and 142 new confirmed infections.</p><p>___</p><p>RALEIGH, N.C. — North Carolina has announced plans to test all nursing home patients and workers for the coronavirus.</p><p>Mandy Cohen, the state’s top public health official, said Tuesday that the one-time tests will be given between July and mid-August to help curb the virus.</p><p>Cohen said the state is partnering with CVS Omnicare to test an estimated 36,000 nursing home residents and 25,000 workers in more than 400 sites throughout the state.</p><p>The cost of the program was not immediately provided, but Cohen said when possible insurance will be billed. Otherwise, the costs will be covered by the Department of Health and Human Services.</p><p>Recent statewide data recorded by the public health agency shows 4,440 of the state’s 64,670 laboratory-confirmed coronavirus cases occurred in nursing homes. </p><p>But nursing homes account for 660 of the state’s 1,343 coronavirus deaths.</p><p>___</p><p>WASHINGTON — The head of the Food and Drug Administration says vaccine developers will be expected to study COVID-19 shots in racial minorities, the elderly, pregnant women and those with other health conditions.</p><p>FDA Commissioner Stephen Hahn outlined the guidelines for potential vaccines at a Senate hearing on reopening schools and workplaces.</p><p>Hahn says “while the FDA is committed to help expedite this work, we will not cut corners in our decision-making.”</p><p>The agency has come under criticism for granting emergency authorization to a malaria drug touted by President Donald Trump as a treatment for coronavirus. The agency revoked that designation earlier this month after studies found the drug was ineffective against the virus.</p><p>The U.S. is set to begin a 30,000-person trial of a government-created shot starting next month. Under the Trump administration’s program dubbed “Operation Warp Speed,” health officials aim to have 300 million doses on hand by January.</p><p>About 15 experimental COVID-19 vaccines are in various stages of testing worldwide. There is no guarantee that any will prove effective.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/O5zCPZWyiW-AsRSKYacXtCYR22k=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/ER6V65QGIVFD3G27JBI7JYLJN4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Residents wearing masks to curb the spread of the coronavirus line up for COVID-19 test outside the Worker's Stadium in Beijing on Tuesday, June 30, 2020. Test sites have sprung up through the Chinese capital as test have become a daily normal after the latest outbreak of the coronavirus, (AP Photo/Ng Han Guan)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ng Han Guan]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/K8IHm1k4NxKF15YyTB6ptq4lw4A=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/XABWE3D2XFFABCFABT6IAL6MQY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A security guard checks the body temperature of a men before entry a market, amid coronavirus outbreak in Jakarta, Indonesia Tuesday, June 30, 2020.(AP Photo/Achmad Ibrahim)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Achmad Ibrahim]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/lE-afNVxzFW6TA9yukvjcF03D8o=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/5KPFJJQMCZBS7CIADG4QPV4T7M.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Accessories venders wearing face mask wait customers amid fears of the new coronavirus outbreak at a market in Jakarta, Indonesia Tuesday, June 30, 2020.(AP Photo/Achmad Ibrahim)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Achmad Ibrahim]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/2d0OB4bk3y-AFnnuJgXGXnbT1pE=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/LSMGMWDGRNAP3INJMGGKF3WOZY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A man wearing a protective face mask to help curb the spread of the coronavirus stands against a roll of boats parked on the barricaded Houhai Lake, a usually popular tourist spot before the new coronavirus outbreak in Beijing, Tuesday, June 30, 2020. China, where the coronavirus pandemic began in December, was the first economy to reopen in March after the ruling Communist Party declared victory over the disease. Manufacturing and other activity is reviving but demand for exports is feeble and Chinese consumers, worried about losing jobs, are reluctant to spend. (AP Photo/Andy Wong)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Andy Wong]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/lEn7esQ8P4v_tP1cc_-9XPwL_6o=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/3HCOT5KWEBEENIANCX5JXZECJI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this April 9, 2020, file photo, healthcare workers wheeling a gurney into Salem Hospital's emergency room in Salem, Ore., during the coronavirus outbreak. Oregon health officials reported its second-highest tally of confirmed cases of COVID-19 and five additional deaths on Friday, June 26, 2020, the same day that authorities released new modeling that shows increased transmission of the coronavirus since the state began reopening in mid-May. (AP Photo/Andrew Selsky, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Andrew Selsky]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/1OBed35UKchJ5ejwYRmRN78OF1Q=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/4XQMWENEKVFLPIW3375XI5FAGQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Dr. Anthony Fauci, director of the National Institute for Allergy and Infectious Diseases, testifies before a Senate Health, Education, Labor and Pensions Committee hearing on Capitol Hill in Washington, Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Kevin Dietsch/Pool via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Kevin Dietsch]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/rkAM2hg9ip6K0L9svq-adUHA6e0=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/YFE53ONE4RHCPGX4LX2IQ4MWGQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Dr. Anthony Fauci, director of the National Institute for Allergy and Infectious Diseases, lowers his face mask as he prepares to testify before a Senate Health, Education, Labor and Pensions Committee hearing on Capitol Hill in Washington, Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Kevin Dietsch/Pool via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Kevin Dietsch]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/X8VxVceNW09bl3rnvqvZUhkTTio=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/J6JCBRUYJRHGNLVWLRAZ4O3VSM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Adm. Brett Giroir, left, director of the U.S. coronavirus diagnostic testing, and Food and Drug Administration (FDA) Commissioner Stephen Hahn, prepare to testify before a Senate Health, Education, Labor and Pensions Committee hearing on Capitol Hill in Washington, Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Kevin Dietsch/Pool via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Kevin Dietsch]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/kKL2VsrPEByXM0tKtEGXgj38unM=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/FQB5U55CQNDYTOUFZDJBGWOEPQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Sen. Lamar Alexander, R- Tenn., speaks during a Senate Health, Education, Labor and Pensions Committee hearing on Capitol Hill in Washington, Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Al Drago/Pool via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Al Drago]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/AzCGzeAPZB4wH_ItLRMuTbjAqLw=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/2T2BGWU7WNGKVFVYJ3MWWME4CE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Thursday, May 14, 2020, file photo California Gov. Gavin Newsom discusses his revised 2020-2021 state budget during a news conference in Sacramento, Calif. Gov. Newsom signed a $202.1 billion state budget Monday, June 29, in Sacramento, Calif. The budget closes an estimated $54.3 billion deficit through a combination of spending cuts, internal borrowing and temporary tax increases on businesses. Like most states, California's deficit was driven by the economic downturn caused by the coronavirus. (AP Photo/Rich Pedroncelli, Pool, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rich Pedroncelli]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/CkRdwdUrL5VC6BALVnmD28iWMKw=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/FDKXAB4OLRCPRDJDLBXXQPJDZM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Participants wearing face masks to help protect against the spread of the new coronavirus gesture as they join the "Thank You Challenge" for medical workers fighting the coronavirus during the Yonhap News Symposium on Korean Peace in Seoul, South Korea, Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (AP Photo/Ahn Young-joon)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ahn Young-Joon]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/wFjQQqDJVJGRJEHyrv5ANPHo530=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/DQAQKG575BCGBOSAB2KEGWEPCE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Indonesian soldiers wearing face mask patrol amid fears of the new coronavirus outbreak at a market in Jakarta, Indonesia Tuesday, June 30, 2020.(AP Photo/Achmad Ibrahim)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Achmad Ibrahim]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Biden and Trump agree: November election could be corrupt</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/07/01/biden-and-trump-agree-november-election-could-be-corrupt/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/07/01/biden-and-trump-agree-november-election-could-be-corrupt/</guid><dc:creator>Bill Barrow, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:36:40 +0000</pubDate><description>President Donald Trump and his challenger, Joe Biden, have found something they agree on: The November election could be rife with corruption because of how officials handle the voting process.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Donald Trump and his challenger, Joe Biden, have found something they agree on: The November election could be rife with corruption because of how officials handle the voting process.</p><p>Of course, the Republican incumbent and his Democratic rival place the prospective blame in different places. Each points at the other’s party.</p><p>“I really, really, really believe we’re on the cusp of what could be the most corrupt process that we’ve seen in a general election if we don’t monitor this every single second,” Biden told donors Tuesday evening as he discussed Trump’s and many Republicans’ opposition to expanding early voting and mail-in voting amid the COVID-19 pandemic.</p><p>That’s similar language to what Trump has tweeted to his millions of social media followers in recent weeks. “Mail-in voting … will lead to the most corrupt election in USA history,” Trump declared Sunday.</p><p>The president previously argued that mail-balloting allows voters to “cheat.” One such tweet <a href="https://apnews.com/700c52aab0869253625b80255a397f19">drew a rare, special tag</a> from Twitter that directed readers to mail-voting facts that rebutted the president’s unsupported claims about voter fraud. There are instances of voter fraud in the U.S., most often found in local or smaller jurisdictional elections, but there is no evidence of widespread fraud that would tilt statewide or national results.</p><p>Biden noted Tuesday that Trump himself has voted using mail ballots, most recently using Florida’s absentee process to cast his Republican primary ballot in March. </p><p>Similar word choice aside, Biden’s and Trump’s disparate framing of voting by mail tracks the long-running, largely partisan fight over ballot access and election security. Republicans nationally have pushed aggressive culling of voter rolls, identification requirements that are arduous for some voters, and strict signature and witness rules for absentee ballots. GOP officials cast such rules as necessary fraud prevention; Democrats call them systemic voter suppression. </p><p>“We have got to keep ringing the bell about this all the way to the election,” Biden said, adding that his campaign and the Democratic Party have put together a team of hundreds of lawyers and volunteers to focus on voter protection and education. “It’s the greatest concern I have,” Biden said, “not just for my race, but for races up and down the ballot.” </p><p>Biden singled out Trump’s opposition to injecting federal aid into the <a href="https://apnews.com/d52e51e5392d2f4d32a56a2060446847">U.S. Postal Service</a>. “He’s talking about defunding the post office so they can’t deliver mail-in ballots,” Biden said. </p><p>The postal agency doesn’t actually get direct taxpayer support for normal operations, as Biden's dig suggested. But COVID-19 has devastated its already precarious finances, and Congress has considered an aid package. Trump’s White House blocked one bailout effort earlier this year and wants to attach strings to any taxpayer assistance.</p><p>At the time, Biden said that he believed Trump was pushing a narrative to cloud the results in November should the president lose. Biden went so far in that April 23 event as to <a href="https://apnews.com/6cf3ca7d5a174f2f381636cb4706f505">suggest Trump might attempt</a> to postpone the election. Biden offered no evidence of that claim. </p><p>Besides Trump’s opposition to mail ballots, Biden declared Tuesday that dozens of proposals from state lawmakers around the country amount to “Jim Crow-type efforts to restrict access to voting.” He did not elaborate. But he promised to “restore the Voting Rights Act,” the 1965 civil rights law that, until a 2013 Supreme Court ruling, required many Southern states and some counties outside the South to get federal approval for all changes to election rules and procedures.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/ySgpa6hINxHBV0Ix8XwTFjRlQkU=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/DPJJVFCW2FC5LCFRANVEKUBWUE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this May 28, 2020, file photo a voter casts her mail-in ballot at in a drop box in West Chester, Pa., prior to the primary election. Just over four months before Election Day, President Donald Trump is escalating his efforts to delegitimize the upcoming presidential election. Last week he made a startling, and unfounded, claim that 2020 will be the most corrupt election in the history of our country." (AP Photo/Matt Rourke, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Matt Rourke]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Trump faces pressure over Russia bounties to kill US troops </title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/gop-lawmakers-urge-action-after-russia-afghanistan-briefing/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/gop-lawmakers-urge-action-after-russia-afghanistan-briefing/</guid><dc:creator>Zeke Miller, James Laporta And Mary Clare Jalonick, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 22:46:28 +0000</pubDate><description>Eight Democrats are to be briefed on Tuesday about explosive allegations that Russia secretly offered bounties to Taliban-linked militants for killing American troops in Afghanistan.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Donald Trump on Tuesday came under growing pressure to respond to allegations that Russia offered bounties for killing American troops in Afghanistan, with Democrats demanding answers and accusing Trump of bowing to Russian President Vladimir Putin at the risk of U.S. soldiers' lives.</p><p>Frustrated House Democrats returning from a briefing at the White House said they learned nothing new about American intelligence assessments that suggested Russia was making overtures to militants as the U.S. and the Taliban held talks to end the conflict in Afghanistan. Senate Republicans who attended a separate briefing largely defended the president, arguing along with the White House that the intelligence was unverified.</p><p>The intelligence assessments were first reported by The New York Times, then confirmed to The Associated Press by American intelligence officials and others with knowledge of the matter.</p><p>White House press secretary Kayleigh McEnany said Tuesday that Trump had been briefed on the intelligence, a day after saying he hadn't because it had not been verified. McEnany added that there were still reservations within the intelligence community on the veracity of the allegations.</p><p>“Make no mistake. This president will always protect American troops,” she said.</p><p>Majority Leader Steny Hoyer and a small group of other House Democrats met with White House officials as Trump downplayed the allegations. The Democrats questioned why Trump wouldn't have been briefed sooner and pushed White House officials to have the president make a strong statement about the matter.</p><p>House Intelligence Committee Chairman Adam Schiff, one of the Democrats who attended the briefing, said it was “inexplicable” why <a href="https://apnews.com/da9b215d7ca8405d2e664b04b799304e">Trump won’t say publicly that he is working to get to the bottom of the issue and why he won’t call out Putin</a>. He said Trump’s defense that he hadn't been briefed was inexcusable.</p><p>“Many of us do not understand his affinity for that autocratic ruler who means our nation ill,” Schiff said.</p><p>Rep. Mikie Sherrill, D-N.J., a freshman and former Navy helicopter pilot and Russia policy officer, said White House chief of staff Mark Meadows briefed the group. She said the Democrats told the White House briefers that the president should make a statement.</p><p>“These are very concerning allegations and if they’re true, Russia is going to face repercussions,” Sherrill said. "We really pushed that strongly in the meeting.”</p><p>She wouldn’t say how the White House officials reacted or say if the briefers told the Democrats that in fact Trump had been briefed.</p><p>Trump and his aides set a high bar for briefing a president since it is rare for intelligence to be confirmed without a shadow of doubt before it is presented to senior government decision-makers.</p><p>McEnany declined to say why a different standard of confidence in the intelligence might apply to briefing lawmakers than for bringing information to the president.</p><p>Some House Republicans who were briefed by the White House on Monday also said they left with questions.</p><p>Texas Rep. Mac Thornberry, the top Republican on the Armed Services Committee, said the panel would "leave no stone unturned” in seeking further information. Rep. Liz Cheney of Wyoming insisted there would be “ramifications” for any targeting of Americans.</p><p>But Senate Republicans seemed less concerned and questioned the media reports. Majority Leader Mitch McConnell said he didn't think Trump should be “subjected to every rumor.”</p><p>“Conclusions, apparently, were not reached," McConnell said.</p><p>The White House was working to schedule a briefing for Wednesday with McConnell, House Speaker Nancy Pelosi and the top Republicans and Democrats on the two intelligence committees according to a person familiar with the talks. The person declined to be identified because the so-called “Gang of 8” briefing will be classified. That group receives the most sensitive information in regular meetings with administration officials.</p><p>A separate group of Senate Republicans briefed in the White House Situation Room on Tuesday appeared mostly satisfied with the answers they received. Senate Armed Services Chairman Jim Inhofe of Oklahoma said he was “convinced” Trump hadn't known about the intelligence. Wisconsin Sen. Ron Johnson, chairman of the Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee, said Trump “can’t be made aware of every piece of unverified intelligence.”</p><p>Senate Intelligence Committee Chairman Marco Rubio said he believed the U.S. was prepared "to do everything possible to protect our men or women stationed abroad, from a variety of threats."</p><p>Some Republican senators did express frustration.</p><p>Nebraska Republican Ben Sasse, a member of the intelligence panel, said Monday evening that Congress should focus on finding out who knew what, and when, “and did the commander in chief know? And if not, how the hell not?”</p><p>While Russian meddling in Afghanistan isn’t new, officials said Russian operatives became more aggressive in their desire to contract with the Taliban and members of the Haqqani Network, a militant group aligned with the Taliban in Afghanistan and designated a foreign terrorist organization in 2012.</p><p>The intelligence community has been investigating an April 2019 attack on an American convoy that killed three U.S. Marines after a car rigged with explosives detonated near their armored vehicles as they traveled back to Bagram Airfield, the largest U.S. military installation in Afghanistan, officials told the AP.</p><p>Three other U.S. service members were wounded in the attack, along with an Afghan contractor. The Taliban claimed responsibility for the attack. The officials the AP spoke to also said they were looking closely at insider attacks — sometimes called “green-on-blue” attacks — from 2019 to determine if they are also linked to Russian bounties.</p><p>One official said the administration discussed several potential responses, but the White House has yet to authorize any.</p><p>Intelligence officials told the AP that the White House first became aware of alleged Russian bounties in early 2019 — a year earlier than had been previously reported. The assessments were included in one of Trump’s written daily briefings at the time, and then-National Security Adviser John Bolton told colleagues he had briefed Trump on the matter. Bolton declined to comment on that matter, and the White House did not respond to questions.</p><p>The intelligence officials and others with knowledge of the matter insisted on anonymity to discuss the highly sensitive matter.</p><p>Trump’s Democratic general election rival, former Vice President <a href="https://apnews.com/256b1855ec06dcc0cdd7ddcf96602987">Joe Biden, accused the president Monday of a “betrayal” of American troops</a> in favor of “an embarrassing campaign of deferring and debasing himself before Putin.”</p><p>“I’m disgusted,” Biden told donors, as he recalled his late son Beau’s military service. Families of service members, Biden said, “should never, ever have to worry they’ll face a threat like this: the commander in chief turning a blind eye.”</p><p>Asked about the reports on the alleged bounties, Putin’s spokesman Dmitry Peskov said Monday, “These claims are lies.”</p><p>___</p><p>Associated Press writers Lisa Mascaro, Alan Fram, and Deb Riechmann contributed to this report.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>McGrath wins Kentucky Dem primary; McConnell showdown awaits</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/mcgrath-wins-primary-to-set-up-showdown-with-mcconnell/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/mcgrath-wins-primary-to-set-up-showdown-with-mcconnell/</guid><dc:creator>Bruce Schreiner, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 22:19:44 +0000</pubDate><description>Former Marine pilot Amy McGrath has overcome a bumpier-than-expected Kentucky primary to win the Democratic U.S. Senate nomination.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Marine pilot Amy McGrath overcame a bumpier-than-expected Kentucky primary to win the Democratic U.S. Senate nomination Tuesday, fending off progressive Charles Booker to set up a bruising, big-spending showdown with Republican Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell.</p><p>Voting ended June 23, but it took a week until McGrath could be declared the winner due to the race’s tight margins and a deluge of mail-in ballots. The outcome seemed a certainty early in the campaign but became tenuous as Booker’s profile surged as the Black state lawmaker highlighted protests against the deaths of African Americans in encounters with police.</p><p>It was a narrow victory for McGrath. She outlasted Booker by 15,149 votes out of more than 544,000 votes cast. Several other candidates attracted tens of thousands of votes. McConnell, a key ally to President Donald Trump, already breezed to victory in the GOP primary in his bid for a seventh term.</p><p>Kentucky switched to widespread absentee voting amid the coronavirus pandemic, and election officials needed days to count ballots. In Lexington, the state's second-largest city, about 6,000 absentee ballots were thrown out on technicalities ranging from unsigned envelopes to detached security flaps, said Fayette County Clerk Don Blevins. </p><p>Since last summer, McConnell and McGrath had looked past their respective primaries to skirmish with each other. Those attacks will now intensify heading into the fall campaign.</p><p>Declaring victory, McGrath reached out to Booker's supporters to try to unite the party for the challenge ahead against McConnell, who has dominated Kentucky's political landscape for decades.</p><p>“There is far too much at stake," McGrath said in a statement. “The differences that separate Democrats are nothing compared to the chasm that exists between us and the politics and actions of Mitch McConnell. He’s destroyed our institutions for far too long."</p><p>McConnell's campaign said McGrath's narrow victory showed her candidacy is damaged heading into the general election. McConnell campaign spokeswoman Kate Cooksey portrayed McGrath as a “tool" for the national Democratic establishment and said the challenger was out of step with Kentucky with her support for abortion rights and “government-run health care."</p><p>Booker conceded later in the day and called on Democrats to dedicate themselves “to the work of beating Mitch, so ... we can get him out of the way." But his statement mentioned McGrath only briefly, focusing instead on his campaign for economic and racial justice.</p><p>“We’ve proven Kentuckians are hungry for a new kind of leadership, one that puts working people and their struggles before corporate special interests and the corrupt politicians who serve them," he said. “We’ve proven you don’t have to pretend to be a Republican to run as a Democrat in Kentucky, and that people want big, bold solutions to the enormous crises our state is facing." </p><p>McGrath has raised prodigious amounts of campaign cash, capitalizing on the disdain national Democrats have for McConnell. It places her in a position to go toe-to-toe with the always-well-funded McConnell.</p><p>Despite her advantages, McGrath sweated out her victory against the hard-charging Booker.</p><p>Booker’s long-shot bid surged amid the national eruption of protests against police brutality. He joined demonstrations in his hometown of Louisville to demand justice for <a href="https://apnews.com/40123de08dd6558acba5cd7cec8f0408">Breonna Taylor</a>, who was fatally shot by Louisville police in her own home. Booker gained the backing of leading national progressives as he supported a universal basic income and Medicare for All — ideas that McGrath resisted.</p><p>McGrath charted a more moderate course inside Democratic politics. She supports adding a public health insurance option as part of the Obama-era Affordable Care Act and supports expanded access to Medicare for people 55 and older.</p><p>She portrays McConnell as an overly partisan, Washington insider who exemplifies what’s wrong with national politics. She accuses McConnell of undermining labor unions, awarding tax cuts for the wealthy and cozying up to pharmaceutical companies while people struggle to afford prescription drugs.</p><p>McConnell accuses her of being too liberal for Kentucky on issues ranging from abortion to border security. He promotes his work with Trump — who remains popular in Kentucky — to appoint conservatives to fill federal court seats. McConnell also plays up his Senate leadership role and his ability to steer federal money back to the Bluegrass State.</p><p>Trump could turn into a focal point in the Senate race.</p><p>McConnell <a href="https://apnews.com/1f2816e8800ec4d85a06d0f233d5f59e">led the effort to defend the president</a> after House Democrats impeached him. McGrath has <a href="https://apnews.com/dd3e7ddb0b62b202c9f3038a509ec202">said she would have voted to convict Trump</a> on both impeachment counts. She accused of the GOP-led Senate of lacking “the guts” to put a check on “out-of-control presidential power.”</p><p>___</p><p>Associated Press Writer Piper Hudspeth Blackburn contributed to this report.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/aw96PwwYu8Wud5qM2aXNYKUjDLw=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/CM72VZZLRFE7DPZ2BKH7TY7RCQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Nov. 6, 2018, file photo, Amy McGrath speaks to supporters in Richmond, Ky. McGrath overcame a bumpier-than-expected Kentucky primary to win the Democratic U.S. Senate nomination Tuesday, June 30, 2020 fending off progressive Charles Booker to set up a bruising, big-spending showdown with Republican Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell. (AP Photo/Bryan Woolston, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Bryan Woolston]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/TV1yPGVsacklmsPEqgdzwAioH2A=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/VHL6UJ67ZRHO5EF6ZUHGOALZB4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[U.S. Senate candidate Charles Booker speaks at a campaign stop at Pikeville City Park in Pikeville, Ky., Monday, June 22, 2020. (Ryan C. Hermens/Lexington Herald-Leader via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ryan C. Hermens]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Report shows $480,000 in donations to cover Pence legal aid</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/report-shows-480000-in-donations-to-cover-pence-legal-aid/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/report-shows-480000-in-donations-to-cover-pence-legal-aid/</guid><dc:creator>Kevin Freking, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 22:17:49 +0000</pubDate><description>Donors contributed nearly $480,000 to cover Vice President Mike Pence’s legal expenses from special counsel Robert Mueller’s probe of Russian meddling in the 2016 elections.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donors contributed nearly $480,000 last year to cover Vice President Mike Pence’s legal expenses from special counsel Robert Mueller’s probe of Russian meddling in the 2016 elections, according to Pence’s financial disclosure report.</p><p>The annual report, released Tuesday, shows that a dozen donors contributed to the trust fund in May of last year. The amounts ranged from $100,000 for the top three donors to $25 for the person who is listed as the fund’s trustee, James Atterholt, who served as Pence’s chief of staff from 2014 through 2016 when Pence was governor of Indiana.</p><p>“I believe the vice president is a decent and honorable person but he is not someone of great financial means. I started the trust because I believe significant legal bills should not be the cost of public service,” Atterholt said via email.</p><p>The six-figure donations came from Indiana Pacers owner Herbert Simon of Indianapolis and California apartment developers Michael Hayde and Laura Khouri. Half of the donors came from Pence’s home state.</p><p>The report states the money was used to pay a bill from McGuireWoods LLP. The firm’s Richard Cullen served as Pence’s lawyer in the Mueller probe. Atterholt terminated the trust on Aug. 12, 2019. Many government officials have turned to legal defense funds over the years to finance their legal representation.</p><p>The report states that every contributor had to certify that they are U.S. citizens, the money came from personal funds and that Pence did not solicit the contribution, among other requirements. The report was filed with the U.S. Office of Government Ethics.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/fgbJrdF9LQs-OHUCZf279XN8xh4=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/PQGGS6DOSFHVRFAUPYFLSTMO6U.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Vice President Pence leaves the podium after speaking to the Commissioned Corps of the U.S. Public Health Service at their headquarters in Rockville, Md., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Jacquelyn Martin]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Republicans, with exception of Trump, now push mask-wearing</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/republicans-with-exception-of-trump-now-push-mask-wearing/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/republicans-with-exception-of-trump-now-push-mask-wearing/</guid><dc:creator>Aamer Madhani And Laurie Kellman, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 22:10:01 +0000</pubDate><description>In Republican circles -- with the notable exception of the man who leads the party -- the debate about masks is over: It’s time to put one on.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Republican circles -- with the notable exception of the man who leads the party -- the debate about masks is over: It’s time to put one on. </p><p>As a surge of infections hammers the South and West, GOP officials are pushing back against the notion that masks are about politics, as President Donald Trump suggests, and telling Americans they can help save lives. </p><p>Sen. Lamar Alexander, a Tennessee Republican, on Tuesday bluntly called on Trump to start wearing a mask, at least some of the time, to set a good example.</p><p>"Unfortunately, this simple, lifesaving practice has become part of a political debate that says: If you’re for Trump, you don’t wear a mask. If you’re against Trump, you do,” Alexander said. </p><p>It’s a rare break for Republicans from Trump, who earlier this month told the Wall Street Journal that some people wear masks simply to show that they disapprove of him. And the Republican nudges for the public -- and the president -- to embrace mask-wearing are coming from all corners of Trump’s party and even from friendly conservative media.</p><p>Both Vice President Mike Pence and Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell in recent days have urged Americans to wear one when they are unable to maintain social distance. Sen. Mitt Romney, a Utah Republican, told reporters it would be “very helpful” for Trump to encourage mask usage. </p><p>“Put on a mask -- it’s not complicated," McConnell, R-Ky., urged Americans during his weekly news conference Tuesday.</p><p>Last week, Republican Rep. Liz Cheney of Wyoming tweeted a photo of her father, former Vice President Dick Cheney, wearing a disposable mask and a cowboy hat. She included the message: “Dick Cheney says WEAR A MASK #realmenwearmasks,” a hashtag that echoed words spoken earlier by the Democratic House Speaker Nancy Pelosi.</p><p>Steve Doocy, co-host of a Trump friendly morning show “Fox &amp; Friends,” said during an interview with House Minority Leader Kevin McCarthy that he doesn’t “see any downside in the president being seen more often wearing it.”</p><p>McCarthy, R-Calif., responded that, for the upcoming holiday, “we could all show our patriotism with a red, white and blue mask.”</p><p>Jacksonville, the Florida city where Trump is scheduled to accept his renomination as Republicans' presidential candidate in August, announced a mask requirement for indoor public spaces this week. The president’s eldest son said the new requirements were no big deal.</p><p>“You know, I don’t think that it’s too complicated to wear a mask or wash your hands and follow basic hygiene protocols,” Donald Trump Jr. told Fox Business on Tuesday.</p><p>Trump aides have defended the president’s refusal to wear a mask by noting that he is regularly tested for the coronavirus, as are his aides. Those outside the administration -- including White House visitors and members of the media who are in close proximity to him and Pence -- are also tested. </p><p>White House press secretary Kayleigh McEnany didn’t directly address Republican calls for Trump to wear a mask in public more often, but noted that the president has said in the past he has no problem wearing one when necessary.</p><p>But even with safeguards, the virus has found its way into the White House. A top aide to Pence, as well as a military valet to Trump, in May tested positive for the virus.</p><p>Still, mask usage remains rare in the West Wing, said Rep. Brad Sherman, a California Democrat who attended an intelligence briefing at the White House on Tuesday with senior members of the president’s staff.</p><p>At the briefing, which he said included about eight White House staffers, only national security adviser Robert O’Brien wore a mask, Sherman said. He added that no one in the secure briefing room was able to maintain 6 feet (1.8 meters) of social distancing, as recommended by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. </p><p>“I learned something major, and that is the White House is a mask-free zone,” Sherman told The Associated Press. “The president is consistent. He’s fine with people not wearing masks.”</p><p>Polls show how the partisan divide on masks has seeped into public opinion.</p><p>The vast majority of Democrats think people in their community should wear a mask when they are near other people in public places at least most of the time, including 63% who say they should always, according to a Pew Research Center poll published in early June. Among Republicans, 29% say masks should be worn always, and 23% say they should be worn most of the time. Another 23% say masks should rarely or never be worn. </p><p>Trump has been caught on camera once wearing a mask. But Pence and members of the White House coronavirus task force frequently appear in public wearing masks. </p><p>“If you want the return of college football this year, wear a face covering. If you want a chance at prom next spring, wear a face covering,” Surgeon General Jerome Adams urged Americans.</p><p>Over the course of the crisis, the government has sent mixed messages on masks. As the first COVID-19 cases were identified on U.S. soil, top public health officials insisted masks should be reserved for front-line workers. </p><p>In early April, the CDC issued a recommendation that people wear cloth face coverings in public settings where other social distancing measures were difficult to maintain. </p><p>But Trump immediately undercut the CDC guidance by flatly stating that he wouldn’t be following it, suggesting it would be unseemly for the commander in chief to wear one as he meets with heads of states. </p><p>Other world leaders, including Canada’s Justin Trudeau and France’s Emmanuel Macron, have worn masks in public and urged their citizens to do the same when they can’t maintain social distance</p><p>Lawrence Gostin, a public health expert at Georgetown University, says he worries Republican calls for wearing masks “might be too late.”</p><p>“The public has received such mixed messages from the administration,” Gostin said. “I fear we may be stuck with coronavirus until it burns through the American population and leaves hundreds of thousands dead.”</p><p>___</p><p>Associated Press writers Jill Colvin, Darlene Superville and Hannah Fingerhut in Washington contributed to this report.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/5xxJwCUGpy_PbWU9jfggBJPSWz8=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/FIE6XZIPEVCGBOAIKFQFFFAMRI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell, R-Ky., listens to questions during a news conference following a GOP policy meeting on Capitol Hill, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Washington. (AP Photo/Manuel Balce Ceneta)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Manuel Balce Ceneta]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/qRoOhWIZCkjWaXXQ223CH_0ZnV4=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/QM2OUJ36NNHD5DHINMUIDKPIMI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Dr. Anthony Fauci, director of the National Institute for Allergy and Infectious Diseases, left and Center for Disease Control (CDC) Director Dr. Robert Redfield, talk with Sen. Lamar Alexander, R-Tenn., right, as they prepare to testify before a Senate Health, Education, Labor and Pensions Committee hearing on Capitol Hill in Washington, Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Kevin Dietsch/Pool via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Kevin Dietsch]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>High court sparks new battle over church-state separation</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/high-court-sparks-new-battle-over-church-state-separation/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/high-court-sparks-new-battle-over-church-state-separation/</guid><dc:creator>David Crary And Elana Schor, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 22:07:42 +0000</pubDate><description>Religious freedom advocates are pleased and some secular groups alarmed following a Supreme Court ruling that states must give religious schools the same access to public funding that other private schools receive.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Supreme Court elated religious freedom advocates and alarmed secular groups with its Tuesday ruling on public funding for religious education, a decision whose long-term effect on the separation of church and state remains to be seen.</p><p>In Espinoza v. Montana Department of Revenue, the high court ruled 5-4 that states must give religious schools the same access to public funding that other private schools receive, preserving a Montana scholarship program that had largely benefited students at religious institutions. </p><p>It prompted a jubilant reaction from the reelection campaign of President Donald Trump, who counts religious conservatives as a core part of his base. The campaign lauded the decision as “a victory for educational freedom,” underscoring its importance for a White House that often spotlights religious liberty. </p><p>Sister Dale McDonald, public policy director for the National Catholic Education Association, said the ruling has the potential to stem nationwide enrollment declines at Roman Catholic schools that are <a href="https://apnews.com/4fe7bd56c238888d9842760236502453">forcing the closure</a> of hundreds of institutions.</p><p>“This is a chance to get public schools and religious schools on equal footing,” McDonald said, adding that the extent of change would depend on how many state legislatures opt to expand tuition assistance. </p><p>Critics assailed the decision as another in a series of setbacks for a principle with long roots in the U.S. legal system. </p><p>It is "the latest in a disturbing line of Supreme Court cases attacking the very foundations of the separation of church and state,” said Daniel Mach, director of the American Civil Liberties Union’s freedom of religion program. </p><p>Tuesday’s ruling focused on a program that offered indirect tuition assistance through tax credits rather than direct state aid to religious schools. The court left unresolved the extent to which religious schools may use public funding for explicitly religious activities, such as worship services and religious-education courses. Mach said that issue likely would be the focus of future litigation, given that many religious schools consider doctrinal education to be at the core of their mission. </p><p>Others tracking the Montana case stopped short of predicting a major expansion of state funding for religious education. </p><p>Douglas Laycock, a law professor at the University of Virginia who co-authored a brief supporting the plaintiffs on behalf of multiple religious groups, described the decision as “incremental” and “building cautiously” on a 2017 case that ruled a Missouri church could use a state grant to resurface its playground. </p><p>“But incremental moves have been accumulating since 1986, and what would pretty clearly have been unconstitutional in the ’70s and early ’80s is now, sometimes, constitutionally required,” Laycock wrote in an email. </p><p>At least two faith-based organizations joined secular counterparts in opposing the ruling on principles of church-state separation, saying public money for religious education forces people to fund faiths to which they do not subscribe.</p><p>“Government funding to religious schools requires taxpayers to support religious institutions and beliefs that may violate their own, something the First Amendment was intended to avoid,” Rabbi Jonah Pesner, director of the Religious Action Center of Reform Judaism, said in a statement.</p><p>Rachel Laser, president of Americans United for Separation of Church and State, contended that many of the religious schools participating in Montana’s program had discriminatory policies.</p><p>“Members of the faith should fund those religious schools, not the taxpayers,” said Laser, who is Jewish. “It would offend my religious freedom to fund a school that requires belief that Jesus Christ is necessary for my salvation.” </p><p>Another attorney who co-authored a brief supporting the plaintiffs, Becket Fund for Religious Liberty vice president and senior counsel Eric Baxter, predicted the ruling will not result in significant new funds flowing to religious schools.</p><p>“Legislatures are not compelled to provide this funding,” Baxter said, pointing to language in Chief Justice John Roberts’ majority opinion saying most states with provisions barring aid to religious schools still let them participate in public scholarship programs.</p><p>“If they do provide this funding to the private sphere,” Baxter said of states, “then they just have to treat everybody equally.”</p><p>Institute of Justice vice president Tim Keller, whose group represented the plaintiffs, told reporters that Idaho, Texas, South Dakota and Missouri were among the states most likely to create school choice programs that include religious education.</p><p>Arizona has had such programs in place for several years, enabling Catholic schools there to reverse enrollment declines that were due at least in part to parents’ inability to afford tuition. </p><p>McDonald, of the Catholic education association, also predicted that the ruling would bring swift changes in Maine and Vermont, where parents have been able to get public funds for tuition at secular private schools, but not at faith-based schools. </p><p>___</p><p>Associated Press reporter Mark Sherman in Washington contributed.</p><p>___</p><p>Associated Press religion coverage receives support from the Lilly Endowment through the Religion News Foundation. The AP is solely responsible for this content.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/VgCByIY86IZggpIpFBvi8qztfLk=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/YTGTULUOWRHZTIH7SON372DCVE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The U.S. Supreme Court is seen Tuesday, June 30, 2020 in Washington. (AP Photo/Manuel Balce Ceneta)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Manuel Balce Ceneta]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Dem climate plan would end greenhouse gas emissions by 2050</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/dem-climate-plan-would-end-greenhouse-gas-emissions-by-2050/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/dem-climate-plan-would-end-greenhouse-gas-emissions-by-2050/</guid><dc:creator>Matthew Daly, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 21:55:38 +0000</pubDate><description>House Democrats have unveiled a plan to address climate change that would set a goal of net-zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2050.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>House Democrats on Tuesday unveiled a plan to address climate change that would set a goal of net-zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2050, while pushing renewable energy such as wind and solar power and addressing environmental contamination that disproportionately harms low-income and minority communities.</p><p>The election-year plan backed by House Speaker Nancy Pelosi and other leaders is less ambitious than a sweeping Green New Deal that a group of progressive Democrats outlined last year to combat climate change and create thousands of jobs in renewable energy.</p><p>The Green New Deal, championed by Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez, D-N.Y., calls for dramatic steps to virtually eliminate U.S. greenhouse gas emissions by 2030 with a goal of meeting “100% of the power demand in the United States through clean, renewable and zero-emission energy sources,” including nuclear power. </p><p>The new plan, put forth Tuesday in a 538-page report, offers similar goals but at a slower pace. It sets a range of targets, including a 45% reduction by 2030 of greenhouse gas emissions, which cause global warming. </p><p>The plan also would require that by 2035 new cars emit no greenhouse gases, while heavy-duty trucks would eliminate those emissions by 2040. The plan would eliminate overall emissions from the power sector by 2040 and all but eliminate greenhouse emissions from all economic sectors by 2050.</p><p>Supporters say the plan, presented by Democrats on the House Select Committee on the Climate Crisis, by 2050 would save more than 60,000 American lives every year thanks to reduced air pollution, as well as nearly $8 trillion thanks to health and climate benefits.</p><p>"Democrats know the climate crisis is the essential crisis of our time, threatening public health, jobs and the economy, national security and values,'' Pelosi said Tuesday at a Capitol news conference. </p><p>“We are here today to provide hope and vision,'' said Rep. Kathy Castor, D-Fla., chairwoman of the climate panel. She called the Democratic plan a "transformative road map for solving the climate crisis,'' and pledged it would address environmental justice and vulnerable communities that are suffering from the effects of air and water pollution and industrial waste.</p><p>"The health of our families and the air we breathe are at the heart of our plan,'' Castor said, adding that it would create good-paying jobs in solar and wind energy, manufacturing electric vehicles and ensuring that communities are more resilient to flooding, extreme heat, intense hurricanes and wildfires.</p><p>While likely to win approval in the Democratic-controlled House, the plan faces insurmountable opposition in the Republican-controlled Senate. Democrats are hoping to make inaction on climate change by congressional Republicans and the Trump administration a key campaign issue in November’s election.</p><p>GOP lawmakers immediately slammed the plan as a job-killer. The Democratic plan “punishes the American economy” and “gives a free pass to China” to pollute, said House Minority Leader Kevin McCarthy, R-Calif.</p><p>President Donald Trump and congressional Republicans have expanded responsible, clean-energy technologies "while the Democrats continue to push radical Green New Deal-like polices that would cripple America’s economy and crush the poorest communities across the globe,” said White House spokesman Judd Deere. </p><p>The Democratic plan is similar to one proposed by former Vice President Joe Biden, the presumptive Democratic nominee for president. Biden's plan also sets a goal for net-zero greenhouse emissions by 2050 and pledges an enforcement mechanism that includes milestone targets no later than 2025.</p><p>A Biden spokesman applauded Pelosi and House Democrats and said that as president, Biden “will work with Congress to implement a bold agenda that addresses the climate emergency, achieves environmental justice and creates good-paying jobs.″ </p><p>The new plan received immediate support from more than 90 outside organizations, including major environmental groups and leaders in environmental justice, agriculture, public health and transportation.</p><p>The Sunrise Movement, a progressive group that helped develop the Green New Deal, said the plan did not go far enough, fast enough to halt climate change.</p><p>"This plan is more ambitious than anything we have seen from Democratic leadership so far, but it still needs to go further to match the full scale of the crisis,'' said Lauren Maunus, the group's legislative manager.</p><p>“There’s nothing to lose by going bigger,'' Maunus said. "Taking action at the scale of the crisis will help lift our economy out of recession and put millions of people back to work building a more just and resilient society.''</p><p>In a sign of the changed political environment, the Democratic plan heavily emphasizes environmental justice and notes that the report’s release comes as the nation is reeling from a cascade of crises, including the COVID-19 pandemic. which has killed more than 120,000 Americans; stay-at-home orders and business closures that have put 40 million Americans out of work; and nationwide protests in response to the police killing of an unarmed Black man, George Floyd. </p><p>Throughout these crises, Trump has "failed to lead the country in a unified and compassionate response, instead choosing to fan the flames of discord and distrust,'' the report said.</p><p>Cornell University climate scientist Natalie Mahowald, lead author of a 2018 report on climate change for the United Nations, said the House committee’s report got the science correct. “If you want to keep temperatures low, we need to act quickly. The emission cuts required are really quite dramatic, as they say here,” Mahowald said in an email.</p><p>Pennsylvania State University climate scientist Michael Mann called the report “an excellent starting point” that offers a sensible mix of subsidies for renewable energy and a price on carbon emissions. </p><p>The report was released as the Trump administration pushed a plan to spur production of fossil fuels even higher. In a 56-page report that did not mention the word "climate,'' the Energy Department on Tuesday urged building up four Appalachian states as a petrochemical production and manufacturing hub, while delaying market-driven retirements of the region’s coal plants. The four targeted states — Pennsylvania, Ohio, West Virginia and Kentucky — are the heart of Appalachian energy production. Pennsylvania is a key battleground in the 2020 election, and recent polls show Biden narrowly leading Trump in Ohio.</p><p>Trump has mocked the science of climate change, and his administration has dismantled Obama-era initiatives to cut greenhouse gas emissions, while throwing a series of financial and regulatory breaks to the coal, oil and gas sectors.</p><p>___</p><p>Associated Press writers Seth Borenstein and Ellen Knickmeyer contributed to this report. </p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/ZPdad_hfXU5b2coyassaiUHyKWA=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/JGADB5TILFGJDDJCXPKBI4WUTM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[House Speaker Nancy Pelosi of Calif., speaks at a news conference on Capitol Hill in Washington, Friday, June 26, 2020. (AP Photo/Carolyn Kaster)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Carolyn Kaster]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/hU2ajzPse84ynk6X3MERPmTW1AI=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/FZDZHKWPFBC4BNBJMQPJNUXNDE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this May 14, 2020 file photo Rep. Kathy Castor, D-Fla., speaks during House Energy and Commerce Subcommittee on Health hearing on Capitol Hill in Washington. House Democrats on Tuesday unveiled a plan to address climate change that would set a goal of net-zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2050, while pushing renewable energy such as wind and solar power and addressing environmental injustice that harms low-income and minority communities. (Greg Nash/Pool via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Greg Nash]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/88S39CaZ2cKoS1DeuRM3vH-HZYM=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/FLG4FBCPMZGLNDMXWMH2FUGCIM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Democratic presidential candidate, former Vice President Joe Biden, speaks Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Wilmington, Del. (AP Photo/Patrick Semansky)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Patrick Semansky]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/7vcX1PREhnh7C9wx0DQYCwcxRnU=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/2JYJ5DL7ZZEQHAC5C6XQOLM73Q.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[House Minority Leader Kevin McCarthy of Calif., speaks during a news conference on Capitol Hill in Washington, Thursday, June 25, 2020. (AP Photo/Carolyn Kaster)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Carolyn Kaster]]></media:credit></media:content></item></channel></rss>