<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"><channel><title>WPLG Local 10</title><link>https://www.local10.com</link><atom:link href="https://www.local10.com/arcio/rss/tags/education/?size=10" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>WPLG Local 10 News Feed</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:54:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><ttl>1</ttl><sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod><sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency><item><title>Parents, teachers in Broward County say students should go back to class full-time </title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/parents-teachers-in-broward-county-say-students-should-go-back-to-class-full-time/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/parents-teachers-in-broward-county-say-students-should-go-back-to-class-full-time/</guid><dc:creator>Layron Livingston</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 22:47:33 +0000</pubDate><description>The Broward County School District has sent out a questionnaire to parents asking what they think school should look like in the fall.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Broward County School District has sent out a questionnaire to parents asking what they think school should look like in the fall.</p><p>The district presented four options:</p><p>1) Distance or electronic learning, which is what students have been doing since the pandemic started.</p><p>2) Full-time, in class instruction.</p><p>3) A combination of in-class and virtual learning</p><p>4) Broward virtual school, which many students already participate in, but those programs aren’t affiliated with a specific campus.</p><p>That questionnaire got a lot of parents and teachers riled up.</p><p>Many of them showed up outside the School Board building Tuesday with signs.</p><p>They were chanting and overwhelmingly calling for in-class, five days a week instruction.</p><p>They say there are ways to do it safely, following CDC guidelines.</p><p>The parents and teachers who participated in the protest are concerned about widening learning gaps and future impacts. They say children are just not learning at home.</p><p>“Kids are safer in school,” one teacher, Kelly Blaire, said. “There’s parents that have to work. They’re leaving the kids home alone. They’re safer in school. Some of these kids don’t eat unless they’re in school. Some, they don’t get attention, they don’t get hugs, they don’t get praises unless they’re in school. They’re safer, they’re healthier in school.”</p><p>Broward County Public Schools spokeswoman Kathy Koch said school officials are still researching different possibilities and appreciate the input.</p><p>“This is not a done deal,” she said. “We can’t make the decision without our parents. It’s for our parents and for our students.”</p><p>The parents who came out Tuesday also came with expert opinion from the American Academy of Pediatrics, which has also outlined steps schools should take at different grade levels with the pandemic in mind.</p><p>But the organization “strongly advocates that all policy considerations for the coming school year should start with a goal of having students physically present in school.”</p><p>The issue is one of the items expected to be discussed at Tuesday’s board meeting.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fauci: US ‘going in wrong direction’ in coronavirus outbreak</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/fauci-us-going-in-wrong-direction-in-coronavirus-outbreak/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/fauci-us-going-in-wrong-direction-in-coronavirus-outbreak/</guid><dc:creator>Lauran Neergaard, Associated Press, Jenise Fernandez</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 18:15:31 +0000</pubDate><description>Dr. Anthony Fauci says the U.S. is “going in the wrong direction” with coronavirus cases surging in some regions, and that's putting the entire country at risk.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. is “going in the wrong direction” with the coronavirus surging badly enough that Dr. Anthony Fauci told senators Tuesday some regions are putting the entire country at risk — just as schools and colleges are wrestling with how to safely reopen.</p><p>With about 40,000 new cases being reported a day, Fauci, the government’s top infectious disease expert, said he “would not be surprised if we go up to 100,000 a day if this does not turn around.”</p><p>“I am very concerned,” he told a hearing of the Senate Health, Education, Labor and Pensions committee. </p><p>Infections are rising rapidly mostly in parts of the West and South, and Fauci and other public health experts said Americans everywhere will have to start following key recommendations if they want to get back to more normal activities like going to school.</p><p>“We’ve got to get the message out that we are all in this together,” by wearing masks in public and keeping out of crowds, said Fauci, infectious disease chief at the National Institutes of Health.</p><p>Connect the dots, he told senators: When and how school buildings can reopen will vary depending on how widely the coronavirus is spreading locally. </p><p>“I feel very strongly we need to do whatever we can to get the children back to school,” he said.</p><p>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention plans more guidelines for local school systems, Director Robert Redfield said. </p><p>But in recommendations for colleges released Tuesday, the agency said it won’t recommend entry testing for all returning students, faculty and staff. It’s not clear if that kind of broad-stroke testing would reduce spread of the coronavirus, CDC concluded. Instead, it urged colleges to focus on containing outbreaks and exposures as students return.</p><p>Lawmakers also pressed for what Sen. Patty Murray of Washington, the committee’s top Democrat, called a national vaccine plan — to be sure the race for the COVID-19 vaccine ends with shots that really are safe, truly protect and are available to all Americans who want, one.</p><p>“We can’t take for granted this process will be free of political influence,” Murray said. She cited how President Donald Trump promoted a malaria drug as a COVID-19 treatment that ultimately was found to be risky and ineffective.</p><p>The Food and Drug Administration released guidelines Tuesday saying any vaccine that wins approval will have to be at 50% more effective than a dummy shot in the final, required testing. That’s less effective than many of today’s vaccines but independent experts say that would be a good start against the virus.</p><p>FDA Commissioner Stephen Hahn said vaccine makers also must test their shots in diverse populations, including minorities, the elderly, pregnant women and those with chronic health problems.</p><p>“We will not cut corners in our decision-making,” Hahn told senators.</p><p>About 15 vaccine candidates are in various stages of human testing worldwide but the largest studies -- including 30,000 people each -- needed to prove if a shot really protects are set to begin in July. First up is expected to be a vaccine created by the NIH and Moderna Inc., followed closely by an Oxford University candidate.</p><p>At the same time, the Trump administration’s “Operation Warp Speed” aims to stockpile hundreds of millions of doses by year’s end, so they could rapidly start vaccinations if and when one is proven to work.</p><p>Redfield said the CDC already is planning how to prioritize who is first in line for the scarce first doses and how they’ll be distributed.</p><p>But a vaccine is at the very least many months away. For now, the committee’s leading Republican stressed wearing a mask -- and said Trump, who notoriously shuns them, needs to start because politics is getting in the way of protecting the American people.</p><p>“The stakes are too high for the political debate about pro-Trump, anti-Trump masks to continue,” said Sen. Lamar Alexander of Tennessee, who chaired Tuesday’s hearing. </p><p>Alexander said he had to self-quarantine after a staff member tested positive for the virus but that he personally was protected because his staffer was wearing a mask. </p><p>“The president has plenty of admirers. They would follow his lead,” Alexander said. “The stakes are too high” to continue that fight.</p><p>___</p><p>AP writers Ricardo Alonso-Zaldivar and Matthew Perrone in Washington, Collin Binkley in Boston and Mike Stobbe in New York contributed to this report.</p><p>___</p><p>The Associated Press Health and Science Department receives support from the Howard Hughes Medical Institute’s Department of Science Education. The AP is solely responsible for all content.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Broward County School Board discusses changing the name of 5 schools due to racial connotation </title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/broward-county-school-board-discusses-changing-the-name-of-5-schools-due-to-racial-connotation/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/broward-county-school-board-discusses-changing-the-name-of-5-schools-due-to-racial-connotation/</guid><dc:creator>Saira Anwer</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 16:58:47 +0000</pubDate><description>The Broward County School Board is discussing the possible changing of five Plantation schools’ names, not due to a racist history, but rather due to racial connotation associated with the word “plantation” and its connection to slavery.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Broward County School Board is discussing the possible changing of five Plantation schools’ names, not due to a racist history, but rather due to racial connotation associated with the word “plantation” and its connection to slavery.</p><p>“It continues to hurt people that look like me, people that are immigrants to this country, people that are a part of the family’s LGBTQ community. Racism is alive and well,” School Board Member Dr. Rosalind Osgood said. </p><p>The discussion of renaming the five Broward public schools containing the city name “Plantation” was brought up by Osgood. </p><p>Tuesday morning’s meeting was open to public comment over possible changes. </p><p>The discussion comes amid nationwide conversations surrounding race, sparked by protests against the killing of George Floyd.</p><p>“If these people are feeling hurt, if people are feeling that it’s a reminder of something that we would no longer like to remember, then I think that I would like to, as briefly as possible, tell you to please listen,” one commenter, Terry Lopez Preuss, said.  </p><p>Commenters spoke both for and against name changes.</p><p>One commenter spotlighted the city of Plantation’s history and that the name plantation comes from the Everglades Plantation Company, which drained the area where the city now stands for farmland, and that the area was not affiliated with slavery or slave plantations. </p><p>“We love our city, we like the name, and I’m here today to ask for us to take a breath (and) not make any rash decisions as far as the city of Plantation names go,” Aston Bright said. </p><p>The school names in question include Plantation High, South Plantation High, Plantation Middle, Plantation Elementary and Plantation Park Elementary. Osgood suggested the board change its school naming guidelines moving forward to exclude names with racial connotations. </p><p>Current guidelines already prohibit naming schools after cities, but the five Plantation schools were named prior to the issuance of that guideline. </p><p>Name changing potential will be discussed in a future workshop.</p><p>So far, school board members agreed that there should be a task force to discuss renaming of schools, but whether that take place at the county level or within individual school communities is still up for debate. </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Gov. Ron DeSantis signs Alyssa’s Law, requiring silent alarms at all Florida public schools</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/gov-ron-desantis-signs-alyssas-law-requiring-silent-alarms-at-all-florida-public-schools/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/gov-ron-desantis-signs-alyssas-law-requiring-silent-alarms-at-all-florida-public-schools/</guid><dc:creator>Amanda Batchelor, Christian De La Rosa</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 15:56:21 +0000</pubDate><description>Gov. Ron DeSantis has signed a new law that requires all public schools in the state of Florida to have a silent panic alarm.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gov. Ron DeSantis has signed a new law Tuesday that requires all public schools in the state of Florida to have a silent panic alarm.</p><p>Alyssa’s Law was named in honor of Alyssa Alhadeff, 14, who was killed in the Feb. 14, 2018, massacre at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland.</p><p>Students or teachers will be able to push the buttons inside their classrooms, directly alerting law enforcement of what and where the threat may be, cutting down on response times.</p><p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Alyssa’s Law is signed! ⁦<a href="https://twitter.com/GovRonDeSantis?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@GovRonDeSantis</a>⁩ <a href="https://twitter.com/Book4Senate?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Book4Senate</a>⁩ ⁦<a href="https://twitter.com/DanDaley?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DanDaley</a>⁩ ⁦<a href="https://twitter.com/BrowardCrimeLaw?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BrowardCrimeLaw</a>⁩ <a href="https://t.co/hG73BlqYUf">pic.twitter.com/hG73BlqYUf</a></p>— Lori Alhadeff (@lorialhadeff) <a href="https://twitter.com/lorialhadeff/status/1277989785634770946?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 30, 2020</a></blockquote> </p><p>“If a panic button was pushed, and it was a direct link to law enforcement, they would know where the threat was because it’s geofenced to the area,” Alyssa’s mother and Broward County School Board Member <a href="https://www.local10.com/news/local/2019/12/11/alyssas-law-requires-silent-alarm-at-all-florida-public-schools/" target="_blank">Lori Alhadeff said last year </a>as the bill was making its way through the Florida Legislature.</p><p>Panic button technology that is already available can work through a smart phone application, allowing users to notify authorities.</p><p>Users can even categorize incidents, such as a medical emergency or an active shooter.</p><p>“We need to provide all these layers and hopefully we will stop the next school shooting,” Alhadeff said.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/xWZ_108oMru7_fr5m1nFnv2brbE=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/3JDODD5IIVBUFDDEHBE2KYNTDE.jpg"></media:content></item><item><title>Monroe County school officials release school reopening plan</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/29/monroe-county-school-officials-release-school-reopening-plan/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/29/monroe-county-school-officials-release-school-reopening-plan/</guid><dc:creator>Amanda Batchelor</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 18:10:46 +0000</pubDate><description>Monroe County School District officials released their school reopening plan on Monday as concerns surrounding the coronavirus pandemic continue.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Monroe County School District officials released their school reopening plan on Monday as concerns surrounding the <a href="https://www.local10.com/topic/coronavirus/" target="_blank">coronavirus </a>pandemic continue.</p><p>“None of us can accurately predict what will happen with the COVID-19 virus between now and the opening of school in August,” incoming Superintendent Theresa Axford said in a news release. “But we have to be ready to go anyway. So, we convened a large group to look at how we will respond to each possible iteration. And by doing this as early as possible, we are able to communicate this to the rest of those affected so they can, in turn, make appropriate plans.” </p><p>The school district separated the plan into three possible scenarios.</p><p>Axford said keeping schools closed for long periods of time is disruptive for families and school officials also want to make sure that students are receiving the “best education possible.” </p><p>“What we did was look at all of the ways we can safely keep as many kids in school for as many days as possible under all of the different phases of exposure. This is the best way we can serve the community and the kids,” Axford said.</p><p>Parents who wish to continue virtual learning for their children in the fall, however, may do so, school officials said.</p><p>Below is a list of safety measures that the school district says are already in place and will continue into the school year:</p><ul><li><i>Mask-wearing will be required  at all times when social distancing is not possible. This would include on  buses, when walking between classes, and at any meetings or events which don’t allow for adequate space between people.</i></li><li><i>Classrooms will be provided with adequate amounts of cleaning supplies such as soap, hand sanitizer, gloves and cleansing agents for surface cleaning. Students and staff will be instructed in how to adequately clean both themselves and the classroom.</i></li><li><i>Cleaning staff will receive training on how to best clean school buildings, buses and playground equipment and normal cleaning routines will be substantially increased to ensure safety.</i></li><li><i>Classrooms will be rearranged to provide for more space between students. Students will sit facing forward instead of facing toward one another. Schools will be identifying extra rooms which can be used for instruction to ensure that social distancing of students is possible.</i></li><li><i>Signs will be posted school-wide to remind people of safety and cleanliness guidelines. There will also be markings on floors where necessary to remind people about social distancing.</i></li><li><i>Visitors to schools will be limited and will be required to wear face masks; points of entry into schools will be restricted and office staff will be protected by plexiglass shields. </i></li><li><i>Each school will review its cafeteria operations and determine how best to organize mealtimes safely. The plan outlines a number of possibilities depending on the school,  including staggering mealtimes and feeding students in their classrooms.</i></li></ul><p>Guidelines for school reopenings in the county will be based upon the current COVID-19 outlook.</p><p>Below are the school district’s three planned guidelines:</p><p><b>Guidelines during Minimal Community Exposure</b></p><p><i>Minimal exposure in the community is defined as isolated cases with limited community transmission and case investigations with no evidence of exposure in large community settings.</i></p><p><i>Under these circumstances, all students would return to school except those whose parents choose to keep them enrolled in a virtual environment at home. </i></p><p><i>The plan for this phase provides schools with guidance on how to do this safely. Some considerations include:</i></p><ul><li><i>Teaching smaller groups of  students to ensure social distancing, which will require identifying  additional classroom space and instructional staff.</i></li><li><i>Grouping students in “cohorts” which would stay together for various activities during the school day. The use of these smaller “cohort” groups would limit any potential virus exposure which might happen within schools.</i></li><li><i>Developing schedules which allow for the minimal amount of student movement, and safe movement of students when necessary. This will include changes in cafeteria schedules and operations if necessary for safety.</i></li></ul><p><b>Guidelines for Moderate Community Exposure</b></p><p><i>This phase is defined as “sustained transmission with likelihood or confirmed exposure and potential for rapid increase in cases.”</i></p><p><i>In this phase of exposure, students in Pre-K through Grade 5 will attend face-to-face instruction every day. Class sizes will be reduced and may require schedule adjustments to ensure CDC guidelines are being followed. Grades 6-12 will use a schedule of alternating days to reduce numbers. These students will attend school every other day on a staggered schedule and will have virtual school on the alternating days.</i></p><p><i>All of the social distancing and cleanliness concerns of the previous phase will remain in place and in some circumstances will be more stringent. In this phase, meal service may be substantially changed to include students eating in the classroom instead of the cafeteria to reduce movement around the school and to enforce social distancing guidelines. Schools may also consider canceling extracurricular activities and events.</i></p><p><b>Guidelines for Substantial Exposure</b></p><p><i>This phase is defined by large-scale community transmission. </i></p><p><i>In this phase, schools will be closed with students self-isolating, attending full time virtual school. Meal service will continue. Cafeteria staff will prepare meals and transportation staff will deliver them to centralized locations throughout the Keys where families can pick them up.</i></p><p>School officials said staff members will also help in providing mental and physical health and wellness assistance that may be required for students. </p><p>“This is new for all of us,” Axford said. “We will all have to be as flexible as possible while keeping in mind our main goals: keeping our kids safe, and providing them with the best education under difficult circumstances. With that in mind, we are also putting in place a communications plan so we can keep everyone informed. We need everyone concerned to stay informed for all of this to work and we will do our best to provide up to date information in as many formats and locations as possible.”</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/JYD_a1xvNNlQfojKhbaP7084P38=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/YTFB2JWJSFABRJ2EK5HLNTCFYM.jpg"></media:content></item></channel></rss>