<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"><channel><title>WPLG Local 10</title><link>https://www.local10.com</link><atom:link href="https://www.local10.com/arcio/rss/tags/dolphins/?size=10" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>WPLG Local 10 News Feed</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:56:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><ttl>1</ttl><sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod><sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency><item><title>Former Miami Dolphins star Jim Kiick dies at 73</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/20/former-miami-dolphins-star-jim-kiick-dies/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/20/former-miami-dolphins-star-jim-kiick-dies/</guid><dc:creator>Clay Ferraro</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 03:45:34 +0000</pubDate><description></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jim Kiick, a key member of the 1972 Miami Dolphins undefeated team, has died at the age of 73.</p><p>As a runner and receiver, joining Larry Csonka and Mercury Morris, they formed one of the best backfields in NFL history.</p><p>Kiick had been battling dementia for the last few years and lived in an assisted living facility.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">And it’s amazing to see all my dads fans.... all the stories. Thank you all. He is the best dad I could have ever asked for and will forever be a legend and my hero #21</p>— Allie Kiick (@AllieKiick) <a href="https://twitter.com/AllieKiick/status/1274489976982470657?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 20, 2020</a></blockquote><p>His daughter, Allie, a professional tennis player, posted a heartfelt message about her father’s struggles on her Twitter account earlier in the week.</p><p>She said that because of the coronavirus, visitors weren’t being allowed in his room.</p><p>“I miss my dad,” she wrote Thursday on Twitter. “It’s pretty hard when you’re sitting on the outside of the glass and can’t do anything to cheer him up. He’s lost the spark in his eyes as anyone would in this situation.”</p><p>On Saturday, she announced that he had passed away.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Our thoughts and prayers are with the family and friends of Jim Kiick. <a href="https://t.co/ufih9qRDMt">pic.twitter.com/ufih9qRDMt</a></p>— Miami Dolphins (@MiamiDolphins) <a href="https://twitter.com/MiamiDolphins/status/1274467153081774083?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 20, 2020</a></blockquote><p><a href="https://www.nfl.com/players/jim-kiick/stats/career" target="_blank">Kiick helped lead the Dolphins </a>to two Super Bowl titles, playing seven seasons in Miami.</p><p>Kiick made the American Football League All-Star team in his first two seasons. He had two touchdowns for the ’72 Dolphins in the AFC championship game, and also scored in the Super Bowl victory that capped their 17-0 season under Pro Football Hall of Fame coach Don Shula. Shula died May 4 at age 90.</p><p>After Kiick retired from football, he worked as a private investigator in the Broward County Public Defenders office.</p><p><i>(The Associated Press contributed to this story)</i></p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/l9_ezguc3XFLqlgk3XkOkO8Lq7s=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/HVA6KF4DBRFE7MR2U6BPIJWGBI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[MIAMI, FL - JANUARY 26: Former Miami Dolphin Jim Kiick heads down field against the Miami Hurricanes at the Orange Bowl January 26, 2008 in Miami, Florida. This is the last game to be played in the Orange Bowl. (Photo by Eliot J. Schechter/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Eliot J. Schechter]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Miami Dolphins set to open drive-in and open air move theaters at Hard Rock Stadium</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/19/miami-dolphins-set-to-open-hard-rock-stadium-for-drive-in-and-open-air-move-theaters/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/19/miami-dolphins-set-to-open-hard-rock-stadium-for-drive-in-and-open-air-move-theaters/</guid><dc:creator>Louis Aguirre</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 03:30:40 +0000</pubDate><description>The Miami Dolphins are getting ready to new outdoor movie theatres at Hard Rock Stadium, which includes a drive-in experience.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Miami Dolphins are getting ready to new outdoor movie theatres at Hard Rock Stadium, which includes a drive-in experience. </p><p>Beginning Friday night, the Dolphins are opening up their home (field) to create a movie experience like none other, with cars driving right onto the field to catch the show. </p><p>“It’s a perfect opportunity to invite the community to do something that is social distanced but also have a good time,” said Laura Sandall, VP of Marketing for the Miami Dolphins and Hard Rock Stadium. </p><p>There is room on the field for 175 cars, with tickets costing $39 per vehicle. Movies will change every weekend, from Jurassic Park to Transformers.  </p><p>Waiter service is offered in order to help keep everyone socially distant and safe. </p><p>All proceeds benefit the Miami Dolphins Foundatiopn, which gives out 1000 free meals a day, five days a week, to those who need it in the community. </p><p>“Just being back in the stadium (brings back memories),” said former Dolphins player Patrick Surtain. “Great thing they’re doing for the community, man.” </p><p>And if drive-in isn't your thing, there is also an open-air theatre with plush, comfortable seating. </p><p>The outdoor theatre can accommodate 400 people. They even have a VIP section with pods that can seat up to parties of four, all while keeping everybody socially distant. </p><p>For more information on movies, times and pricing, <a href="https://hardrockstadium.com/theater/" target="_blank">click here</a>. </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Tua Tagovailoa establishes $300,000 scholarship for his high school</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/16/tua-tagovailoa-establishes-300000-scholarship-for-his-high-school/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/16/tua-tagovailoa-establishes-300000-scholarship-for-his-high-school/</guid><dc:creator>David Lang</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 18:51:07 +0000</pubDate><description>Dolphins rookie quarterback Tua Tagovailoa is already giving back.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dolphins rookie quarterback Tua Tagovailoa is making a difference, before even taking an NFL snap.</p><p>The team’s first round pick announced Tuesday that he’s setting up a $300,000 scholarship to benefit his high school, Saint Louis School in Honolulu, Hawaii.</p><p>In addition, four scholarships will be given to students from Hawaii over the next four years, each in the name of Tagovailoa’s grandparents.</p><p>Tagovailoa said, “My hope is that these scholarships will give deserving Hawaii students the same opportunities Saint Louis School gave me. It is a blessing to honor my family and high school through this gift.”</p><p>The Dolphins draft Tagovailoa with the No. 5 overall pick in the draft out of the University of Alabama.</p><p>The quarterback was known for his leadership of his college team and his generosity in the community.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/5O9FmKfXUC7i87Ym-xpVKaBJEOQ=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/BZNEL773CFCL5FDPIOMDQERIOY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Dolphins QB Tua Tagovailoa announced that he would wear jersey No. 1 in a Tweet.]]></media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Dolphins’ Christian Wilkins finds protests personal after grandfather was killed in police shooting</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/11/wilkins-finds-protests-personal-hopes-to-be-spark-of-hope/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/11/wilkins-finds-protests-personal-hopes-to-be-spark-of-hope/</guid><dc:creator>David Lang</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 17:50:09 +0000</pubDate><description>Dolphins defensive lineman Christian Wilkins was 15 when his grandfather was killed in a police-involved shooting.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dolphins defensive lineman Christian Wilkins plans to make his voice heard.</p><p>The 2019 first-round pick talked about the protests around the country concerning racial injustice and police brutality and said that it’s personal for him.</p><p>When Wilkins was 15, his grandfather was killed in a police-involved shooting.</p><p>“What’s going on in the country right now is extremely personal for me,” he said. “I experienced it with my family. Whether it was brothers or close family and friends. A lot of people know the story of what happened to my grandfather.</p><p>“It’s my job to use my platform to shed a positive light, to be a spark of hope through all of this,” he added.</p><p>As far as kneeling for the national anthem, Wilkins said he’ll figure it out as the season gets closer.</p><p>He believes it’s something that the team will talk about.</p><p>“It hurts to see what’s happening to a lot of people that look like me,” he said. “It’s something that’s been going on forever and stuff that we’ve had to deal with. But the rest of the world is really starting to see what we go through as a black community.”</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/98_qW3ggUkHxUUHijJPo1BYCCaM=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/DQHVNL2QJNFKNEJHZ2WGXMXED4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Ryan Fitzpatrick and Christian Wilkins of the Miami Dolphins celebrate a touchdown at Hard Rock Stadium on December 22, 2019.]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Mark Brown/Getty Images]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>South Florida’s professional sports teams speak out following George Floyd death, protests </title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/01/south-floridas-sports-teams-speak-out-following-george-floyd-death-protests/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/01/south-floridas-sports-teams-speak-out-following-george-floyd-death-protests/</guid><dc:creator>David Dwork</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 20:26:16 +0000</pubDate><description>South Floridians, like many others in regions across United States, have been holding protests following the death of George Floyd at the hands of Minneapolis police officers.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Floridians, like many others in regions across the United States, have been holding protests following the death of George Floyd at the hands of Minneapolis police officers.</p><p>Peaceful protests in Miami turned violent Saturday night, though officials believe the instigating parties may have been from out of state and specifically in town to start trouble.</p><p>Demonstrations continued Sunday evening, and were almost entirely peaceful; in one instance in Downtown Miami, protestors formed a human chain to stop others from breaking the windows of a CVS pharmacy.</p><p>Several statements have been released by South Florida’s sports teams and, in some cases, their respective owners over the past few days, and instead of trying to paraphrase those words, here they are as intended:</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Statement from Head Coach Brian Flores. <a href="https://t.co/dJOdHHSvNT">pic.twitter.com/dJOdHHSvNT</a></p>— Miami Dolphins (@MiamiDolphins) <a href="https://twitter.com/MiamiDolphins/status/1266472470871183361?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 29, 2020</a></blockquote><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="und"><a href="https://t.co/IX61igEIPO">pic.twitter.com/IX61igEIPO</a></p>— Miami HEAT (@MiamiHEAT) <a href="https://twitter.com/MiamiHEAT/status/1267467188799242242?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2020</a></blockquote><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="und"><a href="https://t.co/rObsemS29n">pic.twitter.com/rObsemS29n</a></p>— Miami Marlins (@Marlins) <a href="https://twitter.com/Marlins/status/1267488248626139137?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2020</a></blockquote><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="und"><a href="https://t.co/tyosRG9MYl">pic.twitter.com/tyosRG9MYl</a></p>— Inter Miami CF (@InterMiamiCF) <a href="https://twitter.com/InterMiamiCF/status/1267499934812643329?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2020</a></blockquote><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Dolphins head coach Brian Flores speaking this morning at the team’s meal distribution at Hard Rock stadium.  On leadership and bringing change.  (Via <a href="https://twitter.com/MiamiDolphins?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MiamiDolphins</a>) <a href="https://t.co/tl8XOnCfDz">pic.twitter.com/tl8XOnCfDz</a></p>— Will Manso (@WillManso) <a href="https://twitter.com/WillManso/status/1267501658206019584?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2020</a></blockquote><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">I am deeply impacted by the death of George Floyd and share the outrage over his senseless death. We have seen, for too long, how the ills of prejudice have sought to divide us. There is no room for racism and hatred in our world yet here we are. Let us stand together and condemn</p>— Jorge Mas (@Jorge__Mas) <a href="https://twitter.com/Jorge__Mas/status/1267503996694134787?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2020</a></blockquote><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="und"><a href="https://t.co/0qgVq8UYMr">pic.twitter.com/0qgVq8UYMr</a></p>— Florida Panthers (@FlaPanthers) <a href="https://twitter.com/FlaPanthers/status/1267531267664379904?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2020</a></blockquote>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/6lgM-dvGYX6MOPD4kDHwAHnGx2s=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/2XCFPFQR5VBQXLDPGVE2VS52G4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A protester of the death of George Floyd stands on his car as he and others demonstrate Sunday, May 31, 2020, in Miami. Floyd died May 25 after he was pinned at the neck by a Minneapolis police officer. (AP Photo/Wilfredo Lee)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Wilfredo Lee]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Miami Dolphins announce program to provide jobs, feed 1,000 families each weekday for a year</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/05/27/miami-dolphins-announce-program-to-provide-jobs-feed-1000-families-each-weekday-for-a-year/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/05/27/miami-dolphins-announce-program-to-provide-jobs-feed-1000-families-each-weekday-for-a-year/</guid><dc:creator>David Dwork</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 20:04:30 +0000</pubDate><description>Miami Dolphins owner Stephen Ross and the Miami Dolphins Foundation have found a way to feed South Florida families while at the same time providing jobs to many who need them.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Miami Dolphins owner Stephen Ross and the Miami Dolphins Foundation have found a way to feed South Florida families while at the same time providing jobs to many who need them. </p><p>Starting on June 1, and for up to 12 months, the Miami Dolphins Foundation Food Relief Program will provide a minimum of 1,000 meals every weekday out of Hard Rock Stadium. </p><p>Ross and the organization have committed $2 million to the program, and Ross will also be matching all donations in an attempt to raise an additional $2 million for the cause. </p><p>"We are committed to combating food insecurity and helping to provide consistent employment as the first step in rebuilding our community, starting in Miami Gardens," said Ross. "We are thankful for the strength that our community has shown through this pandemic and it’s our hope that this program will inspire others to give."</p><p>The meals will be prepared by Centerplate, the team's food, beverage and retail partner. </p><p>In an additional effort to help local businesses, every Sunday the Dolphins will team up with area churches, community groups and local leadership to order food from various local restaurants.</p><p>A minimum of 1,000 meals will be purchased each Sunday and distributed to residents dealing with food insecurity. </p><p>For more information on how to donate, visit <a href="http://dolphins.com/meals" target="_blank">dolphins.com/meals</a>. </p><p><iframe allowfullscreen="" data-original-height="2000" data-original-width="1280" frameborder="0" height="1500" mozallowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" src="https://www.thinglink.com/card/1291074429790453762" type="text/html" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="960"></iframe></p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Iv-N0feO63cxrJSVLuR567vwKTU=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/5LN2G7ABHBFC3OJTW6IKC4KED4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[MIAMI GARDENS, FL - SEPTEMBER 01: A general view of Hard Rock Stadium during a preseason game between the Miami Dolphins and the Tennessee Titans on September 1, 2016 in Miami Gardens, Florida. (Photo by Mike Ehrmann/Getty Images)]]></media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Dolphins legend Jason Taylor to host virtual poker tournament for charity </title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/05/26/dolphins-legend-jason-taylor-to-host-virtual-poker-tournament-for-charity/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/05/26/dolphins-legend-jason-taylor-to-host-virtual-poker-tournament-for-charity/</guid><dc:creator>Will Manso</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 21:31:33 +0000</pubDate><description>Dolphins great Jason Taylor will host his charity poker tournament tomorrow night from his house.  Well, at least via zoom.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dolphins great Jason Taylor will host his charity poker tournament tomorrow night from his house. Well, at least via zoom.</p><p>"With this current environment we live in, everything is from home," Taylor explained.</p><p>The Hall of Fame defensive end is inviting everyone to take part in his first virtual charitable event. As always, Taylor is All-In for Literacy. That’s the name of this event. </p><p>He’s raised money over the years for kids in need for reading programs, and it’s even more important in a world disrupted by the coronavirus pandemic.</p><p>"I think it creates a challenge for everybody but particularly the kids that needed extra help and needed extra guidance. We’ve been providing that at the reading room in Miramar for over a decade. We had to recreate how are we are still going to make this service available," Taylor said.</p><p>Through his foundation, they’re still finding ways to work with kids by using technology. Now, it’s technology that will allow us to see if the football great is any good at poker.</p><p>"It’ll be fun either way. I never expect to win these things. I have to let somebody else win. I can’t always win," Taylor joked.</p><p>You can still take part in the tournament. The suggested donation is $99 per player and you can visit <a href="http://jasontaylorfoundation.com" target="_blank">jasontaylorfoundation.com</a> for more information.</p><p>The tournament is scheduled to start at 6:30 p.m. on Wednesday.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/oXo_6fhpxCYCBgp3YL58cF-YkhY=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/BWWDH777SZBDFD3SGYGLKDESLE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Former Dolphins defensive end Jason Taylor talks with the media Thursday at Fins camp in Davie, Fla.]]></media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Miami Dolphins to turn Hard Rock Stadium into drive-in movie theater</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/05/26/miami-dolphins-to-turn-hard-rock-stadium-into-drive-in-movie-theater/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/05/26/miami-dolphins-to-turn-hard-rock-stadium-into-drive-in-movie-theater/</guid><dc:creator>David Dwork</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 19:46:51 +0000</pubDate><description>The Miami Dolphins are opening up Hard Rock Stadium to host drive-in movies.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Miami Dolphins are opening up their home and offering South Floridians a way to get out of the house, be entertained and remain safe and socially distant. </p><p>The team announced plans for The Outdoor Theaters at Hard Rock Stadium on Tuesday. </p><p>The plans include an open-air theater and a drive-in theater. </p><p>According to the team, featured items would include "classic Miami Dolphins content from the team’s 54-year history, classic motion picture films, host commencement ceremonies and other events."</p><p>"We’ve spent several weeks planning this to be able to provide people with a safe option to go out and enjoy movies, classic Dolphins content, concerts, and celebrate 2020 graduates," said Miami Dolphins and Hard Rock Stadium Vice Chairman and CEO Tom Garfinkel. "It’s a fundamental human need to physically experience and celebrate events and experiences together, and we’re trying to provide options for everyone where they can be safely socially distant and socially present at the same time."</p><p>Additional amenities include delivery service for food and drinks, and available restrooms. </p><p>The drive-in events held inside the stadium can accommodate up to 230 cars, according to the team. </p><p>The open-air theater is intended for smaller groups and is located on the south plaza of the stadium complex. </p><p>An open date for the theaters has not been announced. </p><p>Additional information can be found by <a href="https://hardrockstadium.com/Theater/" target="_blank">clicking here</a>. </p><p><b>MORE: </b>The team released several renderings, which can be seen below.</p><img alt="Hard Rock Stadium Drive-In Rendering" height="432" src="https://www.local10.com/resizer/XhZTBUt-UpJKN9MY_-7E57qx59E=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/IMPKDZ3UDVEUPNDDVRFIYC2AEY.jpg" width="768"/><br/><caption>Hard Rock Stadium Drive-In Rendering</caption><img alt="Hard Rock Stadium Drive-In Rendering" height="576" src="https://www.local10.com/resizer/MUjEXtN1YTLpxQhndz6vkRuqcsA=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/YNBJMGGY3RAAXDQYHHR25QSSKQ.jpg" width="1024"/><br/><caption>Hard Rock Stadium Drive-In Rendering</caption><img alt="Hard Rock Stadium Drive-In Rendering" height="576" src="https://www.local10.com/resizer/08XXu3eqpUa1vNHhaTiN8ZonJ2c=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/UDWTXZGXTRGETADIVSHMJS4BPM.jpg" width="1024"/><br/><caption>Hard Rock Stadium Drive-In Rendering</caption><img alt="Hard Rock Stadium Drive-In Rendering" height="576" src="https://www.local10.com/resizer/8IVTob74u5-7Wbdm7WiS9OhXKjQ=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/G2VQOQL3RNBCTAKUJ62N3RR464.jpg" width="1024"/><br/><caption>Hard Rock Stadium Drive-In Rendering</caption><img alt="Hard Rock Stadium Drive-In Rendering" height="432" src="https://www.local10.com/resizer/ZSVLx1upr0Vkgf1wRGp0fXlmYI0=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/QDGTQ6W4XRCO3LJQQJPC4THNDQ.jpg" width="768"/><br/><caption>Hard Rock Stadium Drive-In Rendering</caption>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/RHui0NUD4nLhUGAh4YED_LxZ1zQ=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/CW4ELXEMN5E2ZHBEZVTYO3W3EM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Hard Rock Stadium Drive-In Rendering]]></media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Dolphins owner Stephen Ross says there ‘definitely’ will be an NFL season</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/05/26/dolphins-owner-stephen-ross-says-there-definitely-will-be-an-nfl-season/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/05/26/dolphins-owner-stephen-ross-says-there-definitely-will-be-an-nfl-season/</guid><dc:creator>David Lang</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 17:16:02 +0000</pubDate><description>Dolphins owner Stephen Ross has made it very clear that he believes the NFL season will go forward. Ross appeared on CNBC on Tuesday morning.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dolphins owner Stephen Ross has made it very clear that he believes the NFL season will go forward.</p><p>Ross appeared on CNBC on Tuesday morning and said there will “definitely” be a season in 2020.</p><p>The question becomes, will there be fans in the stands if the NFL proceeds?</p><p>Ross said that the team was putting in place plans to have fans, however, that has not yet been determined.</p><p>While the COVID-19 outbreak started in the middle of the season for the NBA, MLS, and NHL, the National Football League was in the offseason when it began.</p><p>The NFL was able to move forward with both the start of free agency and a virtual NFL draft.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/5nnDuR7j4uTQ6A1sBb_QhE6H0lc=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/BSJAVHQEHNBSVO7VFMNB5WUGJQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Feb. 4, 2019, file photo, Miami Dolphin's owner Stephen Ross speaks during a news conference in Davie, Fla. Ross says he's confident the NFL will play in 2020, with or without spectators. I think there definitely will be a football season this year, Ross said Tuesday, May 26, 2020, during an interview on CNBC. The real question is will there be fans in the stadiums?"(AP Photo/Brynn Anderson, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Brynn Anderson]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Dolphins’ Ryan Fitzpatrick discusses his beard, offseason work, and Tua</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/05/21/fitzpatrick-discusses-his-beard-offseason-work-and-tua/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/05/21/fitzpatrick-discusses-his-beard-offseason-work-and-tua/</guid><dc:creator>David Lang</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 21:31:33 +0000</pubDate><description>Miami Dolphins quarterback Ryan Fitzpatrick has been growing out his beard this offseason and preparing for the 2020 season, when he'll be a mentor to rookie Tua Tagovailoa.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ryan Fitzpatrick has been growing out his beard this offseason and preparing for 2020.</p><p>The Dolphins’ veteran quarterback first addressed his beard, Thursday: “Ever since they shut down barbershops. There’s only two people in the country that I trust to touch this thing. One is in Tampa, one is in New Jersey, it’s been going ever since everything’s been shut down. The neck hair is out of control, I’m glad you can’t see it.”</p><p>Fitzpatrick said he wasn’t surprised that the Dolphins drafted a QB with the No. 5 pick.</p><p>The veteran said he’s been in this situation before.</p><p>He said he wants to be a mentor to the younger quarterbacks.</p><p>Fitzpatrick said, “Just try to go in every day and be myself. Even the zoom meetings right now. I go in and try to help them.”</p><p>Fitzpatrick likes to teach the younger players his thought process.</p><p>Fitzpatrick said of Tua Tagovailoa, “I’m excited for him to be here. I loved watching him play in college. I think he’s going to be an awesome addition to the team for a long time.”</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/XYW9fRk11AX33PY7RPwPK8fii50=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/B245QHQUBNCCTAXCI2PSO7LN4E.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Ryan Fitzpatrick talks to reporters on Thursday.]]></media:description></media:content></item></channel></rss>