<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"><channel><title>WPLG Local 10</title><link>https://www.local10.com</link><atom:link href="https://www.local10.com/arcio/rss/category/news/?size=10" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>WPLG Local 10 News Feed</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:53:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><ttl>1</ttl><sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod><sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency><item><title>Florida man arrested after allegedly going on gun-toting rant, yelling racial slur at random Miami-Dade resident</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/florida-man-arrested-after-allegedly-going-on-gun-toting-rant-yelling-racial-slur-at-random-miami-dade-resident/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/florida-man-arrested-after-allegedly-going-on-gun-toting-rant-yelling-racial-slur-at-random-miami-dade-resident/</guid><dc:creator>Roy Ramos</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:15:01 +0000</pubDate><description>A South Florida man is in trouble with the law after going on racist rant and pulling out a gun.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A South Florida man is in trouble with the law after yelling a racial slur and going on a rant while holding a gun.</p><p>It all happened in the West Little River neighborhood of Northwest Miami Dade County back on June 14th. </p><p>According to the resident, Dewayne Wynn, he was talking to his neighbor when he saw an SUV pull up to his home and drop a flyer into his mailbox. </p><p>But when Wynn walked across the street to get the flier, he said he was confronted by a man who pulled a gun out on him and then began shouting racial slurs. </p><p>Part of that rant was captured on cell phone video taken by Wynn.</p><p>The man seen in that video is 58-year-old Joseph Fucheck, who Local 10 News discovered is a real-estate agent in North Miami Beach. </p><p>In that cell phone video, Fucheck can be heard telling Wynn it is not his home and he does not live there.  All this while brandishing a handgun. </p><p>Fucheck goes on to say he was a former Navy Seal and a former member of the Hillsboro County SWAT Team. Local 10 is working to confirm that information. </p><p>Eventually Fucheck drives off, but not before Wynn said he yelled a racial slur.</p><p>Fucheck was ultimately arrested and charged with aggravated assault with a firearm and with prejudice, and possession of a firearm by a convicted felon. He remains in Miami-Dade County Jail with no bond. </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fort Lauderdale officer charged with battery for pushing woman at protest</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/fort-lauderdale-officer-charged-with-battery-for-pushing-woman-at-protest/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/fort-lauderdale-officer-charged-with-battery-for-pushing-woman-at-protest/</guid><dc:creator>David Selig</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 23:16:02 +0000</pubDate><description>Steven Pohorence, the Fort Lauderdale police officer who was seen on video pushing a female protester May 31, is being charged with battery, Broward State Attorney Mike Satz announced Tuesday.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Fort Lauderdale police officer who was seen on video <a href="https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/01/video-shows-officer-pushing-woman-during-fort-lauderdale-protests/" target="_blank">pushing a female protester May 31</a> is being charged with battery, Broward State Attorney Mike Satz announced Tuesday.</p><p>Officer Steven Pohorence, 29, is charged with battery for “intentionally touching or striking” the 19-year-old woman by “pushing [the victim] to the ground,” according to court records.</p><p>The video was first obtained by Local 10 News’ Jeff Weinsier from another protester. It shows Pohorence shoving a woman around the time when what had been a peaceful protest in Fort Lauderdale against racial inequality <a href="https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/05/31/second-day-of-protests-over-death-of-george-floyd-begin-in-parts-of-miami-dade-broward/">turned contentious outside a parking garage</a> at SE 2nd Street and SE 1st Avenue near the Broward County Main Library.</p><p>Prosecutors filed the charging document in Broward County Court on Tuesday after an investigation by the Florida Department of Law Enforcement, Satz’s office said.</p><p>The battery charge is a first-degree misdemeanor, which carries a maximum punishment of up to one year in jail. Prosecutors say they decided to file a misdemeanor charge after reviewing the victim’s medical records to see if her injury fell under the legal requirements for a misdemeanor or felony.</p><p>A date has not yet been scheduled for Pohorence to appear in court.</p><p>The day after the incident, Pohorence was removed from duty with pay as the investigation was launched. As a result of state attorney’s decision to charge Pohorence, Fort Lauderdale Police Chief Rick Magilone said Tuesday night that the officer is now on administrative leave without pay. </p><p>“At the conclusion of the process being led by the State Attorney’s Office, our Office of Internal Affairs will complete an administrative investigation to determine if any departmental policies were violated,” Maglione said in a statement. </p><p>Prosecutors say videos of other incidents of use of force by Pohorence remain under review. Magilone <a href="https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/23/watch-live-chief-discusses-officer-who-pushed-black-lives-matter-protester/" target="_blank">released two bodycam videos last week</a> of incidents unrelated to the shoving of the protester.</p><p>“These videos are concerning his response to resistance and the general manner in which those incidents were handled,” Magilone said then.</p><p>Pohorence has been a member of the Fort Lauderdale Police Department since October 2016, and prior to that, he spent almost four years working for the Florida Highway Patrol.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Parents, teachers in Broward County say students should go back to class full-time </title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/parents-teachers-in-broward-county-say-students-should-go-back-to-class-full-time/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/parents-teachers-in-broward-county-say-students-should-go-back-to-class-full-time/</guid><dc:creator>Layron Livingston</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 22:47:33 +0000</pubDate><description>The Broward County School District has sent out a questionnaire to parents asking what they think school should look like in the fall.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Broward County School District has sent out a questionnaire to parents asking what they think school should look like in the fall.</p><p>The district presented four options:</p><p>1) Distance or electronic learning, which is what students have been doing since the pandemic started.</p><p>2) Full-time, in class instruction.</p><p>3) A combination of in-class and virtual learning</p><p>4) Broward virtual school, which many students already participate in, but those programs aren’t affiliated with a specific campus.</p><p>That questionnaire got a lot of parents and teachers riled up.</p><p>Many of them showed up outside the School Board building Tuesday with signs.</p><p>They were chanting and overwhelmingly calling for in-class, five days a week instruction.</p><p>They say there are ways to do it safely, following CDC guidelines.</p><p>The parents and teachers who participated in the protest are concerned about widening learning gaps and future impacts. They say children are just not learning at home.</p><p>“Kids are safer in school,” one teacher, Kelly Blaire, said. “There’s parents that have to work. They’re leaving the kids home alone. They’re safer in school. Some of these kids don’t eat unless they’re in school. Some, they don’t get attention, they don’t get hugs, they don’t get praises unless they’re in school. They’re safer, they’re healthier in school.”</p><p>Broward County Public Schools spokeswoman Kathy Koch said school officials are still researching different possibilities and appreciate the input.</p><p>“This is not a done deal,” she said. “We can’t make the decision without our parents. It’s for our parents and for our students.”</p><p>The parents who came out Tuesday also came with expert opinion from the American Academy of Pediatrics, which has also outlined steps schools should take at different grade levels with the pandemic in mind.</p><p>But the organization “strongly advocates that all policy considerations for the coming school year should start with a goal of having students physically present in school.”</p><p>The issue is one of the items expected to be discussed at Tuesday’s board meeting.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Coronavirus educational effort goes door to door at Miami-Dade’s hot zones</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/coronavirus-hot-zones-surge-team-focuses-on-miami-dades-33136-33142-33030-zip-codes/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/coronavirus-hot-zones-surge-team-focuses-on-miami-dades-33136-33142-33030-zip-codes/</guid><dc:creator>Christina Vazquez, Andrea Torres</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 22:23:44 +0000</pubDate><description>The members of the new Surge Teams are going door to door in Miami-Dade County neighborhoods where the coronavirus pandemic has had the most impact. They are visiting residences in Allapattah on Tuesday and Liberty City on Wednesday.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The members of the new Surge Teams are going door to door in Miami-Dade County neighborhoods where the coronavirus pandemic has had the most impact. They are visiting residences in Allapattah on Tuesday and Liberty City on Wednesday.</p><p>Their mission is to prevent more infections by reminding residents to distance themselves from others at least six feet, to wear a face mask, avoid touching their face and wash their hands frequently. They are also distributing face masks, hand sanitizer and educational materials.</p><p>According to Juan Diasgranados, a spokesman for the Miami-Dade Corrections &amp; Rehabilitation Department, the teams are focusing on zip codes 33136, 33142 and 33030. He didn’t specify where the outbreaks are.</p><p>Zip code 33136 includes Jackson Memorial Hospital and the historic Spring Garden and Overtown neighborhoods.</p><p>Zip code 33142 includes the Miami International Airport’s Rental Car Center and Transit Station, the Casino Miami, Jackson Memorial Long-Term Care Center in Allapattah and Brownsville, a neighborhood with several affordable housing projects.</p><p>Zip code 33030 includes farms, wholesale plant nurseries and <a href="https://chisouthfl.org/mlk-clinica-health-center/" target="_blank">CHI Martin Luther King Jr. Clinica Campesina</a>, an urgent care center that provides services to Homestead’s agricultural workers.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>South Florida hospitals track rising coronavirus cases: ‘It is already tight'</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/south-florida-hospitals-track-rising-coronavirus-cases-it-is-already-tight/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/south-florida-hospitals-track-rising-coronavirus-cases-it-is-already-tight/</guid><dc:creator>Glenna Milberg</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 22:16:14 +0000</pubDate><description></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Protecting COVID-19 hospital capacity is getting harder.</p><p>Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis said Tuesday that “we are very well positioned to handle what comes down the pike.” </p><p>But, statewide, hospital capacity is either wide open or tight, depending on geography.</p><p>In the state’s coronavirus capital, South Florida, the numbers trend in a concerning direction.</p><p>“If we continue at the rate we are today, there will be a very high climb, and I don’t know about not having enough beds, but it is already tight,” said Carlos Migoya, president and CEO of Jackson Health System.</p><p>Tuesday marks two weeks of slow but significant and consistent climb in hospital admissions.</p><p>Memorial Healthcare System Senior VP and Chief Medical Office Stanley Marks says “the hospitals have an ability to both staff up and surge up, in terms of new ICU beds or new beds.”</p><p>Not including that surge capacity, real-time numbers Tuesday night show South Florida hospital bed availability hovering around 20-30 percent.</p><p>The field hospital set up at the Miami Beach Convention Center in case of potential overflow has not yet had patients and remains at the ready.</p><p>“If we protect the vulnerable, we’re going to be able to get thru this patch adequately,” DeSantis said. He repeated Tuesday that there are no plans to roll back reopening measures.</p><p>Though the spiking COVID-19 cases include many younger patients, they too account for hospital admissions — and the spread that concerns those managing the medical front lines.</p><p>“We need to figure out how to slow down that infection rate that’s happening out there that’s creating the sickness that makes the people need to be hospitalized,” Migoya said.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>THE LATEST: Coronavirus: Cases in Miami-Dade, Broward cities</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/03/29/the-numbers-how-many-coronavirus-cases-in-my-city/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/03/29/the-numbers-how-many-coronavirus-cases-in-my-city/</guid><dc:creator>Michelle Solomon</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 22:07:24 +0000</pubDate><description>By the numbers. How many cases of coronavirus are in my city? The Florida Department of Health has the test results.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>UPDATED: 5:27 p.m., Tuesday, June 30</b></p><p>Here are the number of coronavirus cases in individual cities in Miami-Dade and Broward County, Florida, from data verified as <u><b>of Tuesday, June 30 </b></u>from <a href="http://www.floridahealth.gov/">Florida Department of Health</a>. (County list numbers released earlier than city by city.) <i><b>The information below includes the cities in Broward County and Miami-Dade County for cases of Florida residents based on zip code of person tested. </b></i><i>Numbers are from results received by the Florida Department of Health from the state public health laboratory (BPHL) as well as commercial and hospital labs. No change in number or low number does not mean no new cases of COVID-19; reports may be pending. </i><b>(*</b><a href="http://local10.com/" target="_blank"><b>Local10.com</b></a><b>’s cases’ list is updated as soon as Florida Department of Health releases daily numbers.)</b></p><p><b>RELATED</b>: <a href="https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/04/04/florida-coronavirus-map-listing-cases-by-zip-code/" target="_blank">Florida coronavirus cases: Department of Health list by zip code</a></p><p><b>Where to get tested in South Florida. </b><a href="https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/03/20/map-shows-drive-through-testing-locations-in-florida/" target="_blank">Check the list.</a></p><p><i><b>(*Now in our chart, number of tests recorded along with results)</b></i></p><p></p><p>Check more statistics at <a href="https://fdoh.maps.arcgis.com/apps/opsdashboard/index.html#/8d0de33f260d444c852a615dc7837c86">Florida’s COVID-19 Data and Surveillance Dashboard.</a></p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/ePqmaSAZYVky1cn7IP_thwuEEq0=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/32RNTMQCOJC2LJ4G2IXSYKYDFU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Swabs and test tube kit to test people for COVID-19, the disease that is caused by the new coronavirus]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Paul Sancya]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Coronavirus: Hialeah officials aim to stem flow of new COVID-19 cases in city with numerous long-term care facilities</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/coronavirus-hialeah-officials-aim-to-stem-flow-of-new-covid-19-cases-in-city-with-numerous-long-term-care-facilities/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/coronavirus-hialeah-officials-aim-to-stem-flow-of-new-covid-19-cases-in-city-with-numerous-long-term-care-facilities/</guid><dc:creator>Ian Margol</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 21:57:43 +0000</pubDate><description>Deaths of patients at long-term care facilities make up more than half of all of the COVID-19 deaths in the state.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Deaths of patients at long-term care facilities make up more than half of all of the COVID-19 deaths in the state.</p><p>According to Hialeah's mayor, the city is home to the most long-term care facilities per capita in all of Florida, which is why officials are trying to stem the flow of new COVID-19 cases ravaging them. </p><p>Daylet Collazo gushes about her grandmother, Olga Rodriguez, who was one of the many residents of long-term care facilities in Florida who have been killed by the novel coronavirus. </p><p>"My grandmother was the sweetest, nicest person anyone can ever meet," she said. </p><p>Rodriguez had dementia and couldn’t walk, but otherwise, Collazo describes her as a healthy 81-year-old woman, living at the Hialeah Nursing and Rehabilitation Center.</p><p>"She was strong, she had her talking," said Collazo. "She was such a sweet, little old lady."</p><p>Then, COVID-19 began hitting long-term care facilities in South Florida and, unfortunately, Rodriguez became one of the victims.</p><p>On May 22nd she was hospitalized. Collazo said her grandmother had pneumonia and could barely breathe. About a month later, she passed away.</p><p>Collazo feels that the facility her grandmother was living in could have gotten her emergency medical treatment sooner and done more to help her.</p><p>"When I received the phone call at June 23 at 4:30 in the morning, it was like they killed me, because I received a call from the hospital that she had passed away, because they took her from me, there was no reason," she said. </p><p>In response, the facility sent a statement about the large number of cases they’ve seen, saying in part:</p><p>"Hialeah Nursing and Rehabilitation Center remains committed to the care and safety of our residents and staff, and we continue taking critical steps to keep them protected, following all CDC guidelines and working with our state and local health officials and regulatory partners."</p><p>In Miami-Dade County there have been more than 500 deaths at long-term care facilities, and two out of the three facilities with the highest number of deaths in the entire state are in Hialeah (the third is in Miami Springs). </p><p>Hialeah Mayor Carlos Hernandez said when the pandemic started, staff members at certain facilities were positive for the virus without knowing and spreading it to their patients. </p><p>Now he said more stringent guidelines from the state, as well as a new effort on the city's side, will hopefully see the number of new cases slow down. </p><p>"We all know that these places have been the worst hit and we want to stay ahead of that," Hernandez said. "We've actually formed a task force to assist the state, ACA, in making sure we can identify any place where there is a hot spot."</p><p>State guidelines are that long-term care facility staff be tested for COVID-19 every 14 days, but the City of Hialeah is going to push for them to be tested every five to seven days. </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Coronavirus in Florida: With eviction protections ending, many who lost their job fear living without a home</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/coronavirus-in-florida-with-eviction-protections-ending-many-who-lost-their-job-fear-living-without-a-home/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/coronavirus-in-florida-with-eviction-protections-ending-many-who-lost-their-job-fear-living-without-a-home/</guid><dc:creator>Amy Viteri</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 21:51:58 +0000</pubDate><description>Countless Floridians are facing uncertainty due to the state’s moratorium on non-payment evictions ending on Wednesday.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Countless Floridians are facing uncertainty due to the state’s moratorium on non-payment evictions ending on Wednesday. </p><p>One South Florida woman told Local 10 News her landlord has already tried to kick her out. </p><p>Adele Penny received a notice to get out of her Hialeah rental home in May, despite an official freeze on evictions for non-payment during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p><p>“It’s like life and death you are going to kick me and my family out on the streets because you can’t get a couple hundred dollars,” she said. </p><p>Penny said her daughters had been helping her make ends meet before the pandemic. She had agreed with her landlord to move out of by March, but then came the novel coronavirus. Both daughters lost their jobs and Penny has been unable to find one. </p><p>Attorney Guerby Noel represents Penny and got her case dismissed. That’s because since March, non-payment eviction cases are suspended under an executive order issued by Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis. </p><p>"They found themselves in their current situation whereby they are unemployed with no means of actually paying the event through no fault of their own," said Noel. </p><p>The governor extended that order last month, but it’s now set to expire by Wednesday. Unfortunately, for many renters like Penny, the situation has not improved.</p><p>“I don’t know where my fate is, what’s next for me, what do I do now,” Penny said. </p><p>As coronavirus cases continue to climb, Noel predicts so will the number of people out of work, now potentially without any protection to keep them in their homes. </p><p>“There are many landlords out there that are waiting in the wings to file their evictions, and all things point to there being an avalanche of eviction cases for non-payment,” Noel said. </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>State budget cuts will affect dozens of South Florida services</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/state-budget-cuts-will-affect-dozens-of-south-florida-services/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/state-budget-cuts-will-affect-dozens-of-south-florida-services/</guid><dc:creator>Hatzel Vela</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 21:47:19 +0000</pubDate><description>Gov. Ron DeSantis cut $1 billion in spending from the state budget that runs from July 1 through June 30, 2021, partly because of shortfalls caused by the coronavirus pandemic.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Who could forget the smile, and the heartbreak we all felt back in 2013 when we lost 10-year-old <a href="https://www.local10.com/news/2013/05/29/bella-rodriguez-torres-dies-after-6-year-cancer-battle/" target="_blank">Bella Rodriguez-Torres</a>?</p><p>Her six-year battle with cancer is what sparked the <a href="https://livelikebella.org/" target="_blank">Live Like Bella</a> childhood cancer foundation. The foundations has grown to the point where it now provides services in more than 30 countries.</p><p>But it will lose $750,000 in state funding after Gov. Ron DeSantis cut $1 billion in spending from the state budget that runs from July 1 through June 30, 2021, partly because of shortfalls caused by the coronavirus pandemic. </p><p>“It is very devastating and very hard to hear that this cut happens, because it will very significantly impact the way Live Like Bella can continue to support families that are going through the worse battle imaginable,” said Raymond Rodriguez-Torres, Bella’s father and the foundation’s chairman. “These children need us now more than ever. And we won’t stop.”</p><p>The foundation is not alone in feeling the state’s budget crunch. Out of an 18-page list of vetoes, over 100 entities in South Florida are affected.</p><p>The Miami-Dade Homeless Trust wanted $250,000 for what they call permanent supportive housing, the bridge housing program for homeless people who don’t do well in a congregate living facility. </p><p>“We would have used the funds to prefund these immediate placement options at places like Camillus Somerville, which is essentially like paying rent in an apartment but in a setting that is very close in supervision,” said Ron Book, chairman of <a href="http://www.homelesstrust.org/home.asp" target="_blank">the Homeless Trust</a>. </p><p>“Like everybody else’s revenue, our revenue is shrinking as well.”</p><p>Because the Homeless Trust gets its funding from county food and beverage tax, the money has dried up. And they recently had to find more than $7 million to cut.</p><p>Some other examples of cuts that affect South Florida include:</p><ul><li>Broward County’s health department is not getting $800,000 they requested for their HIV test and treatment program. </li><li>FIU will not be getting $3.1 million meant for scholarships and STEM (science, technology, engineering and math) initiatives. </li><li>South Florida Behavioral Network won’t be getting $4 million. </li><li>And the city of Homestead is not getting $500,000 for their breast cancer screening. </li></ul><p><b>See the full 2020 veto list below:</b></p><p><iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" data-aspect-ratio="0.7729220222793488" data-auto-height="true" frameborder="0" height="600" scrolling="no" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/467518069/content?start_page=1&amp;view_mode=scroll&amp;access_key=key-VXup1tZgbpKJ9J2wzGaK" title="Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis budget veto list for 2020" width="100%"></iframe></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Officer faces charges for firing service weapon outside while drunk in Miami Gardens</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/officer-faces-charges-for-firing-service-weapon-outside-while-drunk-in-miami-gardens/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/30/officer-faces-charges-for-firing-service-weapon-outside-while-drunk-in-miami-gardens/</guid><dc:creator>Roy Ramos</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 21:11:06 +0000</pubDate><description>Miami Gardens Police Department officers recently responded to the home of a Miami-Dade County correctional officer after a gunshot detection system went off.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Miami Gardens Police Department officers recently responded to the home of a Miami-Dade County correctional officer after a gunshot detection system went off. </p><p>According to the arrest form, Donald White had red glossy eyes, he wasn’t able to stand on his own, he had slurred speech and a strong odor of alcohol. It was at about 4 p.m. </p><p>“I was just [expletive] around. I shot a couple of times here in the bushes,” White said, according to the officer’s report, adding White was in possession of a Glock 19, his service weapon. </p><p>The Miami-Dade Corrections &amp; Rehabilitation Department’s Internal Affairs Unit and the Miami Gardens Police Department are investigating White, according to Juan Diasgranados, a Miami-Dade County spokesman.</p><p>Records show officers arrested White on May 21 and prosecutors filed the case on June 8. White is facing one count of using a firearm while under the influence and one count of discharging a firearm while in public.  </p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Eh1XHKd_oOdlgcCd0FmHoFdr60s=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/VTJU2PO7LZBHLPJ24KT3KXT4CU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Lights atop a police cruiser flash at the scene of a crime in this undated file image.]]></media:description></media:content></item></channel></rss>