<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"><channel><title>WPLG Local 10</title><link>https://www.local10.com</link><atom:link href="https://www.local10.com/arcio/rss/category/sports/?size=10" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>WPLG Local 10 News Feed</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:57:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><ttl>1</ttl><sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod><sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency><item><title>Teams not able to disclose who goes on IL due to virus</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/teams-not-able-to-disclose-who-goes-on-il-due-to-virus/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/teams-not-able-to-disclose-who-goes-on-il-due-to-virus/</guid><dc:creator>Joe Reedy, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:38:05 +0000</pubDate><description>New York Yankees general manager Brian Cashman says teams have not been given clearance to announce which players wind up on the injured list due to COVID-19.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Trying to find out the status of a baseball player coming back from an ankle injury definitely will be easier than learning whether someone tested positive for the coronavirus.</p><p>Major League Baseball said Tuesday that a team will not specifically announce a COVID-19 injured list placement for a player who is removed from the club after testing positive, just an IL trip.</p><p>MLB's operations manual says a positive test, exhibiting symptoms that require isolation for additional assessment or exposure to someone who has had the virus are cause for placement on the new COVID-19 IL.</p><p>“It would be a speculating circumstance," Yankees general manager Brian Cashman told media during a conference call.</p><p>Baseball’s collective bargaining agreement states that for any medical condition not related to employment “a club may disclose only the fact that a medical condition is preventing the player from rendering services to the club and the anticipated length of the player’s absence from the club.” </p><p>Cashman noted the situation continues to evolve as MLB and the players' union continue discussions. Testing of players and staff will begin Wednesday as they report to their teams to resume workouts. They will be tested once every two days.</p><p>Last week, <a href="https://apnews.com/dd0357da156125c19953a4afab6a1e2c">Charlie Blackmon of the Colorado Rockies</a> became the first MLB player known to have tested positive. According to reports, the All-Star outfielder was one of three Colorado players to have a positive test.</p><p>Numerous other teams have said they have players who have tested positive for the virus without identifying any of them. The Philadelphia Phillies announced seven, while the Detroit Tigers said one player who was living in Florida but not working out at the team’s spring training facilities in Lakeland also tested positive.</p><p>Seattle Mariners general manager Jerry Dipoto said a few players have tested positive but declined to specify how many. Several Toronto Blue Jays players and staff members also have tested positive.</p><p>Mets general manager Brodie Van Wagenen said remaining educated about best practices is going to be crucial for everyone.</p><p>“Leadership really is going to be the difference-maker for the teams that are able to best handle this and best cope with the challenges that we face,” he said. "And that really is the accountability that needs to be shared by all of us — not just baseball, but our whole society.”</p><p>Baltimore general manager Mike Elias said the Orioles have had no reported cases and that no one on the team has decided against playing in the shortened season.</p><p>He’s hoping for a smooth start to the camp that’s scheduled to begin Friday at Camden Yards.</p><p>“We recognize that this will be fluid and everyone is having to make personal decisions and circumstances might not be fully understood until the season starts, but so far we are expecting full participation,” Elias said. “You see in the news around the league that’s not the case everywhere and I wouldn’t be shocked if that ends up happening, but that’s going to be part of this.”</p><p>“We’re not pressuring anyone or shaming anyone that feels they shouldn’t be here. We’re making that known, and I think it’s well-received,” Elias added. “Our players have been itching to play for a while. I think the whole delay was frustrating for them, for us, and everyone just wants to go play.”</p><p>Marlins CEO Derek Jeter is hoping the return of baseball can provide some solace, much like the Yankees did when they returned after 9-11.</p><p>“We were thinking as players, ‘Do we even play? What does it mean? We’re playing a game.’ Talking to family members who had lost family members and them thanking us — ‘What are you thanking us for?’ They said, ‘We’re thanking you because you’re giving us something to cheer for. There haven’t been too many happy days around here,’" Jeter said. "Baseball played a big role, at least in New York, in the healing process. It’s not saying you’re ever going to forget what happened. But at least for three hours a day we have the opportunity to give them something to cheer for. We hope that’s the case here when we get going in a couple of weeks.”</p><p>___</p><p>AP Baseball Writers Ronald Blum, Mike Fitzpatrick and Ben Walker, and AP Sports Writers David Ginsburg and Steven Wine contributed to this report.</p><p>___</p><p>More AP MLB: https://apnews.com/MLB and https://twitter.com/AP_Sports</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/gfh-raFuXKOfM18JeIUwZr4tvUg=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/3IFGLFCDUFHC5ENPSJZKYONHWQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Sept. 11, 2019, file photo, Colorado Rockies right fielder Charlie Blackmon waits to enter the batting cage before the team's baseball game against the St. Louis Cardinals in Denver. All-Star outfielder Charlie Blackmon of the Colorado Rockies has become the first Major League Baseball player known to have tested positive for the coronavirus. A person familiar with Blackmons situation confirmed the test result to The Associated Press on condition of anonymity because there was no official announcement. (AP Photo/David Zalubowski, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[David Zalubowski]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Rockies GM supports Desmond's decision to skip '20 season </title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/07/01/rockies-gm-supports-desmonds-decision-to-skip-20-season/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/07/01/rockies-gm-supports-desmonds-decision-to-skip-20-season/</guid><dc:creator>Arnie Stapleton, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:21:33 +0000</pubDate><description>Colorado Rockies general manager Jeff Bridich says he supports outfielder Ian Desmond's decision to sit out the 2020 major league baseball season over concerns about the coronavirus pandemic and other issues in society.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Colorado Rockies general manager Jeff Bridich says he supports Ian Desmond’s decision to sit out the 2020 season to focus on his young family and help rejuvenate youth baseball in his hometown in Florida.</p><p>Bridich says he had a pair of recent conversations with the 34-year-old outfielder who announced his decision in a <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CCCp7aSptTr/?utm_source=ig_embed">lengthy and heartfelt Instagram post </a> Monday night.</p><p>Desmond wrote that the “COVID-19 pandemic has made this baseball season one that is a risk I am not comfortable taking.” The biracial slugger also mentioned a myriad of issues within baseball, including sexism, homophobia and socioeconomic concerns, as well as the racial reckoning that emerged after George Floyd’s death while in police custody in Minneapolis sparked protests around the world.</p><p>“The conversations with Ian felt the exact same that his written words feel to me,” Bridich said, “which is from the heart and honest. ... I did not know that he was going to write something as thoughtful and as comprehensive as (he did) but I’m not surprised.”</p><p>Desmond, who hit .255 with 20 homers in 140 games last season, had been due $5,555,556 for the prorated share of his $15 million salary, part of a $70 million, five-year contract. He is owed $8 million next year, and his deal includes a $15 million team option for 2022 with a $2 million buyout.</p><p>Opting out this summer doesn’t affect his 2021 status, nor does it affect his relationship with Bridich.</p><p>“Ian is extremely thoughtful in what he does, he’s thoughtful in how he prepares as a professional athlete, he’s thoughtful as a husband and a father ... he’s thoughtful about things that are bigger than him,” Bridich said. “And to this point, the reference has been the team or the clubhouse or the locker room, or things that affect the organization, his charity work, passion projects of his outside of the game of baseball.</p><p>“He’s willing to devote a lot of time and energy and thought to all of the things that he does. And so when you have somebody like that who is a professional athlete who is in the thick of it every day and trying to do the very best that he can to hold up his end of the bargain as an athlete, a teammate, a performer and then he’s always willing to think about other people on the team, in the organization and outside the organization, it’s easy to gravitate to people like that.”</p><p>Desmond complained about a lack of diversity in baseball and criticized the clubhouse atmosphere, saying it includes racism, sexism and homophobia. Bridich said Desmond didn’t complain specifically about the Rockies’ clubhouse, but Bridich did acknowledge the organization could be more diverse.</p><p>In his Instagram post, Desmond said he has been sharing more of his thoughts and experiences as a biracial man since Floyd’s death on May 25. Floyd, a Black man in handcuffs, died after a white police officer held his knee on Floyd’s neck for nearly eight minutes.</p><p>Desmond said his mind started racing during a recent visit to the Sarasota baseball fields that he played on as a kid. He wrote how they looked run down and neglected, and how important youth baseball was for him growing up.</p><p>Desmond said he wants to help Sarasota Youth Baseball get back on track.</p><p>Although Desmond’s decision is a big loss for Colorado, the Rockies on Tuesday agreed to a minor league deal with veteran Matt Kemp, who owns a .327 batting average with 21 home runs and 77 RBIs over 86 career games at Denver’s downtown ballpark. </p><p>“Yeah, we’re well aware of the damage that he’s done against us,” Bridich said. </p><p>Kemp, who is expected in Denver by Thursday, will have to earn his way onto the roster, and he’ll benefit from the National League using the designated hitter when pro baseball attempts to start the coronavirus-delayed season in late July.</p><p>“The DH is an obvious benefit in terms of his potential place on our major league roster,” Bridich said. “That was going to be the case whether Ian opted in or opted out, and so again, it’s a right-handed power bat. He’s got a sense of the strike zone, we’ve seen it for how many years? And he’s very motivated to get back on the field and continue his career and play well. Whether that’s in the outfield or only at DH, we have to let some weeks pass before we can make any decisions like that.”</p><p>___</p><p>Follow Arnie Melendrez Stapleton on Twitter: http://twitter.com/arniestapleton</p><p>___</p><p>More AP MLB: https://apnews.com/MLB and https://twitter.com/AP_Sports</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/4BK5YlbeAdRNzRVQmgxlmYP-pdk=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/5IJPU46LQZCANJJ3UWNUU2GARM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this July 29, 2019, file photo, Colorado Rockies' Ian Desmond follows the flight of his triple off Los Angeles Dodgers starting pitcher Kenta Maeda in the second inning of a baseball game in Denver. Desmond plans to sit out this season to be with his family and help the youth baseball program in his hometown in Florida. The 34-year-old Desmond wrote on Instagram that the COVID-19 pandemic has made this baseball season one that is a risk I am not comfortable taking. (AP Photo/David Zalubowski, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[David Zalubowski]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Tigers give $8.4M deal to Torkelson, who joins player pool</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/tigers-give-84m-deal-to-torkelson-who-joins-player-pool/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/tigers-give-84m-deal-to-torkelson-who-joins-player-pool/</guid><dc:creator>Noah Trister, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:14:31 +0000</pubDate><description>No. 1 overall draft pick Spencer Torkelson and the Detroit Tigers agreed to a minor league contract, and the team said the infielder will join its player pool for this abbreviated season.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No. 1 overall draft pick Spencer Torkelson and the Detroit Tigers agreed to a minor league contract on Tuesday, and the team said the infielder will join its player pool for this abbreviated season.</p><p>Torkelson's deal includes an $8,416,300 is a signing bonus, which is $1,000 above slot value, and a $2,500 contingent bonus for days on the roster of a minor league affiliate, which cannot be earned until 2021. He is to receive $100,000 within 30 days of the deal’s approval by Major League Baseball, and 50% of the rest on each July 1 in 2021 and 2022.</p><p>Detroit had the top pick for the second time in three years after drafting right-hander Casey Mize in 2018.</p><p>Undrafted out of high school, Torkelson hit 54 home runs at Arizona State. The Tigers took the slugging first baseman with the top pick, <a href="https://apnews.com/a941e91e943610d708d702d571bd6f69">then said</a> they intended to try him at third.</p><p>He'll get a chance to show what he can do, sooner rather than later. Detroit announced 58 selections for its player pool Sunday, leaving two spots open. On Tuesday, the Tigers said Torkelson will be added to that group.</p><p>The Tigers <a href="https://apnews.com/9f8f54a82d963805072f0a3b93f0ca8c">also included Mize</a> and several other top pitching prospects in that player pool, meaning it's possible that some of Detroit's biggest young names could reach the majors at some point this season.</p><p>Torkelson hit .340 with six home runs and 11 RBIs in 17 games this year during a college season shortened by the coronavirus pandemic.</p><p>___</p><p>Follow Noah Trister at https://twitter.com/noahtrister</p><p>___</p><p>More AP MLB: https://apnews.com/MLB and https://twitter.com/AP_Sports</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Yza2O0FX1bRjukjo_2bO-hbENzQ=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/NGZNPTAERFCALKDCUUFMRBEAQI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[In this Feb. 18, 2020 photo Arizona State infielder Spencer Torkelson makes a play during an NCAA college baseball game in Phoenix, Ariz. The Detroit Tigers agreed to terms Tuesday, June 30, 2020 with No. 1 overall draft pick Spencer Torkelson, and the team said he's joining the player pool for this abbreviated season. (AP Photo/Rick Scuteri)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rick Scuteri]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Baseball's minor leagues cancel 2020 seasons</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/baseballs-minor-leagues-cancel-2020-seasons/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/baseballs-minor-leagues-cancel-2020-seasons/</guid><dc:creator>Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:25:26 +0000</pubDate><description>Baseball’s minor leagues have canceled their seasons after Major League Baseball decided not to provide any players to its affiliated teams amid the coronavirus pandemic.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Baseball's minor leagues canceled their seasons Tuesday because of the coronavirus pandemic, and the head of their governing body said more than half of the 160 teams were in danger of failing without government assistance or private equity injections.</p><p>The National Association of Professional Baseball Leagues, the minor league governing body, made the long-expected announcement. </p><p>“We are a fans-in-the-stands business. We don’t have national TV revenues,” National Association president Pat O’Conner said during a digital news conference. “There was a conversation at one point: Well, can we play without fans? And that was one of the shortest conversations in the last six months. It just doesn’t make any sense.”</p><p>O’Conner estimated 85-90% of revenue was related to ticket money, concessions, parking and ballpark advertising. The minors drew 41.5 million fans last year for 176 teams in 15 leagues, averaging 4,044 fans per game.</p><p>MLB teams are planning for a 60-game regular season and most of their revenue will derive from broadcast money.</p><p>“I had a conversation with the commissioner, and we weren’t unable to find a path that allowed us to play games,” O'Conner said. “It wasn’t an acrimonious decision on our part.”</p><p>O'Conner said many minor league teams had received money through the federal Paycheck Protection Program Flexibility Act. </p><p>“That was a Band-Aid on a hemorrhaging industry,” he said. “Many of our clubs have gone through one, two, maybe three rounds of furloughs. In our office here, we’ve had varying levels of pay cuts between senior management, staff, and we’ve furloughed some individuals, as well, and are just about to enter in a second round of furloughs.”</p><p>He hopes for passage of <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/house-bill/7023/text"> H.R. 7023,</a> which would provide $1 billion in 15-year federal loans from the Federal Reserve to businesses that had 2019 revenue of $35 million or less and “have contractual obligations for making lease, rent, or bond payments for publicly owned sports facilities, museums, and community theaters.”</p><p>In addition, the Professional Baseball Agreement between the majors and minors expires Sept.. 30, and <a href="https://apnews.com/0f4779c5e306b2aea711d8793e648270">MLB has proposed reducing the minimum affiliates</a> from 160 to 120. </p><p>“There’s no question that what the pandemic has done is made us somewhat weaker economically,” O'Conner said. “I don’t think it’s challenged our resolve. I don’t think it’s impacted our desire to stick together and get a good deal.”</p><p>There have not been substantive talks for about six weeks.</p><p>“There are very many teams that are not liquid, not solvent, not able to proceed under normal circumstances, and these are anything but normal circumstances given the PBA and the uncertainty of the future for some of these ballclubs,” O’Conner said. “So I think the coronavirus has really cut into many clubs’ ability to make it. And I think that we’re looking at without some government intervention, without doing something to take on equity partners, you might be looking at half of the 160 who are going to have serious problems.”</p><p>MLB already has told clubs to retain expanded 60-player pools, of which 30 players can be active during the first two weeks of the season starting in late July.</p><p>Conner said the financial impact of the pathogen might extend until 2023.</p><p>“As serious as the threat from Major League Baseball was,” O'Conner said, “this threat from the coronavirus, it transcends any list that anybody wants to make with respect to the possibility of teams not being around in the future.”</p><p>___</p><p>More AP MLB: https://apnews.com/MLB and https://twitter.com/AP_Sports</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/l4RUgOBc-uPfJ7nhVjT8ZWoC4bw=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/CFIFLEHZUNAOLBMQV2AFUUYJIU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A cyclist rides past Principal Park, home to the Triple-A minor league baseball Iowa Cubs, Thursday, June 25, 2020, in Des Moines, Iowa. Two high school baseball games scheduled for Thursday at the stadium were postponed after officials said a ballpark staff member tested positive for coronavirus. (AP Photo/Charlie Neibergall)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Charlie Neibergall]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Panthers launching behind-the-scenes digital series chronicling team’s return from COVID-19 stoppage</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/panthers-launching-behind-the-scenes-digital-series-chronicling-teams-return-from-covid-19-stoppage/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/panthers-launching-behind-the-scenes-digital-series-chronicling-teams-return-from-covid-19-stoppage/</guid><dc:creator>David Dwork</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 23:32:37 +0000</pubDate><description>Buckle up, hockey fans, because after nearly four months off, the NHL is ready to hit the ground running.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Buckle up, hockey fans, because after nearly four months off, the NHL is ready to hit the ground running. </p><p>Sort of. </p><p>The NHL is preparing to resume its season after pausing everything in March due to the coronavirus pandemic, and the hope is for all 24 teams participating in the league's Return to Play Plan to enter mandatory training camps in the coming weeks. </p><p>The league moved to Phase 2 of its plan in early June, opening up team facilities to players and limited staff members for voluntary, non-contact workouts in small groups. </p><p>Since that time, around half of the Florida Panthers roster has been taking part in Phase 2 at the Ice Den in Coral Springs. </p><p>The NHL and NHLPA are hoping to open official training camps on, or around, July 10th.</p><p>According to the league's plan, when the season does resume, Florida will face the New York Islanders in a best-of-5 qualifying round series. </p><p>As Panthers players continue to get back into form and prepare to battle the Islanders, the team is launching a new, behind-the-scenes series that aims to provide an all-access look at how Florida’s players go from pause to playoffs. </p><p>The five-part digital series called ‘Panthers Uncaged’ premieres Wednesday, July 1st at 5 p.m. on the team’s <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Flapanthers/" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, IGTV, <a href="https://www.nhl.com/panthers/video" target="_blank">PanthersVision</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSSc4wVk6telelb58RrLYdg" target="_blank">YouTube</a> pages. </p><p>A link to the YouTube premiere can be found by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4HblPw1XZHo&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;utm_source=youtube&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=uncaged1" target="_blank">clicking here</a>. </p><p>According to a statement released by the team, "(Panthers Uncaged) will be created with a combination of socially-distant footage, go-pros, Zoom interviews, iPhone footage and non-traditional content capture."</p><p>It will be a welcomed window into the world of the Panthers as they navigate through this completely new and unparalleled experience while preparing to compete for the most sought after trophy in professional sports. </p><p>“We wanted to give our Panthers family a behind-the-scenes look at what our players, trainers and staff are doing to ensure a safe environment as the NHL’s Return to Play plan begins,” Panthers Senior Vice President Shawn Thornton said in a press release. “During these unprecedented times, we aim to provide access into players’ lives to showcase their emotions, perseverance and dedication in their quest to bring the franchise its first Stanley Cup.”</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/VQL5mtZl0jcWmqRSlDnmPDyUxno=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/2ZO2VOQJHFB37K5QCOKTTUAZPM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The Florida Panthers take part in a practice at the Ice Den in Coral Springs.]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[David Dwork]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Shohei Ohtani returns to 2-way role with Angels this season</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/shohei-ohtani-returns-to-2-way-role-with-angels-this-season/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/shohei-ohtani-returns-to-2-way-role-with-angels-this-season/</guid><dc:creator>Greg Beacham, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 22:04:39 +0000</pubDate><description>Shohei Ohtani will resume his two-way career with the Los Angeles Angels when baseball returns.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shohei Ohtani will resume his two-way career with the Los Angeles Angels when baseball returns.</p><p>Angels general manager Billy Eppler confirmed Tuesday that his Japanese star will pitch and hit in the majors this season.</p><p>Ohtani was only a designated hitter last season after undergoing Tommy John surgery. He wasn't expected to pitch in 2020 until at least May, and Eppler confirmed that the coronavirus pandemic hasn't altered the Angels' plans.</p><p>“We'll probably have a little bit more of a governor on him, at least at the outset,” Eppler said. “He's had a number of live (throwing sessions against hitters), but we want to up that intensity a little bit more and put him into a game situation. Just watching how he responds on a day-to-day basis will help guide us to how much we can push down on the gas pedal on him. We're expecting him to be on the mound and stay on the mound and roll through spring training.”</p><p>Manager Joe Maddon said last week that he hoped Ohtani would start roughly once a week on the mound while serving as the Halos' designated hitter in 3-4 games between starts. The Angels could have a six-man rotation for the short season.</p><p>Ohtani batted .286 last season with 18 homers and 62 RBIs and an .848 OPS in 106 games. His production at the plate was nearly identical to his work in 2018, when he was the AL Rookie of the Year while making 10 starts on the mound.</p><p>Eppler said none of the Angels' players are currently intending to opt out of playing in the shortened season. That includes three-time AL MVP Mike Trout, whose wife is due with their first child later this summer.</p><p>Eppler confirmed that first-round pick Reid Detmers will be on the Angels' summer roster as the 56th player, although the left-handed starter hasn't officially yet been added.</p><p>Eppler also went into details on the Angels' adherence to health and safety protocols at Angel Stadium and at Blair Field in Long Beach, where the Angels also will hold their summer camp. The Angels have removed communal couches and tables from their clubhouses in a bid to remind their players of the new realities.</p><p>“Think of the clubhouse as more of a closet,” said Eppler, who has received positive feedback from his players over their safety steps. “It’s where clothes hang. Absent of anything you need to do in the training room or weight room, get outside.”</p><p>___</p><p>More AP MLB: https://apnews.com/MLB and https://twitter.com/AP_Sports</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/EL3TwPwhtv7j-a3_q3qEFMbX5Ig=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/4E7M5KS3DNEGLENPJDPDKPMG4I.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this  Friday, Feb. 28, 2020 file photo, Los Angeles Angels' Shohei Ohtani bats during the first inning of a spring training baseball game against the Texas Rangers in Tempe, Ariz. Angels general manager Billy Eppler confirmed Tuesday, June 30, 2020 that Japanese star Shohei Ohtani will pitch and hit in the majors this season.(AP Photo/Charlie Riedel, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Charlie Riedel]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>'A dark past': MVPs say time to pull Landis name off plaques</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/a-dark-past-mvps-say-time-to-pull-landis-name-off-plaques/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/a-dark-past-mvps-say-time-to-pull-landis-name-off-plaques/</guid><dc:creator>Ben Walker, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 16:08:40 +0000</pubDate><description>As monuments, statues and memorials around the world come under increased scrutiny, some former Most Valuable Players in Major League Baseball are saying they'd like to see a change in future MVP plaques.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Something still bothers Barry Larkin about his Most Valuable Player award.</p><p>The other name engraved on the trophy: Kenesaw Mountain Landis.</p><p>“Why is it on there?” said Larkin, the Black shortstop voted National League MVP in 1995 with the Cincinnati Reds.</p><p>“I was always aware of his name and what that meant to slowing the color line in Major League Baseball, of the racial injustice and inequality that Black players had to go through,” the Hall of Famer said this week.</p><p>Hired in 1920 as the sport’s first commissioner to help clean up rampant gambling, Landis and his legacy are “always a complicated story” that includes “documented racism,” official MLB historian John Thorn said.</p><p>This much is true, in black and white: No Blacks played in the majors during his quarter-century tenure. Jackie Robinson broke the barrier in April 1947, about 2 1/2 years after Landis died.</p><p>"Landis is a part of history, even though it was a dark history,” Houston Astros manager Dusty Baker said.</p><p>Fact is, few fans realize Landis’ name is plastered all over the Most Valuable Player trophies. Most people just call it the MVP.</p><p>But there it is, prominently displayed on every American League and NL MVP plaque since 1944 — Kenesaw Mountain Landis Memorial Baseball Award, in shiny, gold letters literally twice as big as those of the winner.</p><p>With a sizable imprint of Landis’ face, too.</p><p>To some MVPs, it’s time for that 75-year run to end.</p><p>“If you’re looking to expose individuals in baseball’s history who promoted racism by continuing to close baseball’s doors to men of color, Kenesaw Landis would be a candidate,” three-time NL MVP Mike Schmidt of Philadelphia said.</p><p>“Looking back to baseball in the early 1900s, this was the norm. It doesn't make it right, though,” said the Hall of Famer, who is white. “Removing his name from the MVP trophy would expose the injustice of that era. I’d gladly replace the engraving on my trophies.”</p><p>Added 1991 NL MVP Terry Pendleton of Atlanta, who is Black: “This is 2020 now and things have changed all around the world. It can change for the better.”</p><p>“Statues are coming down, people are looking at monuments and memorials,” he said. “We need to get to the bottom of things, to do what’s right. Yes, maybe it is time to change the name.”</p><p>“I’ve always thought about that, why is that still on there?” Pendleton said. “No doubt, MVP stands on its own. It doesn’t need a name.”</p><p>Many hallowed baseball trophies are graced by the names of the greats: Robinson, Hank Aaron, Roberto Clemente, Cy Young, Willie Mays, Ted Williams and more.</p><p>How Landis got etched into the list is easy to trace.</p><p>A federal judge in Chicago, Landis quickly established his powerful authority as commissioner, banning Shoeless Joe Jackson and the Black Sox for throwing the 1919 World Series.</p><p>In 1931, Landis decided members of the Baseball Writers’ Association of America would pick and present the MVP awards. Before that, the leagues had their own mishmash system.</p><p>Then during the 1944 World Series, the BBWAA voted to add Landis’ name to the plaque as “an acknowledgement of his relationship with the writers,” longtime BBWAA secretary-treasuer Jack O’Connell said.</p><p>A month later, Landis died at 78. He soon was elected to the Hall of Fame.</p><p>“Landis is who he is. He was who he was,” Thorn said. “I absolutely support the movement to remove Confederate monuments, and Landis was pretty damn near Confederate.”</p><p>Landis’ father, however, was a Union Army surgeon wounded in the Civil War at the battle of Kennesaw Mountain in Georgia, which became the inspiration for the commissioner’s unique name. Born two years later in Ohio — with a slight tweak on the spelling of the mountain — Landis spent time in Indiana and rose to prominence in Chicago.</p><p>His precise role in racial issues has been debated for decades.</p><p>Landis broke up exhibitions between Black and white All-Star teams. He invited a group of Black newspaper publishers to address owners in what became a cordial but totally fruitless presentation.</p><p>Toward the end of his tenure, he told owners they were free to sign Black players. But there is no evidence he pushed for baseball integration, either, as the status quo of segregation remained.</p><p>“If you have the Jackie Robinson Award and the Kenesaw Mountain Landis Award, you are at diametrically opposed poles,” Thorn said. “And it does represent a conundrum.”</p><p>O’Connell said no MVP had voiced a complaint to him about Landis since taking his post in 1994. He said Landis’ name on the plaque wasn’t pledged or part of the BBWAA constitution.</p><p>Any BBWAA member could raise an objection to Landis’ presence. Normally, that would be discussed at the organization’s next gathering, currently scheduled for December at the winter meetings in Dallas. The coronavirus pandemic has put most everything-baseball related in peril — a 60-game season is set to begin in late July, and MVPs are usually announced in November.</p><p>O’Connell said if someone raised the issue now, it could be brought up to the board and opened to discussion and a vote. To pull Landis’ name “would be a simple matter of redesigning the plaque,” he said.</p><p>To Larkin, that would remove the tarnish from the trophy.</p><p>Larkin recalled that shortly after he was voted MVP, he got a call from two-time NL MVP Joe Morgan. The star Black second baseman of the Big Red Machine talked about Landis’ legacy and “he said it never sat well with him, having that name on there,” Larkin recalled.</p><p>Larkin agrees.</p><p>“His name should not be represented on a plaque or award of honor, especially at this day and time,” he said. “If his name was taken off, I would not be opposed to it at all.”</p><p>___</p><p>More AP MLB: <a href="https://apnews.com/MLB">https://apnews.com/MLB</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/AP_Sports">https://twitter.com/AP_Sports</a></p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/HeNW5D2l2osyXVxlDUev2G6al6E=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/WCARHJIQN5FLHPF5UWOFKOCS54.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Jan. 22, 2006, file photo,a  Joe DiMaggio 1947 MVP Award Plaque is displayed at a news conference in New York. The plaque features the name and image of Kenesaw Mountain Landis. (AP Photo/Jennifer Szymaszek, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Jennifer Szymaszek]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/oD3Etky3G9FS60wVk8ZXFfiYSWI=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/Y7JVVAQD4VCU5HOOZTG4UMJIJQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Oct. 22, 1992, file photo, Atlanta Braves' Terry Pendleton watches an RBI double against the Toronto Blue Jays in the first inning of Game 5 of the baseball World Series in Toronto. "I've always thought about that, why is that still on there?" Pendleton said, speaking of Kenesaw Mountain Landis' name on the MVP trophy. "No doubt, MVP stands on its own. It doesn't need a name." (AP Photo/Rusty Kennedy, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rusty Kennedy]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Zl9-QLUTfqhJtpUftOihfyYLjEU=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/JQCZMC7RKRFRZLT7ZFKW7BUTLY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this July 14, 2015, file photo, Barry Larkin is introduced before the MLB All-Star baseball game in Cincinnati. Something still bothers Barry Larkin about his Most Valuable Player award. The other name engraved on the trophy: Kenesaw Mountain Landis. Why is it on there? said Larkin, the Black shortstop voted National League MVP in 1995 with the Cincinnati Reds.(AP Photo/John Minchillo, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/7obv_5yg0-e-MN_8S-DL4ckT6t0=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/LUQGJLVDVNFEFBRHYEUERJWGM4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Jan. 22, 2006, file photo,a  Joe DiMaggio 1947 MVP Award Plaque is displayed at a news conference in New York. The plaque features the name and image of Kenesaw Mountain Landis. (AP Photo/Jennifer Szymaszek, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Jennifer Szymaszek]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/dG6FyMOP23xc7BrtDmIPMvUDLR0=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/7TPKTLCEVJHHZNREPHBQFSRN7A.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this 1938 file photo, Kenesaw Mountain Landis, baseball's first commissioner, is shown at age 78. The legacy of Landis is "always a complicated story" that includes "documented racism," official MLB historian John Thorn said. (AP Photo/File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Anonymous]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/ubxhTmQinmtWVCfp3d4DEedAung=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/RO6SJ47YQ5C35OROR35LY3ROWU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this April 11, 2019, file photo, Boston Red Sox manager Alex Cora, left, presents right fielder Mookie Betts with the 2018 AL MVP Award before a baseball game between the Red Sox and the Toronto Blue Jays at Fenway Park in Boston. The award includes the name and image of Kenesaw Mountain Landis. (AP Photo/Winslow Townson, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Winslow Townson]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/FwwdWymELLK0MhkBKPvR5LkqC6k=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/O5QIRSELSRERRMSGNB4OISC64A.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Oct. 1, 1941, file photo, Kenesaw Mountain Landis, baseball commissioner, throws out the first ball, formally opening the 1941 World Series featuring the Brooklyn Dodgers and the New York Yankees at Yankee Stadium in New York  on Oct. 1, 1941. New York Mayor Fiorello La Guardia is at right. Landis' name and image are on the National League and American League Most Valuable Player trophies. (AP Photo, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Uncredited]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/eU7oiSJEbm03Ib5QYD9-9NvDctY=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/BWB3DUQ5YJAEDHRRP5YRVWLE34.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this July 28, 2004, file photo, Cincinnati Reds' Barry Larkin takes a curtain call after hitting a pinch-hit grand slam off St. Louis Cardinals pitcher Steve Kline in the fifth inning of a baseball game in Cincinnati. From the time Larkin collected the 1995 National League Most Valuable Player award, something about the prize bothered him. "I was made aware that Kenesaw Mountain Landis' name was on it and there was this question: Why is it on there?" Larkin said this week. (AP Photo/David Kohl, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[David Kohl]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/mDYNyklxVOYFkiq5dYMaycVXDY8=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/3PZVMGPLMRFDPF2EPMBQBS65CA.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this April 8, 2017, file photo, Atlanta Braves bench coach Terry Pendleton sits in the dugout before a baseball game against the Pittsburgh Pirates in Pittsburgh.  Baseball's MVP trophy is engraved with the name of Kenesaw Mountain Landis in large letters. Landis was baseball's first commissioner and there were no Black players in the majors during his reign from 1920 until his death in 1944.  Ive always thought about that, why is that still on there? Pendleton said. No doubt, MVP stands on its own. It doesnt need a name. (AP Photo/Gene J. Puskar, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Gene J. Puskar]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/0L6WysHH57hfi90MRhtkhbxenak=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/Z4DJTYRMAZDGLPG42DW32OZ7XY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Oct. 28, 2008, file photo, a statue of Philadelphia Phillies Hall of Fame third baseman Mike Schmidt stands outside Citizens Bank Park as a passer-by holding an umbrella is reflected in the rain in Philadelphia. "If you're looking to expose individuals in baseball's history who promoted racism by continuing to close baseball's doors to men of color, Kenesaw Landis would be a candidate," three-time NL MVP Schmidt said. (AP Photo/Gene J. Puskar, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Gene J. Puskar]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/3du5Ov1cSsBdhDOH51DDOhiPEjI=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/DROW4HOHYZGUHPKBYGKSSREOJY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Oct. 23, 1945, file photo, Jackie Robinson, first Negro player in the major leagues, signs with the Montreal Royals in Montreal. From left are: Royals president Hector Racine, Branch Rickey Jr., Robinson and Royals vice-president Romeo Gauvreau. Baseball's MVP award is engraved with the name of Kenesaw Mountain Landis, the first baseball commissioner. No Blacks played in the majors during his quarter-century tenure; Jackie Robinson broke the barrier about 2 1/2 years after Landis died. (AP Photo/File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Anonymous]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/xf15LZoDHhx_-UHjZ2lXRifT4Is=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/B2RNP4FSDFCPJHH6473ZJHL7CQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - This March 1, 2012, file photo shows Mike Schmidt of the Philadelphia Phillies baseball team. If youre looking to expose individuals in baseballs history who promoted racism by continuing to close baseballs doors to men of color, Kenesaw Landis would be a candidate, three-time NL MVP Mike Schmidt of Philadelphia said. (AP Photo/Matt Slocum, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Matt Slocum]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>New league attracts softball's best, gives power to players</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/new-league-attracts-softballs-best-gives-power-to-players/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/new-league-attracts-softballs-best-gives-power-to-players/</guid><dc:creator>Andrew Seligman, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 15:52:48 +0000</pubDate><description>Athletes Unlimited launches the first of its professional women's leagues with a six-week season near Chicago in late August.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Victoria Hayward would have been in Japan right about now, preparing for the Olympics as captain of Canada's softball team.</p><p>The coronavirus pandemic pushed the Summer Games back a year. But she won't have to wait too much longer to get back on the field.</p><p>Hayward is one of the 56 elite players signed to suit up when Athletes Unlimited launches the first of its professional women's sports leagues in late August. The six-week season near Chicago is part of an innovative model made for the moment. </p><p>“It's really about the best players in the world, getting together being able to showcase their abilities, work with people they don't necessarily always work with," said the 28-year-old Hayward, an outfielder. “I think as a fan, it's going to be super fun to see some former adversaries getting to team up together. It's great camaraderie. It's high energy. The stakes are high. Every game matters.”</p><p>All 30 games will be broadcast live, with 23 on ESPN and seven on the CBS Sports Network, and will be available in Canada and Latin America as well as the United States. Fans who tune in will see an impressive list of participants that includes top professionals and Olympic medalists such as Cat Osterman. </p><p>The game will look the same at least between the lines. But outside them? Things take a different turn.</p><p>Athletes Unlimited gives players a big say in decisions the league makes, whether it's the uniform colors or TV deals. There are no team owners or general managers, and investors are limiting their returns. Players get to share in the profits, in addition to at least $10,000 guaranteed, plus bonus money.</p><p>“They’re amazing athletes," said Jon Patricof, co-founder and CEO of Athletes Unlimited. “They have huge fan bases at the college level and that there’s really untapped opportunity. At the same time, we thought that if you’re going to launch a league of any sort, whether it's a men's or women's sport, you really have to innovate and think differently about where fandom is heading. And out of that came our model.”</p><p>There will be no travel, with all games in suburban Rosemont. And forget about crowning a team champion. Instead, the title will go to the individual with the most points based on a fantasy-type system. A single, for example will be 10 points. A double will bring in 20 and a victory 50. Players can also lose points. </p><p>Team rosters will change each week, too: At the end of the week, the top four players by points become captains and draft teams.</p><p>Broadcasts will show standings in real time, and players and umpires will wear microphones during the game.</p><p>“A lot of what we’re trying to do is bring in onscreen graphics, miking up of players,” Patricof said. “(There are) great enhancements that are going to elevate the broadcast to a really strong level.”</p><p>A businessman and former president of Major League Soccer's New York City FC, Patricof and fellow founder Jonathan Soros started developing Athletes Unlimited about a year ago. They envisioned a network of sports leagues that followed a sort of fantasy-based model focused on athletes rather than teams in a short and intense season. They plan to launch <a href="https://apnews.com/72179c8582ba78b0f94137a7bd10ecf7">women's volleyball in February</a> and have their sights set on other sports.</p><p>A big point of emphasis for Athletes Unlimited is building the players’ brand. They’ve been getting help from a star-laden advisory board that includes Kevin Durant, Abby Wambach and Jessica Mendoza. </p><p>Don't expect to see fans in the stands once the season opens Aug. 30. The pandemic shutdown began before tickets went on sale and the seats will remain empty. </p><p>Players will be tested frequently for the virus. Some will stay at a hotel in a Rosemont with others in corporate housing, though it's not clear if they will be in an NBA-style bubble or be allowed to go out on their own. .</p><p>Hayward is simply looking forward to playing again after having her Olympic hopes delayed.</p><p>“This is just an amazing opportunity to help me prepare and be even better when the time comes next year,” she said. “Although it's not ideal, I'm really looking forward to playing against some of these people I've been competing with all my life.”</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/k8feN12WYJclmxXaNIFLdIP0N9Q=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/4LCS2QBWOJEH7OEOEUSD3M7VNY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Aug. 27, 2019, file photo, Canada's Victoria Hayward watches her inside-the-park grand slam against Guatemala during the first inning of a game in the Softball Americas Olympic qualifier tournament in Surrey, British Columbia. Hayward would have been in Japan right about now preparing for the Olympics as captain of Canada's softball team. The coronavirus pandemic pushed the Summer Games back a year. But she will not have to wait too much longer to get back on the field. She is one of the 56 elite players signed to suit up when Athletes Unlimited launches the first of its professional women's sports leagues with a six-week season near Chicago in late August and an innovative model made for the moment. (Darryl Dyck/The Canadian Press via AP, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Darryl Dyck]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Grizzlies' Morant apologizes for anti-police Instagram post</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/grizzlies-morant-apologizes-for-anti-police-instagram-post/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/30/grizzlies-morant-apologizes-for-anti-police-instagram-post/</guid><dc:creator>Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 11:14:19 +0000</pubDate><description>Memphis Grizzlies rookie guard Ja Morant tweeted and deleted an Instagram post suggesting he'd replace his name with an expletive on his number 12 jersey in a protest against police.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Memphis Grizzlies rookie guard Ja Morant posted and deleted an Instagram photo suggesting he’d replace his name with an expletive on his number 12 jersey in a protest against police. </p><p>Morant <a href="https://twitter.com/JaMorant/status/1277451639239081985/photo/1">apologized</a> Sunday night, saying the message didn't “accurately convey” what he wanted to share and that he knows “there are good cops ‘12’ out there.”</p><p>“My post was intended to focus on bad cops who get away with the murder of unarmed Black men and women and those who continue to harass peaceful BLACK LIVES MATTER protestors," Morant said.</p><p>Morant also asked for “justice” in the death of <a href="https://apnews.com/BreonnaTaylor">Breonna Taylor</a>, a Black woman shot and killed by Louisville Metro Police officers who were performing a no-knock warrant. </p><p>Morant's post came as the NBA, the National Basketball Players Association and Nike were reportedly working on a deal to allow players to replace their names with social justice statements when the <a href="https://apnews.com/50d2a10355e2aa1756c40c4d1cb5b3d7">NBA season</a> resumes on July 30. </p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/wkVlRkHT1VTkCMlRCGjPaz1RY3w=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/26W5XYWXH5CEHOWVJPAFMFZ7XE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Memphis Grizzlies guard Ja Morant (12) dunks ahead of Orlando Magic forward Aaron Gordon (00) and center Nikola Vucevic (9) during the first half of an NBA basketball game Tuesday, March 10, 2020, in Memphis, Tenn. (AP Photo/Brandon Dill)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Brandon Dill]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>The Latest: Nets' DeAndre Jordan says he has coronavirus</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/29/the-latest-nhl-says-26-players-have-reported-positive-tests/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/29/the-latest-nhl-says-26-players-have-reported-positive-tests/</guid><dc:creator>Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 03:49:27 +0000</pubDate><description>The National Hockey League says a total of 26 players have reported testing positive for the new coronavirus since voluntary workouts began June 8.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Latest on the effects of the coronavirus outbreak on sports around the world:</p><p>___</p><p>DeAndre Jordan says he has tested positive for the coronavirus and won’t be joining the Brooklyn Nets in Florida when the NBA season resumes.</p><p>Jordan announced his status on Twitter, hours after fellow Nets player Spencer Dinwiddie told The Athletic that he had tested positive and was experiencing symptoms.</p><p>They give the Nets at least six players who have tested positive for the virus. The other four were back in March, when Kevin Durant said he was one of them.</p><p>Jordan wrote that he had learned of his diagnosis Sunday night after returning to New York and it was confirmed again Monday.</p><p>Jordan signed with the Nets last summer, joining Durant and Kyrie Irving. The 2016 U.S. Olympic gold medalist spent most of the season as a reserve but had moved into the starting lineup at center for both games after Jacque Vaughn replaced Kenny Atkinson as coach in March.</p><p>___</p><p>Arizona will pause bringing additional athletes back to campus for voluntary workouts as a precaution amid a massive surge of coronavirus cases in the state.</p><p>The school had one positive test among 83 student-athletes who had already returned to campus for voluntary workouts. That person is going through the athletic department’s protocol.</p><p>Monday's decision to stop athletes from coming back to campus came shortly after Republican Gov. Doug Ducey closed bars, nightclubs, movie theaters, gyms and water parks for 30 days. Arizona has continued to set records with newly confirmed cases of the virus eclipsing 3,000 seven times in recent days.</p><p>___</p><p>Michigan’s athletic department is projecting a $26.1 million deficit for the upcoming fiscal year.</p><p>The school says in a news release it expects athletic department revenues to drop by more than $50 million for the fiscal year that starts July 1 because of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p><p>For the current fiscal year, Michigan says it expects athletics to bring in $187.4 million, with expenses of $186.4 million. For the upcoming year, it’s projecting revenue of $135.8 million and expenses of $161.9 million.</p><p>Expenses are expected to drop in part because many coaches and other senior staff are taking 10% pay cuts, including football coach Jim Harbaugh and men’s basketball coach Juwan Howard. Staffers with salaries between $100,000 and $150,000 are having their pay slashed by 7.5% and those who make between $50,000 and $100,000 will get a 5% cut.</p><p>The athletic department says it expects to see a 50% drop in revenues from ticket sales. But it cautions that’s just a projection and could change.</p><p>___</p><p>Brooklyn Nets guard Spencer Dinwiddie says he has tested positive for the coronavirus.</p><p>Dinwiddie told The Athletic he is experiencing symptoms and it is unclear if he can play when the NBA season resumes.</p><p>His absence would be a significant blow to the Nets. He has played well this season with Kyrie Irving out of the lineup because of injuries.</p><p>Dinwiddie says he tested negative for the virus multiple times after returning to New York and took part in a couple practices. But he has since tested positive and says he has a fever and chest soreness.</p><p>He is at least the fifth Nets player to test positive. The previous four were in March, with Kevin Durant saying he was among them.</p><p>Dinwiddie is averaging 20.6 points for the Nets, who have a half-game lead over Orlando for seventh place in the Eastern Conference. They are set to face the Magic on July 31 in their first game back.</p><p>___</p><p>Dan Hughes will not coach the Seattle Storm during the 2020 WNBA season over concerns about his risk for severe illness if he were to test positive for COVID-19.</p><p>The decision was made following a medical assessment by the league and in consultation with Hughes’ primary care physician. The WNBA is set to begin its season in late July with all teams playing in Florida.</p><p>Hughes, 65, had surgery last year to remove a cancerous tumor from his digestive tract. He missed nine games while recovering from the surgery.</p><p>Seattle promoted Gary Kloppenburg to head coach for the season. Kloppenburg served as the interim coach last season while Hughes was recovering from surgery.</p><p>___</p><p>New York Mets general manager Brodie Van Wagenen says one player on the team’s 40-man roster has tested positive for the coronavirus, in addition to multiple minor leaguers.</p><p>Van Wagenen did not identify any of the players on a video call with reporters, nor did he detail their conditions or reveal when they tested positive. He says the club is optimistic the player on the 40-man roster will be able to return to action early in training camp, which begins Friday at Citi Field.</p><p>“He is recovering and we feel like he’s in a good position, but we’ll sort of wait and see once we get everybody here in camp,” Van Wagenen said.</p><p>The GM said none of the positive tests occurred at the club’s regular spring training complex in Port St. Lucie, Florida.</p><p>___</p><p>The Chicago Bears are offering full refunds to season ticket holders because of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p><p>Season ticket holders who choose that option will be able to renew their seats for the 2021 season, the team says. The Bears are not sure how many fans will be allowed at Soldier Field this season.</p><p>Chicago is scheduled to open at Detroit on Sept. 13 and host the New York Giants a week later. The Bears also have home preseason games against Cleveland and San Francisco on Aug. 15 and 29.</p><p>___</p><p>Chicago Cubs general manager Jed Hoyer says two staff members have COVID-19 and were experiencing mild symptoms. </p><p>Hoyer would not reveal their names. He says one was tested because “a friend of a friend had it and he’d been in contact with that person,” and the other was “out of an abundance of caution.”</p><p>Hoyer says no players have tested positive or opted out of this season because of concerns about the coronavirus, nor have any coaches.</p><p>___</p><p>The New York Jets are offering fans refunds or payment deferrals on season tickets this year because of the coronavirus pandemic.</p><p>The team began emailing season ticket holders Monday to alert them about their options. The Jets also are deferring season ticket payments for July, as they have done each of the last three months.</p><p>Jets season ticket holders will have the option to get a full refund on 2020 tickets or defer all payments toward the 2021 season. Season ticket holders who choose one of those options can also opt to keep their same seats in 2021.</p><p>Also, season ticket holders with personal seat licenses who opt for the deferred payment or refund on tickets will also be able to defer their PSL payment, which is due in November to November 2021.</p><p>The team says those fans who make automatic payments on their season tickets will continue to have their payments made unless they opt for the deferral.</p><p>The Jets have not made individual game tickets available as they continue to monitor the situation regarding government restrictions and regulations during the pandemic. NFL teams are scheduled to report for training camp on July 28.</p><p>__</p><p>Austin Peay has suspended voluntary workouts and closed its facilities after a cluster of positive tests for the coronavirus among its athletes.</p><p>The Governors currently have 11 athletes who have tested positive. The FCS-level school in Clarksville, Tennessee, did not identify the sports involved.</p><p>Austin Peay closed its facilities Saturday. Athletic director Gerald Harrison said in a statement Monday that the positive tests are regrettable but procedures put in place worked as expected. That includes isolating those who tested positive along with people at risk through contract tracing in self-quarantine.</p><p>Austin Peay also is cleaning and disinfecting its facilities.</p><p>Austin Peay won the Ohio Valley Conference football championship last season and lost in the FCS quarterfinals.</p><p>___</p><p>The Carolina Hurricanes will help deliver meals to local healthcare workers to thank them for their work amid the coronavirus pandemic.</p><p>The team announced a five-week program Monday to deliver 1,000 meals in partnership with Blue Cross and Blue Shield of North Carolina. It begins Wednesday when Hurricanes coach Rod Brind’Amour assists with the first delivery, this one to the UNC Health Wakebrook behavioral health campus in Raleigh.</p><p>More meals will be delivered each Wednesday through July.</p><p>___</p><p>San Francisco Giants president of baseball operations Farhan Zaidi says minor league center fielder Hunter Bishop has tested positive for the coronavirus.</p><p>Zaidi says Bishop got his test result on Friday and has mild symptoms.</p><p>Bishop would have been on the club’s roster of 51 players announced Monday for the start of camp later this week. Zaidi says Bishop is in Arizona and wasn’t around any others from the organization.</p><p>The 22-year-old Bishop is the team’s first-round draft pick from 2019, selected 10th overall out of Arizona State. The Giants are planning their first workout Friday.</p><p>___</p><p>Miami Marlins president of baseball operations Michael Hill says a player who was asymptomatic has tested positive for the coronavirus.</p><p>Hill didn’t identify the player, but said he “feels great” and will go through MLB protocol to join the team.</p><p>Hill said he would be surprised if any Marlins players opt of the season because of health concerns.</p><p>___</p><p>Longtime Washington Nationals infielder Ryan Zimmerman and teammate Joe Ross have decided not to play this season.</p><p>General manager Mike Rizzo said Zimmerman and Ross opted out “for the personal health and safety of themselves and their loved ones,” adding the team supports their decisions.</p><p>Zimmerman said in a statement his family situation factored into his decision. His mother is at high risk for complications from the coronavirus because she has multiple sclerosis, and he has three young children, including a newborn. He told The Associated Press last week he was still undecided on whether to play.</p><p>As part of his announcement, the 35-year-old Zimmerman said he’s not retiring.</p><p>Ross is a 27-year-old right-hander with five years of major league experience, all with Washington.</p><p>___</p><p>Harris English is the fifth PGA Tour player to test positive for the coronavirus.</p><p>The positive test for English was part of the pre-tournament screening process at the Rocket Mortgage Classic in Detroit. English did not play last week at the Travelers Championship in Cromwell, Connecticut.</p><p>Since its return to golf, the tour had no positive tests the opening week in Texas; one positive test in Hilton Head Island, South Carolina; and three positive tests — plus two positive tests for caddies — in Connecticut.</p><p>English says in a statement he feels healthy and supports the tour’s additional policy of not letting anyone at Detroit Golf Club until the test results were back. </p><p>Previously, a player could practice but not enter the clubhouse while waiting on the results.</p><p>English started the season with limited status and has risen to No. 27 in the FedEx Cup. He must self-isolate for 10 days, meaning he will miss the next two tournaments.</p><p>___</p><p>The National Hockey League says a total of 26 players have reported testing positive for the new coronavirus since voluntary workouts began June 8.</p><p>Monday's update includes four additional cases among those tested at team facilities, to go along with the 11 announced June 19. The league says it’s aware of 11 other players testing positive outside the voluntary workout protocol.</p><p>The NHL said more than 250 players who worked out at team facilities were administered more than 1,450 COVID-19 tests.</p><p>The league and players are in the final stages of agreeing to resume the season. Training camps can open as early as July 10 if an agreement on testing, health and safety protocols and “hub” cities to host the games can be reached.</p><p>___</p><p>NBA All-Stars Kemba Walker and Trae Young, and U.S. women’s Olympians Sue Bird and Breanna Stewart will be coaches for an online basketball camp set up in response to coronavirus restrictions.</p><p>The camp for children of all ages was launched by former NBA player and longtime TNT basketball studio analyst Kenny Smith.</p><p>Two-time NBA All-Star Victor Oladipo and WNBA star Brittney Griner are also set to work “The Jet Academy,” with more participants to be announced.</p><p>The camps begin July 20 at www.jetacademycamp.com and can be streamed on any device. Schedule details and pricing are available on the website.</p><p>Smith has run a camp for 25 years in North Carolina, where he played collegiately. But camps have been limited or canceled in many locations because of rules limiting sizes of gatherings because of the virus.</p><p>___</p><p>NASCAR may be racing during the coronavirus pandemic. Celebrating in early December now is off the schedule.</p><p>The motorsports series has <a href="https://twitter.com/NASCAR/status/1277663142613528580?s=20">canceled its Champion’s Week and Cup Series awards </a> scheduled for early December in Nashville, citing the uncertainty from the coronavirus pandemic and its impact on the industry. NASCAR moved Champion’s Week to Nashville in 2019 from Las Vegas.</p><p>NASCAR still plans to celebrate its champions from the Xfinity Series to the truck series and promises details to come. And NASCAR says the series looks forward to returning to Nashville in 2021. </p><p>___</p><p>More AP sports: <a href="https://apnews.com/apf-sports">https://apnews.com/apf-sports</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/AP_Sports">https://twitter.com/AP_Sports</a></p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/zGvlmklsO8jpijsy5Ci7zvhCfag=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/KPMTJ25T4JGKDB6RPGMFHDC4EA.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Arizona Gov. Doug Ducey announces a new executive order in response to the rising COVID-19 cases in the state, during a news conference in Phoenix on Monday, June 29, 2020. The governor ordered bars, nightclubs and water parks to close again for at least a month starting Monday night  a dramatic about-face as coronavirus cases surge in the Sunbelt. (Michael Chow/The Arizona Republic via AP, Pool)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Michael Chow]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Tyev4jJ2wOqR5D3LUZlLemiNQkc=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/46LIRYKT2FGYVFY3BN632XHQRM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this July 28, 2015, file photo, fans at a Wrigley Rooftops' building down the right-field line outside Wrigley Field watch players during the first inning of a baseball game between the Colorado Rockies and Chicago Cubs in Chicago. This week, Major League Baseball players and owners reached an agreement to play an abbreviated, 60-game season that would start July 23 or 24 in teams home ballparks. But the seats will be empty. Instead, fans hoping to see a game in person will be have to settle for pressing their faces up against hotel windows, squinting through metal grates or climb to rooftops when baseball returns this month in otherwise empty stadiums. (AP Photo/Andrew A. Nelles, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Andrew Nelles]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Rspu4w1WaqbEdp5fjKlRHtaMBWM=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/AJPRJ5P6HVH2NLWJTZ4ZPPZXBU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In a  Monday, March 2, 2020 file photo, Washington Nationals pitcher Joe Ross throws during the first inning of a spring training baseball game against the Miami Marlins, in West Palm Beach, Fla. Longtime infielder Ryan Zimmerman and pitcher Joe Ross are opting out of playing the 2020 season as Major League Baseball tries to get back amid the COVID-19 pandemic. General manager Mike Rizzo says the team is 100% supportive of Zimmerman and Ross deciding not to play.(AP Photo/Jeff Roberson, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Jeff Roberson]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/YJMeGSQaBQepcMSGA5RYSsPg6K4=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/ZBO5GCCEEZALBJREMJVNFUZSZE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this April 19, 2017, file photo, Washington Nationals' Ryan Zimmerman watches his grand slam off Atlanta Braves pitcher Ian Krol during the eighth inning of a baseball game in Atlanta. Zimmerman has been offering his thoughts, as told to AP in a diary of sorts, while waiting for baseball to return. (Curtis Compton/Atlanta Journal-Constitution via AP, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Curtis Compton]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/nvj0gZ8LYCKmUv0bnKs3-xwFBks=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/66XKNX3XJNGYJMSFHJHZDZZAXE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this March 8, 2020, file photo, Harris English hits out of a bunker onto the 14th green during the final round of the Arnold Palmer Invitational golf tournament in Orlando, Fla. Before the PGA Tour season was halted by the coronavirus, English worked his way up to No. 24 in the FedEx Cup. (AP Photo/Phelan M. Ebenhack, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Phelan M. Ebenhack]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/MEQULo3HZSNzLhJfrwqb3YLulzk=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/6ZZEVQKQEJBRREQMW2UUCDB3PI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Jan. 9, 2019, file photo, with KeyArena over his shoulder in the window at left, NHL Commissioner Gary Bettman talks to visitors at a luncheon prior to a news conference in Seattle. Its been over three months since the commissioners of major sports cancelled or postponed events because of the coronavirus. Enough time for us to grade them on how theyve handled the virus so far. (AP Photo/Ted S. Warren, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ted S. Warren]]></media:credit></media:content></item></channel></rss>