<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"><channel><title>WPLG Local 10</title><link>https://www.local10.com</link><atom:link href="https://www.local10.com/arcio/rss/category/entertainment/?size=10" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>WPLG Local 10 News Feed</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:58:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><ttl>1</ttl><sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod><sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency><item><title>Carl Reiner, beloved creator of ‘Dick Van Dyke Show,’ dies</title><link>https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/30/carl-reiner-beloved-creator-of-dick-van-dyke-show-dies/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/30/carl-reiner-beloved-creator-of-dick-van-dyke-show-dies/</guid><dc:creator>Mike Stewart, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:11:09 +0000</pubDate><description>Carl Reiner, the ingenious and versatile comedy writer, actor and director, has died, according to reports.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Carl Reiner, the ingenious and versatile writer, actor and director who broke through as a “second banana” to Sid Caesar and rose to comedy’s front ranks as creator of “The Dick Van Dyke Show” and straight man to Mel Brooks’ “2000 Year Old Man,” has died. He was 98.</p><p>Reiner’s assistant Judy Nagy said he died Monday night of natural causes at his home in Beverly Hills, California. </p><p>Reiner was the father of actor-director Rob Reiner, who tweeted that his “heart is hurting. He was my guiding light.” The younger Reiner starred as Archie Bunker’s son-in-law on “All in the Family” and directed “When Harry Met Sally...”</p><p>Carl Reiner was one of show business’ best-liked men. Bald or toupeed, his was a welcome face on the small and silver screens: In Caesar’s 1950s troupe; as the self-absorbed Alan Brady of “The Dick Van Dyke Show”; and in such films as “The Russians Are Coming, the Russians Are Coming” and “It’s a Mad, Mad, Mad, Mad World.” </p><p>In recent years, he was part of the roguish gang in the “Ocean’s Eleven” movies starring George Clooney and appeared in documentaries including “Broadway: Beyond the Golden Age” and “If You’re Not in the Obit, Eat Breakfast.” </p><p>Tributes poured in, with Van Dyke calling Reiner “kind, gentle, compassionate, empathetic and wise,” and Clooney saying he made “every room he walked into funnier, smarter, kinder.”</p><p>Betty White described herself as privileged to work with Reiner and “heartbroken.” Steve Martin said goodbye to “my greatest mentor in movies and in life. Thank you, dear Carl.” Billy Crystal said “all of us in comedy have lost a giant,” and Sarah Silverman said ”his humanity was beyond compare.”</p><p>Brooks said he and Reiner had been best friends since meeting on “Your Show of Shows." </p><p>“Carl was a giant, unmatched in his contributions to entertainment," Brooks said. “When we were doing ”The 2000 Year Old Man" together there was no better straight man in the world. So whether he wrote or performed or he was just your best friend — nobody could do it better. He’ll be greatly missed. A tired cliché in times like this, but in Carl Reiner’s case it’s absolutely true. He will be greatly missed.”</p><p>Reiner directed such films as “Oh, God!” starring George Burns and John Denver; “All of Me,” with Martin and Lily Tomlin; and the 1970 comedy “Where’s Poppa?” His books include “Enter Laughing,” an autobiographical novel later adapted into a film and Broadway show; and “My Anecdotal Life,” a memoir published in 2003. He recounted his childhood and creative journey in the 2013 book, “I Remember Me.”</p><p>But many remember Reiner for “The Dick Van Dyke Show,” one of the most popular TV series of all time and a model of ensemble playing, physical comedy and timeless, good-natured wit. It starred Van Dyke as a television comedy writer working for a demanding, eccentric boss (Reiner) and living with his wife (Mary Tyler Moore in her first major TV role) and son.</p><p>“The Van Dyke show is probably the most thrilling of my accomplishments because that was very, very personal,” Reiner once said. “It was about me and my wife, living in New Rochelle and working on the Sid Caesar show." </p><p>The pilot, written by Reiner, starred himself as Rob Petrie, and aired in July 1960. When the show was reworked (CBS executives worried Reiner would make the lead character seem too Jewish), Van Dyke was cast and the program ran from 1961 to 1966. One famous fan, Orson Welles, was known for rushing to his bedroom in the afternoon so he could be near a TV when the show was on.</p><p>“Although it was a collaborative effort,″ Van Dyke later wrote, ”everything about the show stemmed from his (Reiner’s) endlessly and enviably fascinating, funny, and fertile brain and trickled down to the rest of us." </p><p>The story line had Petrie as the head writer for “The Alan Brady Show,” a comedy-variety series not unlike “Your Show of Shows,” in which Reiner, as Brady, was the egocentric star. Petrie’s fellow writers were character actors Morey Amsterdam as Buddy Sorrell and Rose Marie as Sally Rogers.</p><p>It was an early parody of the Caesar show, which would later be dramatized in the film “My Favorite Year” and Neil Simon’s play “Laughter on the 23rd Floor.”</p><p>Besides acting in and producing the “Van Dyke” series, Reiner wrote or co-wrote dozens of episodes. Although the show was the best of good clean fun, it wasn’t clean enough for network censors. Reiner often battled network officials over the sleeping arrangements of Rob and his wife; the Petries slept in twin beds. He wanted them to sleep in a double bed.</p><p>Reiner joined the classic comedy revue “Your Show of Shows” in 1950 after performing in Broadway plays. Much of Reiner’s early work came as a “second banana” — although, as Caesar once put it, “Such bananas don’t grow on trees.” He performed in sketches — satirizing everything from foreign films to rock ‘n’ roll — and added his talents to a writing team that included Brooks, Simon, Woody Allen and Larry Gelbart.</p><p>“As second banana,” he told TV Guide, “I had a chance to do just about everything a performer can ever get to do. If it came off well, I got all the applause. If it didn’t, the show was blamed.”</p><p>It was during the “Show of Shows” years that Reiner and Brooks started improvising skits which became the basis for “The 2000 Year Old Man.” Reiner was the interviewer, Brooks the old man and witness to history.</p><p>Reiner: “Did you know Jesus?”</p><p>Brooks: “I knew Christ, Christ was a thin lad, always wore sandals. Hung around with 12 other guys. They came in the store, no one ever bought anything. Once they asked for water.”</p><p>After the pair performed the routine at a party, Reiner said Steve Allen insisted they turn their banter into a record. The album, “2000 Years with Carl Reiner and Mel Brooks,” appeared in 1960 and was the start of a million-selling franchise. </p><p>The duo won a Grammy in 1998 for their “The 2000 Year Old Man in the Year 2000” and Reiner won multiple Emmys for his television work. In 2000, he received the Kennedy Center Mark Twain Prize for Humor. When the sound system failed at the start of the ceremonies, Reiner called from the balcony, “Does anybody have four double-A batteries?”</p><p>Besides “All of Me,” Reiner directed Martin in “Dead Men Don’t Wear Plaid,” “The Man With Two Brains” and “The Jerk.”</p><p>Carl Reiner was born in 1922, in New York City’s Bronx borough, one of two sons of Jewish immigrants. He grew up in a working-class neighborhood, where he learned to mimic voices and tell jokes. After high school, Reiner attended drama school, then joined a small theater group.</p><p>During World War II, Reiner joined the Army and toured in GI variety shows for a year and a half. Back out of uniform, he landed several stage roles, breaking through on Broadway in “Call Me Mister.”</p><p>He married his wife, Estelle, in 1943. Besides son Rob, the couple had another son, Lucas, a film director, and a daughter, Sylvia, a psychoanalyst and author. Estelle Reiner, who died in 2008, had a small role in Rob Reiner’s “When Harry Met Sally...” — as the woman who overhears Meg Ryan's ersatz ecstasy in a restaurant and says, “I’ll have what she’s having.”</p><p>Carl Reiner's greatest disappointment was “Bert Rigby, You’re a Fool,” a 1989 musical he wrote and directed that starred Robert Lindsay, a British actor Reiner believed could be a new Dick Van Dyke. The film flopped, and Reiner’s career as a director faded.</p><p>Reiner, inducted into the Academy of Television Arts and Sciences’ Hall of Fame, remained involved in other entertainment projects. In the 1990s, he reprised the Alan Brady character for an episode of “Mad About You.”</p><p>His death was first reported Tuesday by celebrity website TMZ.</p><p>____</p><p>AP National Writer Hillel Italie and Entertainment Writer Mark Kennedy contributed to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/-sEEfvMbc8m7R-vOKscJpnNlcb4=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/PIPZYLF25FB35OI7VOH4KM6RRY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this May 26, 1963 file photo, Carl Reiner shows holds two Emmy statuettes presented to him as best comedy writer for the "Dick Van Dyke Show," during the annual Emmy Awards presentation in Los Angeles. Reiner, the ingenious and versatile writer, actor and director who broke through as a second banana to Sid Caesar and rose to comedys front ranks as creator of The Dick Van Dyke Show and straight man to Mel Brooks 2000 Year Old Man, has died, according to reports. Variety reported he died of natural causes on Monday night, June 29, 2020, at his home in Beverly Hills, Calif. He was 98. (AP Photo, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Uncredited]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/JT6D4_pWrQ0R6zKQfh7fnr5UTEc=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/OIHAPVE6TNCS3C3BSIZ7RPLENQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this April 7, 2017 file photo, Carl Reiner, left, and his son Rob Reiner pose together following their hand and footprint ceremony at the TCL Chinese Theatre in Los Angeles. Carl Reiner, the ingenious and versatile writer, actor and director who broke through as a second banana to Sid Caesar and rose to comedys front ranks as creator of The Dick Van Dyke Show and straight man to Mel Brooks 2000 Year Old Man, has died, according to reports. Variety reported he died of natural causes on Monday night, June 29, 2020, at his home in Beverly Hills, Calif. He was 98. (Photo by Chris Pizzello/Invision/AP, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Chris Pizzello]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/RhhteAg6tMDZe2vIB2xUL7Yl44k=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/MSKQR2TA5VA4HP2SAZJ7HF3ORM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Oct. 15, 1993 file photo, writer-comedian and film director Carl Reiner, 71, appears after an interview in New York. Reiner, the ingenious and versatile writer, actor and director who broke through as a second banana to Sid Caesar and rose to comedys front ranks as creator of The Dick Van Dyke Show and straight man to Mel Brooks 2000 Year Old Man, has died, according to reports. Variety reported he died of natural causes on Monday night, June 29, 2020, at his home in Beverly Hills, Calif. He was 98. (AP Photo/Crystyna Czajkowsky, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Crystyna Czajkowsky]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/O2KD5QUuQaC0wQI_mKwV3uHldxc=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/2HMUGH7RHZD6NOGDVF77AE6OK4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this May 24, 1964 file photo, cast and crew of the television comedy series "The Dick Van Dyke Show" from left, Richard Deacon, Mary Tyler Moore, Outstanding Continued Performance by an Actress in a Series, Lead; Dick Van Dyke, Outstanding Continued Performance by an Actor in a Series, Lead; Sheldon Leonard, producer of the show, which was named best comedy series; Carl Reiner, Outstanding Writing Achievement in a Series; and Jerry Paris, Outstanding Directorial Achievement in Comedy. pose with their awards at the 16th Annual Emmy Awards in Los Angeles.  Variety reported that Reiner died of natural causes on Monday night, June 29, 2020, at his home in Beverly Hills, Calif. He was 98. (AP Photo, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Uncredited]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/zktNpeMZou0XboNobIkUNgJo0-0=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/LEM4WKEVA5EP5OUNJ7TDPYPXVM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Sept. 8, 2014 file photo, Mel Brooks, left, stands with Carl Reiner during Brooks' hand and footprint ceremony on the 40th anniversary of the movie "Young Frankenstein," in Los Angeles. Reiner, the ingenious and versatile writer, actor and director who broke through as a second banana to Sid Caesar and rose to comedys front ranks as creator of The Dick Van Dyke Show and straight man to Mel Brooks 2000 Year Old Man, has died, according to reports. Variety reported he died of natural causes on Monday night, June 29, 2020, at his home in Beverly Hills, Calif. He was 98. (AP Photo/Nick Ut, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Nick Ut]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/xwLK6ms2PhoGgD6F_KyIlXaz_Q8=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/67HB7O4S7RA6JJVKKTV3MHMCYY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this May 25, 1967 file writer-comedian Carl Reiner poses in his new hairpiece in Los Angeles. Reiner, the ingenious and versatile writer, actor and director who broke through as a second banana to Sid Caesar and rose to comedys front ranks as creator of The Dick Van Dyke Show and straight man to Mel Brooks 2000 Year Old Man, has died, according to reports. Variety reported he died of natural causes on Monday night, June 29, 2020, at his home in Beverly Hills, Calif. He was 98. (AP Photo/Harold Filan, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Harold Filan]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/84G9-UXBuNqstkBQMh3mtstjE3g=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/MSLA4CGTUNF5VKL3UR4U3NL4G4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Oct. 3, 1977 file photo, writer-director Carl Reiner appears during an interview about his movie " Oh God!" in New York. Reiner, the ingenious and versatile writer, actor and director who broke through as a second banana to Sid Caesar and rose to comedys front ranks as creator of The Dick Van Dyke Show and straight man to Mel Brooks 2000 Year Old Man, has died, according to reports. Variety reported he died of natural causes on Monday night, June 29, 2020, at his home in Beverly Hills, Calif. He was 98. (AP Photo/Suzanne Vlamis, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Suzanne Vlamis]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Carl Reiner, comedy’s rare untortured genius, dies at 98</title><link>https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/30/carl-reiner-comedys-rare-untortured-genius-dies-at-98/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/30/carl-reiner-comedys-rare-untortured-genius-dies-at-98/</guid><dc:creator>Hillel Italie, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:35:05 +0000</pubDate><description>Carl Reiner,  who died Monday at 98, was the rare untortured genius of comedy, his career a story of laughter and camaraderie, of innovation and triumph and affection.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No one in the world of comedy was more admired, and loved, than Carl Reiner.</p><p>Reiner was the rare untortured genius of comedy, his career a story of laughter and camaraderie, of innovation and triumph and affection. His persona was so warm and approachable — everyone’s friend or favorite uncle — that you could forget that he was an architect of modern comedy, a “North Star,” in the words of Billy Crystal.</p><p>As a writer and director, he mastered a genial, but sophisticated brand of humor that Steve Martin, Jerry Seinfeld and others emulated. As an actor, he was the ideal straight man for such manic performers as Mel Brooks and Sid Caesar and dependably funny on his own. As an all-around talent, he helped perfect two standard television formats — sketch and situation comedy.</p><p>
<a href="https://apnews.com/ad8fd934534a1c5ea5b2ad8caf18716c">Reiner’s death Monday at 98 </a> from natural causes prompted an outpouring from t <a href="https://apnews.com/fddf60cd85313f3dca8112e9f71cf8be">hose he inspired, a group that included Brooks, Dick Van Dyke, George Clooney and Billy Eichner and millions more</a>. </p><p>Tall and agile, equally striking whether bald or toupeed, he entertained in every medium available to him, from movies and vinyl records to Broadway and Twitter. But he will be remembered best for “The Dick Van Dyke Show,” the landmark series which aired from 1961-66 and was a master class of wit, ensemble playing, physical comedy and the overriding good nature of Reiner himself. </p><p>Based on his time in the 1950s with Sid Caesar’s “Your Show of Shows,” the forerunner to “Saturday Night Live,” it was among the first sit-coms about TV itself and inspired such future hits as “Mad About You” and “30 Rock.”</p><p>As millions of fans know, Van Dyke starred as comedy writer Rob Petrie, who worked for the demanding, eccentric Alan Brady (Reiner) and lived on Bonnie Meadow Road in suburban New Rochelle with his wife Laura (Mary Tyler Moore, in her first major TV role) and young son. Petrie’s fellow writers were veteran character actors Morey Amsterdam as Buddy Sorrell and Rose Marie as Sally Rogers. Reiner originally had a very different title and cast in mind. The pilot was called “Head of the Family,” which starred Reiner and Barbara Britton, and aired as a single episode in July 1960. But CBS executives worried that Reiner would make Petrie seem too Jewish, so Van Dyke was cast instead.</p><p>Reiner likely needed the time spared from playing the lead. Besides acting in and producing the “Van Dyke” series, he wrote or co-wrote dozens of episodes — a feat that exhausted Reiner and amazed the cast and others in the business. Some of the more notable shows: Laura inadvertently revealing to the public that Alan Brady was bald; Rob on a radio marathon, delirious from lack of sleep, calling out to a kitten he’s learned is stuck in a tree; Rob as a jury foreman, clumsily smitten by the attractive defendant (Sue Ann Langdon), and unaware that Laura is in the courtroom.</p><p>“I can explain ... nothing,’’ a sheepish Rob later tells his wife. </p><p>"Although it was a collaborative effort,″ Van Dyke wrote in “My Lucky Life In and Out of Show Business, a memoir published in 2011, ``everything about the show stemmed from his (Reiner’s) endlessly and enviably fascinating, funny, and fertile brain and trickled down to the rest of us.″ On Tuesday, Van Dyke called Reiner “kind, gentle, compassionate, empathetic and wise."</p><p>Reiner and Co. had parodied current events and popular culture on the Caesar program, but for the Van Dyke show he deliberately avoided topical references, hoping it would seem timeless. The sitcom remained highly popular in re-runs, with Laura Petrie’s plaintive “Oh, Rob!” a lasting catchphrase. One famous fan, Orson Welles, was known for rushing to his bedroom in the afternoon so he could be near a TV set when the show was on. First lady Michelle Obama once joked that she preferred watching “Dick Van Dyke” to viewing her husband’s debates.</p><p>Reiner had broken through in television’s early days, before he even owned a TV: He joined “Your Show of Shows” in 1950 after performing in several Broadway plays, and much of his early work came as a “second banana.” Reiner was part of an extraordinary writing team that included Brooks, Neil Simon and Larry Gelbart, and a performing cast featuring Caesar and Imogene Coca. He was never funnier than as an unhinged mechanical figure from a Bavarian clock, never steadier than in a spoof of “This Is Your Life,” in which he is the host and Caesar a surprise honoree who desperately — violently — doesn’t want the honor. “</p><p>As second banana,” Reiner told TV Guide, “I had a chance to do just about everything a performer can ever get to do. If it came off well, I got all the applause. If it didn’t, the show was blamed.” </p><p>Off stage, Reiner and Brooks had a rapport which launched a comic franchise. During the “Show of Shows” years, they started improvising skits which became the basis for “The 2000 Year Old Man.” Reiner was the interviewer, Brooks the old witness to history. </p><p>Reiner: “Did you know Jesus?” </p><p>Brooks: “I knew Christ, Christ was a thin lad, always wore sandals. Hung around with 12 other guys. They came in the store, no one ever bought anything. Once they asked for water.” </p><p>Their routine was an instant favorite at parties, and Reiner recalled that Steve Allen insisted they should turn their banter into a record. “2000 Years with Carl Reiner and Mel Brooks” came out in 1960 and was so popular that Reiner would later tell NPR even Britain’s Queen Mother, “the biggest shiksa in the world,” loved it. The duo updated their shtick over time and won a Grammy in 1998 for their “The 2000 Year Old Man in the Year 2000,” the same year Reiner received the Kennedy Center Mark Twain Prize for Humor. When the sound system failed at the start of the ceremonies, Reiner called from the balcony, “Does anybody have four double-A batteries?” </p><p>After the Van Dyke show, Reiner appeared in such hit movies as “The Russians Are Coming, the Russians Are Coming” and the “Ocean’s Eleven” films that starred George Clooney. He directed George Segal and Ruth Gordon in “Where’s Poppa?”, George Burns in “Oh, God!” and Steve Martin in “The Jerk” and “All of Me.” He took pride in his books, notably “Enter Laughing,” a “bio-novel” which later became a film and Broadway show.</p><p>Reiner was the father of actor-director Rob Reiner, who starred as Archie Bunker’s son-in-law on “All in the Family” and directed “When Harry Met Sally...” Rob Reiner said in a tweet Tuesday that his “heart is hurting. He was my guiding light.”</p><p>Carl Reiner, a son of Jewish immigrants, was born in 1922 in New York City, and raised in a three-room apartment. He loved to mimic voices and tell jokes, and, after high school, attended drama school. He then joined a small theater group. “It was a terrific experience, but I wasn’t getting any money for it,” he told the Akron Beacon Journal in 1963. “I got uppity one day — after all, the audience was paying from 22 to 88 cents for admission — and I demanded to be paid. They settled for $1 a performance and I ... became their highest-priced actor.” </p><p>During World War II, Reiner served in the Army and toured in GI variety shows. After the war, he landed several stage roles, breaking through on Broadway in “Call Me Mister.” He married Estelle Lebost, in 1943. Besides son Rob, the couple had another son, Lucas, a film director; and a daughter, Sylvia, a psychoanalyst and author. Estelle, who died in 2008, had a memorable role in “When Harry Met Sally...” — as the woman who overhears Meg Ryan’s ersatz ecstasy in a restaurant and says, “I’ll have what she’s having.” </p><p>Reiner, winner of multiple Emmys and other awards, was in the business for life. In the 1990s, he won an Emmy by reprising Alan Brady for an episode of “Mad About You” and more recently made appearances on “Two and a Half Men” and “Hot in Cleveland.” In the 21st century, he was writing books and commenting daily through his Twitter feed, venting anger at the presidency of Donald Trump. Most nights, Brooks came over and the two ate dinner together. In the mornings, Reiner had a ritual that provided the title for the 2017 documentary he hosted and received an Emmy nomination for, “If You’re Not in the Obit, Eat Breakfast.”</p><p>“Every morning before having breakfast,” Reiner said in the movie, “I pick up my newspaper, get the obituary section and see if I’m listed. If I’m not, I’ll have my breakfast.” </p><p>____ </p><p>Associated Press writer Mike Stewart contributed to this report</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/nijwQX9wCK6ka8N5UqA95SXY4ic=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/GV2QDPPFGJG2BBPWUV5ZK3KCE4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this May 25, 1967 file writer-comedian Carl Reiner poses in his new hairpiece in Los Angeles. Reiner, the ingenious and versatile writer, actor and director who broke through as a second banana to Sid Caesar and rose to comedys front ranks as creator of The Dick Van Dyke Show and straight man to Mel Brooks 2000 Year Old Man, has died, according to reports. Variety reported he died of natural causes on Monday night, June 29, 2020, at his home in Beverly Hills, Calif. He was 98. (AP Photo/Harold Filan, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Harold Filan]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/LFaBBrQ0fPGl-XiI2GdxsbzBJg0=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/6ILIUKDJ2JAX5M44NR4G6EJ4GQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this April 7, 2017 file photo, Carl Reiner, left, and his son Rob Reiner pose together following their hand and footprint ceremony at the TCL Chinese Theatre in Los Angeles. Carl Reiner, the ingenious and versatile writer, actor and director who broke through as a second banana to Sid Caesar and rose to comedys front ranks as creator of The Dick Van Dyke Show and straight man to Mel Brooks 2000 Year Old Man, has died, according to reports. Variety reported he died of natural causes on Monday night, June 29, 2020, at his home in Beverly Hills, Calif. He was 98. (Photo by Chris Pizzello/Invision/AP, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Chris Pizzello]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/v6fLyPVxpDIWHz3OugqwyMthF5g=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/ROMCBMEK6VGLFNIAALQROUZVIU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this May 24, 1964 file photo, cast and crew of the television comedy series "The Dick Van Dyke Show" from left, Richard Deacon, Mary Tyler Moore, Outstanding Continued Performance by an Actress in a Series, Lead; Dick Van Dyke, Outstanding Continued Performance by an Actor in a Series, Lead; Sheldon Leonard, producer of the show, which was named best comedy series; Carl Reiner, Outstanding Writing Achievement in a Series; and Jerry Paris, Outstanding Directorial Achievement in Comedy. pose with their awards at the 16th Annual Emmy Awards in Los Angeles.  Variety reported that Reiner died of natural causes on Monday night, June 29, 2020, at his home in Beverly Hills, Calif. He was 98. (AP Photo, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Uncredited]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/-me9FCrEOoATPPhTGBQH0TEBpMk=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/NH2Q3VEFN5EY5CC7IHOYYSVIDQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Oct. 15, 1993 file photo, writer-comedian and film director Carl Reiner, 71, appears after an interview in New York. Reiner, the ingenious and versatile writer, actor and director who broke through as a second banana to Sid Caesar and rose to comedys front ranks as creator of The Dick Van Dyke Show and straight man to Mel Brooks 2000 Year Old Man, has died, according to reports. Variety reported he died of natural causes on Monday night, June 29, 2020, at his home in Beverly Hills, Calif. He was 98. (AP Photo/Crystyna Czajkowsky, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Crystyna Czajkowsky]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/awA7zCxvodr3r-qX2EPscE9UuQA=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/VPP7PSUOERFWBJOKPN7PB72J5M.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Feb. 24, 1999 file photo, Mel Brooks, left, and Carl Reiner accept their award for best spoken comedy album, "The 2000 Year Old Man in the Year 2000," during the 41st Annual Grammy Awards in Los Angeles. Reiner, the ingenious and versatile writer, actor and director who broke through as a second banana to Sid Caesar and rose to comedys front ranks as creator of The Dick Van Dyke Show and straight man to Mel Brooks 2000 Year Old Man, has died, according to reports. Variety reported he died of natural causes on Monday night, June 29, 2020, at his home in Beverly Hills, Calif. He was 98. (AP Photo/Kevork Djansezian, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Kevork Djansezian]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/P0paRcmMZ3TYc6byFcDmyXtogck=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/XL5L4CJYYNF2FMBK6Z5PC7ELPY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Sept. 8, 2014 file photo, Mel Brooks, left, stands with Carl Reiner during Brooks' hand and footprint ceremony on the 40th anniversary of the movie "Young Frankenstein," in Los Angeles. Reiner, the ingenious and versatile writer, actor and director who broke through as a second banana to Sid Caesar and rose to comedys front ranks as creator of The Dick Van Dyke Show and straight man to Mel Brooks 2000 Year Old Man, has died, according to reports. Variety reported he died of natural causes on Monday night, June 29, 2020, at his home in Beverly Hills, Calif. He was 98. (AP Photo/Nick Ut, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Nick Ut]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Judge temporarily blocks tell-all book by Trump's niece</title><link>https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/30/judge-temporarily-blocks-tell-all-book-by-trumps-niece/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/30/judge-temporarily-blocks-tell-all-book-by-trumps-niece/</guid><dc:creator>Larry Neumeister, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:21:09 +0000</pubDate><description>A New York state judge has temporarily blocked publication of a tell-all book by President Donald Trump's niece after the president's brother sued to stop it.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A tell-all book by President Donald Trump’s niece cannot be published until a judge decides the merits of claims by the president’s brother that its publication would violate a pact among family members, a judge said Tuesday.</p><p>New York state Supreme Court Judge Hal B. Greenwald in Poughkeepsie, New York, issued an order requiring the niece, Mary Trump, and her publisher to explain why they should not be blocked from publishing the book: “Too Much and Never Enough: How My Family Created the World’s Most Dangerous Man.” A hearing was set for July 10.</p><p>The book, scheduled to be published in July, was written by Mary Trump, the daughter of Fred Trump Jr., the president’s elder brother, who died in 1981. An online description of it says it reveals “a nightmare of traumas, destructive relationships, and a tragic combination of neglect and abuse.”</p><p>The judge said no portion of the book can be distributed before he decides the validity of Robert Trump’s claims. Robert Trump argues Mary Trump must comply with a written agreement among family members that such a book cannot be published without permission from other family members.</p><p>Mary Trump’s lawyer, Theodore J. Boutrous Jr., and her publisher, Simon &amp; Schuster, promised an immediate appeal.</p><p>“The trial court’s temporary restraining order is only temporary but it still is a prior restraint on core political speech that flatly violates the First Amendment," Boutrous said.</p><p>“This book, which addresses matters of great public concern and importance about a sitting president in election year, should not be suppressed even for one day,” Boutrous said in a statement.</p><p>Adam Rothberg, a Simon &amp; Schuster spokesperson, said the publisher was disappointed but looks forward “to prevailing in this case based on well-established precedents regarding prior restraint."</p><p>Charles Harder, an attorney for Robert Trump, said his client was “very pleased."</p><p>He said in a statement that the actions by Mary Trump and her publisher were “truly reprehensible."</p><p>“We look forward to vigorously litigating this case, and will seek the maximum remedies available by law for the enormous damages," he said. “Short of corrective action to immediately cease their egregious conduct, we will pursue this case to the very end."</p><p>In court papers, Robert Trump maintained Mary Trump was part of a settlement nearly two decades ago that included a confidentiality clause explicitly saying they would not “publish any account concerning the litigation or their relationship,” unless they all agreed, the court papers said.</p><p>___</p><p>Associated Press writer Michael Balsamo contributed to this report from Washington.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/hlMsPxk6OyeB1Ye9dZnPFD8wSWg=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/Z6TP26Y76ZDFDMZD3S6UNCLRWA.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Nov. 3, 1999 file photo, Robert Trump, left, joins real estate developer and presidential hopeful Donald Trump at an event in New York. A tell-all book by President Donald Trump's niece cannot be published until a judge decides the merits of claims by the president's brother, her uncle Robert Trump, that its publication would violate a pact among family members, a judge said Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (AP Photo/Diane Bonadreff, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Diane Bondaress]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Zam-MNRW204EXOOr3MpK6GTrHoA=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/36EWUAJGYNDADN4VS75L2AWKF4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE- In this Thursday, June 25, 2020, file photo, President Donald Trump walks on the South Lawn after arriving on Marine One at the White House in Washington. The president's brother Robert Trump has filed a second court action seeking to halt publication of a tell-all book by the president's niece, after his first bid was rejected by a New York City judge. (AP Photo/Alex Brandon, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Alex Brandon]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Famed architect Paul Williams' archive goes to Getty, USC</title><link>https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/30/famed-architect-paul-williams-archive-goes-to-getty-usc/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/30/famed-architect-paul-williams-archive-goes-to-getty-usc/</guid><dc:creator>John Rogers, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 23:27:24 +0000</pubDate><description>The archive of the late African American architect Paul Revere Williams has been acquired by the University of Southern California School of Architecture and the Getty Research Institute.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Before there was Frank Gehry there was Paul Revere Williams, who shaped the face of Los Angeles throughout much of the 20th century, a time in which he also became known as perhaps the greatest Black architect of his time. </p><p>Now Williams' archives, containing tens of thousands of drawings, blueprints, vintage photographs and other papers once thought lost, have been acquired by the University of Southern California School of Architecture and the Getty Research Institute.</p><p>“Paul Williams was a trailblazing architect whose long career helped shape Los Angeles and Southern California. His archive essentially tells the story of how the modern Southland was built,” Getty Research Institute Director Mary Miller said Tuesday. “Its importance as an aesthetic and educational resource cannot be overstated.”</p><p>The archives contain approximately 35,000 plans, 10,000 original drawings, blueprints, hand-colored renderings, photographs and other materials. They have been cared for by his granddaughter Karen Elyse Hudson, who has published extensively about his work. </p><p> “The collaboration of two such esteemed institutions, the University of Southern California and Getty Research Institute to preserve and further his legacy, would make our grandfather extremely proud," Hudson said.</p><p>Williams began his career in the 1920s, a time when there were few opportunities for Black architects, and indeed segregation affected greatly the way he often did his work. </p><p>He learned to draw upside down so he could sketch across a table for white clients who might be uncomfortable sitting next to him. At construction sites he often kept his hands clasped behind his back as he watched his work being created, so as not to risk making anyone uncomfortable about shaking hands with him. </p><p>He came to be known, Hudson said, as the “architect to the stars,” designing eye-popping homes for Frank Sinatra, Cary Grant, Lucille Ball and Desi Arnaz, among others. </p><p>Creating unique homes for the rich and famous represented only a small part of his work. </p><p>His archives also document his early residential commissions from a 1920s housing boom to landmark mid-century civic buildings. The Los Angeles County Courthouse, Los Angeles International Airport and First African Methodist Church were among the projects he led or worked on. </p><p>He was also chief architect for the Pueblo del Rio neighborhood of South Los Angeles, built in 1940 to house African American defense industry workers. </p><p>Although he mainly worked in Southern California, Williams also was chief architect for the United Nations building in Paris and the Langston Terrace in Washington, D.C., the nation's first federally sponsored public housing.</p><p>He was the first African American member of the American Institute of Architects, its first African American Fellow and the first African American recipient of the institute's Gold Medal, its highest honor. </p><p>It was once believed his archives were lost when a South Los Angeles bank building where they were thought to be stored was burned down in the 1992 riots that followed the acquittal of four white police officers for the beating of Black motorist Rodney King. Although some of Williams' business records were stored there, most of his papers were housed elsewhere. </p><p>Born in Los Angeles in 1894, Williams was orphaned following the death of his father at age 2 and his mother at age 4. He died in 1980 at 85. </p><p>Despite those early hardships he would go on to be hailed as one of the University of Southern California's most distinguished alumni. Milton S.F. Curry, dean of the university's School of Architecture, said Tuesday USC was honored to play a role in the archives' acquisition. </p><p>The archives will be a central feature of the USC Center for Architecture + City Design and the African American Art History Initiative at Getty. They will eventually be made available to scholars and others through a digitalization project that will take several years. </p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/9LD_-CLVD7cZkPDet8ftG2K5VsU=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/IS5ACLK3MZGS7NYUUHWVQAULLA.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - This June 28, 1968, file photo, shows the main entrance to the Ambassador Hotel in Los Angeles, Calif. The Ambassador Hotel, where presidents slept, Robert Kennedy was assassinated in 1968 and Mary Pickford collected her Oscar for best actress in 1930 is now the site of a public-school complex. Opened in 1921 and designed by Myron Hunt, with later renovations by African American architect Paul Revere Williams, the Ambassador Hotel was one of Los Angeles' defining historic sites. The archive of the late African American architect Paul Revere Williams has been acquired by the University of Southern California School of Architecture and the Getty Research Institute. (AP Photo/David F. Smith, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[David F. Smith]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>New Mexico tribe transforms old casino into movie studio</title><link>https://www.local10.com/business/2020/06/30/new-mexico-tribe-transforms-old-casino-into-movie-studio/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/business/2020/06/30/new-mexico-tribe-transforms-old-casino-into-movie-studio/</guid><dc:creator>Russell Contreras, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 21:44:02 +0000</pubDate><description>A northern New Mexico Native American tribe is opening a movie studio it hopes will attract big productions.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A small northern New Mexico Native American tribe has opened a movie studio in a former casino that it hopes will lure big productions.</p><p>The Tesuque Pueblo recently converted the building near Santa Fe into a movie studio campus called Camel Rock Studios with more than 25,000 square feet (2,323 square meters) of filming space. </p><p>The tribe's lands feature stunning desert and the iconic Camel Rock formation in the red-brown foothills of the Sangre de Cristo Mountains and tribal officials said outdoor filming can take place on 27 square miles (70 square kilometers) of the reservation.</p><p>The tribe with about 800 members decided to open the studio after scenes from the Universal Pictures western movie “News of the World” starring Tom Hanks were filmed last year in the Camel Rock Casino, which closed in 2018.</p><p>Universal's use of the casino for filming helped convince tribal officials to transform the empty building into studio space, said Timothy Brown, president and CEO of the Pueblo of Tesuque Development Corporation. Also influencing the decision were investments in New Mexico movie studios by Netflix and NBCUniversal in recent years, said Tunte Vigil, Tesuque Pueblo’s business development associate.</p><p>“The Pueblo of Tesuque Development Corporation wants to bring different businesses to the pueblo and the market is really open,” Vigil said. “So this is a good opportunity.”</p><p>No productions are happening now and none are planned for the immediate future because the pueblo and most of the state remains under strict COVID-19 business restrictions. But Brown said that that hasn’t stopped potential productions from contacting the pueblo and asking to reserve studio time.</p><p>Cheyenne and Arapaho filmmaker Chris Eyre, a Santa Fe resident and an advisor to Camel Rock Studio, said the studio’s unique aspect is that its former makeup as a casino provides the site with pre-made infrastructure that can be used for filming different types of movie scenes</p><p>“It’s a museum. It’s an opulent hotel lobby. It’s a capitol building,” said Eyer, who directed the 1998 film “Smoke Signals” about two Coeur d'Alene tribal members who travel from Idaho to Arizona to retrieve the remains of their father after he died alone. “There are sorts of interesting standing sets that can be creatively (crafted) for all sorts of scenes.”</p><p>The site also has a set workshop called a mill that can be used by crews to build sets for use inside the casino or on the tribe's land, Eyer said, adding that he could envision movies filmed there that are set in the Middle East or the U.S. Southwest.</p><p>Older movies filmed on the Tesuque Pueblo include the 1955 western “The Man from Laramie” starring James Stewart and the 1988 “Young Guns” with Emilio Estevez and Kiefer Sutherland.</p><p>But Eyer said previous productions had stereotypes about Indigenous people and limited Native American input and that tribal officials hope future productions don't follow in their footsteps. </p><p>The studio is being established at a time when Native American writers including Pulitzer Prize-winning Cheyenne and Arapaho author Tommy Orange and Inupiaq American poet Joan Naviyuk Kane are transforming American Literature — and putting pressure on Hollywood to incorporate more Native American stories.</p><p>Tribal officials plan to create internships and movie training programs for Tesuque Pueblo members and hope that the studio will foster a new storytelling movement, Eyer said.</p><p>“Native Americans are natural storytellers,” he said. “What better place to do it?”</p><p>___</p><p>Associated Press writer Russell Contreras is a member of the AP’s Race and Ethnicity team. Follow Contreras on Twitter at <a href="http://twitter.com/russcontreras">http://twitter.com/russcontreras</a></p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/-AjGhLQb9Cl33cE4S8xEEGhbTgs=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/P57VPO7PYJANLLQZLBIOZP3V5E.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[In this June 25, 2020 photo, Cheyenne and Arapaho filmmaker Chris Eyre, an advisor to Camel Rock Studio, talks about Tesuque Pueblo's new film studio in Santa Fe, N.M. The Native American tribe in northern New Mexico has opened up the movie studio at the site of a former casino aimed at attracting big productions in what is believed to be a first by a Indigenous tribal government in the U.S. (AP Photo/ Russell Contreras)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Russell Contreras]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/66hCIVZeXlxFXTbP06BbiTmnHuM=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/GLY665A7Q5H53KUZBB3VIMYEQE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[This June 25, 2020 photo shows the exterior of Camel Rock Studios, a new film studio owned by Tesuque Pueblo of New Mexico, in Santa Fe, N.M. The Native American tribe in northern New Mexico has opened up the movie studio at the site of a former casino aimed at attracting big productions in what is believed to be a first by a Indigenous tribal government in the U.S. (AP Photo/ Russell Contreras)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Russell Contreras]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Fe23quk-N1kSoSIZg2cd95DOAss=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/2WG6W4EADZA7ZLHREHD5II4CBA.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[In this June 25, 2020 photo, Tunte Vigil, the business development associate of Tesuque Pueblo of New Mexico, shows off a mill at the Camel Rock Studios in Santa Fe, N.M. The Native American tribe in northern New Mexico has opened up the movie studio at the site of a former casino aimed at attracting big productions in what is believed to be a first by a Indigenous tribal government in the U.S. (AP Photo/ Russell Contreras)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Russell Contreras]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/EqoL8AHUzN1Iq-UFbYIf_pXkYBg=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/TWFZWDFBWNFMJDONQ5DFHNMUII.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Tunte Vigil, the business development associate of Tesuque Pueblo of New Mexico, shows off the set of a restaurant at the Camel Rock Studios in Santa Fe, N.M., on Thursday, June 25, 2020. The Native American tribe in northern New Mexico has opened up the movie studio at the site of a former casino aimed at attracting big productions in what is believed to be a first by a Indigenous tribal government in the U.S. (AP Photo/ Russell Contreras)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Russell Contreras]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/FEZ4eT8wTEo4ixd_U30mA4pWe4w=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/R46XHA5ZBZEDHMXVZC7QNC6LPU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Camel Rock, a sandstone formation the shape of a camel, sits at the entrance of Tesuque Pueblo, N.M. on Thursday, June 25, 2020. The Native American tribe in northern New Mexico has opened up a movie studio at the site of a former casino aimed at attracting big productions in what is believed to be a first by a Indigenous tribal government in the U.S. (AP Photo/ Russell Contreras)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Russell Contreras]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/wzAr4V4lpM1ufliqPxeBMX_RFaM=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/IG2GPIKF35AGZHWOBE5Y7JEZQU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A sign marking the land of Tesuque Pueblo of New Mexico is shown on Tesuque Pueblo, on Thursday, June 25, 2020. The Native American tribe in northern New Mexico has opened up a movie studio at the site of a former casino aimed at attracting big productions in what is believed to be a first by a Indigenous tribal government in the U.S. (AP Photo/ Russell Contreras)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Russell Contreras]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Awkwafina, Zendaya among 819 invited to join film academy</title><link>https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/30/awkwafina-zendaya-among-819-invited-to-join-film-academy/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/30/awkwafina-zendaya-among-819-invited-to-join-film-academy/</guid><dc:creator>Lindsey Bahr, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 21:00:09 +0000</pubDate><description>Cynthia Erivo, John David Washington, Eva Longoria, Zendaya and Awkwafina are among the 819 people who have been invited to join the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cynthia Erivo, John David Washington, Eva Longoria, Zendaya and Awkwafina are among the 819 people who have been invited to join the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences. The organization that puts on the Oscars announced the new invitees Tuesday. If they accept, which most do, those in the new class will have voting privileges at this year’s Oscars. </p><p>The massive 2020 list includes a diverse swath of people from all sectors of the industry, from acting to publicity to costume design. Invited actors include Ana De Armas (“Knives Out”), Brian Tyree Henry (“If Beale Street Could Talk”), Florence Pugh (“Little Women”), Lakeith Stanfield (“Sorry to Bother You”), Beanie Feldstein (“Booksmart”) and Constance Wu (“Crazy Rich Asians”). Directors like Lulu Wang (“The Farewell”), Ari Aster (“Midsommar”), Terence Davies (“The House of Mirth”) and Matthew Vaughn (“Layer Cake”) are also on the list. </p><p>A handful of actors from this year’s best picture winner “Parasite,” including Jang Hye-Jin, Jo Yeo-Jeong, Park So-Dam and Lee Jung-Eun, were also invited to join. The Academy said that 49% of the new invitees are international and represent some 68 countries. </p><p>Other notable invitees include TV mogul Ryan Murphy, who produced the documentary “A Secret Love,” country singer Tim McGraw, who was in “The Blind Side” and lyricist Bernie Taupin who contributed to the Elton John biopic “Rocketman.”</p><p>Academy president David Rubin said that the organization is “delighted to welcome these distinguished fellow travelers in the motion picture arts and sciences.” </p><p>Diversifying its ranks continues to be a main focus for the film academy, which film in 2016 committed to doubling its female and minority membership by 2020. It has since surpassed those goals and continues to infuse membership classes with both women and people from underrepresented communities. Women make up 45% of the 2020 class and people of color comprise 36% of the total of invitees this year. The academy has also announced a new <a href="https://apnews.com/5587ee57833d0ff52978b8c1f457d85a">five-year plan</a> that includes implementing inclusion standards for nominees. </p><p>"We look forward to continuing to foster an Academy that reflects the world around us in our membership, our programs, our new Museum, and in our awards,” said academy CEO Dawn Hudson in a written statement. </p><p>This will also be the first year that talent agent members will be able to vote on the awards. </p><p>The 93rd Academy Awards are set to take place on April 25, 2021, <a href="https://apnews.com/7c4aac5857200d9fb43953a2b7e7c40c">two months later than originally planned</a> due to COVID-19’s effects on the industry. </p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/SQuo9y6bZoWurfnuR8gKssmzCPg=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/AB3CJDE5CFCMVDTCQAYM6XBQ5A.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[In this combination, from left, Awkwafina attends the Santa Barbara International Film Festival Virtuosos Award on Jan. 18, 2020, in Santa Barbara, Calif., Cynthia Erivo arrives at the 51st NAACP Image Awards on Feb. 22, 2020, in Pasadena, Calif., Eva Longoria arrives at the Billboard Music Awards on May 1, 2019, in Las Vegas, John David Washington arrives at the 25th annual Screen Actors Guild Awards on Jan. 27, 2019, in Los Angeles and Zendaya arrives at the MTV Movie and TV Awards on June 16, 2018, in Santa Monica, Calif. Awkwafina, Erivo, Longoria, Washington and Zendaya are among the 819 people who have been invited to join the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences. (AP Photo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Uncredited]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Johnny Mandel, the Oscar- and Grammy- winning composer, dies</title><link>https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/30/johnny-mandel-the-oscar-and-grammy-winning-composer-dies/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/30/johnny-mandel-the-oscar-and-grammy-winning-composer-dies/</guid><dc:creator>Hillel Italie, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 18:44:51 +0000</pubDate><description>Johnny Mandel, the Oscar- and Grammy- winning composer, arranger and musician, has died at 94.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Johnny Mandel, the Oscar- and Grammy-winning composer, arranger and musician who worked on albums by Frank Sinatra, Natalie Cole and many others and whose songwriting credits included “The Shadow of Your Smile” and the theme from the film and TV show “M(asterisk)A(asterisk)S(asterisk)H,” has died. He was 94.</p><p>Mandel died Monday of a cardiac ailment at his home in Ojai, California, according to Lauren Iossa, executive vice president and chief marketing officer of ASCAP. Mandel served on the ASCAP board of directors from 1989-2011. </p><p>“Giant. Genius. Gentleman. There are many ways to describe the legendary composer Johnny Mandel. His incredible music spanned decades, mediums, oceans and firmly established him in the American Songbook canon," ASCAP Chairman and President Paul Williams said in tribute.</p><p>Mandel was among the last of the great songwriters to emerge in the pre-rock ‘n’ roll era, his career dating back to the 1940s, and he enjoyed a long and diverse career. He played trombone and trumpet with such big band and jazz artists as Jimmy Dorsey and Count Basie and spent two years in the 1950s arranging music for Sid Caesar’s landmark TV sketch program “Your Show of Shows.” He collaborated on songs with Johnny Mercer, Paul Williams and the husband and wife team Alan and Marilyn Bergman. Artists recording his material ranged from Marvin Gaye to Stan Getz to Barbra Streisand.</p><p>He even worked on the soundtrack for “Caddyshack.”</p><p>“I don’t have a method or a style, and I never wanted one,” Mandel said during a 2010 interview with The National Endowment for the Arts, which the following year gave him a Jazz Masters award for lifetime achievement. “Some guys really try to have a style. I just work with what’s there and try to do the best with what’s there.”</p><p>As an arranger, Mandel worked with some of the greatest singers of his time. When Sinatra launched his own label, Reprise Records, in 1960 he chose Mandel to arrange his first album there, the exuberant “Ring-a-Ding-Ding!” In the early 1990s, Cole called upon him for her Grammy-winning smash “Unforgettable,” which featured duets with tapes of her late father (and Sinatra’s friend), Nat King Cole. </p><p>In recent years he contributed arrangements for Streisand’s “Love Is the Answer” and Tony Bennett’s “The Art of Romance.” Decades earlier, Bennett sang a memorable cover of “The Shadow of Your Smile,” the theme from the Richard Burton-Elizabeth Taylor movie “The Sandpiper.” The Mandel-Paul Francis Webster ballad won a Grammy in 1966 for song of the year, topping the Beatles’ “Yesterday” among others, and received an Oscar for best original song.</p><p>Mandel also helped write soundtracks for “Being There,” “I Want to Live!” and “The Americanization of Emily,” and songs originating from his film work included the Oscar-nominated “A Time for Love” and the Golden Globe-nominated “Molly and Lawless John.”</p><p>His most widely heard composition was likely “Suicide is Painless,” the droll theme from Robert Altman’s Korean War satire “M(asterisk)A(asterisk)S(asterisk)H,” and later for the hit TV show that starred Alan Alda. In a 2008 interview with the blog JazzWax, Mandel explained that Altman had asked him to come up with a song and made two requests: Call it “Suicide is Painless” and make it as stupid as possible.</p><p>“I said to myself, ‘Well I can do stupid,’” Mandel recalled, adding that Altman brought in extra help for the lyrics.</p><p>“Bob was going to take a shot at the lyrics. But he came back two days later and said, ‘I’m sorry but there’s just too much stuff in this 45-year-old brain. I can’t write anything nearly as stupid as what we need.’ Bob said, ‘All is not lost. I’ve got a 15-year-old kid who’s a total idiot.’ So Michael Altman, at age 15, wrote the lyrics, and then I wrote the music to them.”</p><p>Mandel was born in New York City in 1925, and credited some of his passion for music to his mother, Hannah, an opera singer. Aware from an early age he had perfect pitch, he studied at the Manhattan School of Music and the Juilliard School. By the 1940s, he was writing arrangements and performing with such stars as drummer Buddy Rich and such unlikely musicians as saxophonist Alan Greenspan, the future chairman of the Federal Reserve. </p><p>Mandel was primarily a melodist and would seek out lyricists for his songs. For “The Shadow of Your Smile,” he went first to Mercer, with whom he had written “Emily” from “The Americanization of Emily.” But Mercer turned him down, worrying that the song sounded too much like “New Orleans,” by Mercer’s friend Hoagy Carmichael. “Shadow of Your Smile” became a standard, and Mercer would long regret his decision.</p><p>“Years later, he and Hoagy were drinking at a party or something and Hoagy said, “There’s something I meant to ask you for a long time. Why didn’t you write the lyrics to ‘The Shadow of Your Smile?’” Mandel told the NEA. “He (Mercer) told him, ‘I didn’t want to do this to you,’ and Hoagy said, ‘I never noticed.’”</p><p>Mandel was predeceased by his wife, Martha, and survived by his daughter, Marissa Mandel, and her wife, Lauren Johnson. </p><p>___</p><p>AP Entertainment Writer Mark Kennedy contributed to this report.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/B4MT0md6YNahrMQH4YOriouCNck=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/GYCE6JDYRBHZLE27J2LZWOSOPI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - Johnny Mandel appears at the National Endowment for the Arts Jazz Master Awards Ceremony and Concert  in New York on Jan. 11, 2011. Mandel, the Oscar- and Grammy- winning composer, arranger and musician, died Monday, June 29, 2020, of a cardiac ailment at his home in Ojai, Calif. He was 94. (AP Photo/Charles Sykes, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Charles Sykes]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Tu7KIuGYRYTZ0z_lARyuDhBaoUc=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/25NZDX5AERGTFEXEOZNYQ2NUWU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - Johnny Mandel appears at the National Endowment for the Arts Jazz Master Awards Ceremony and Concert  in New York on Jan. 11, 2011. Mandel, the Oscar- and Grammy- winning composer, arranger and musician, died Monday, June 29, 2020, of a cardiac ailment at his home in Ojai, Calif. He was 94. (AP Photo/Charles Sykes, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Charles Sykes]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Using 'face doubles,' new HBO doc captures LGBTQ purge</title><link>https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/29/using-face-doubles-a-new-doc-captures-an-anti-lgbtq-purge/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/29/using-face-doubles-a-new-doc-captures-an-anti-lgbtq-purge/</guid><dc:creator>Jake Coyle, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 18:29:55 +0000</pubDate><description>Anonymous sources in documentaries have often been reduced to a shadowy, voice-distorted figure, or a pixelated blur.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Anonymous sources in documentaries have often been reduced to a shadowy, voice-distorted figure — or worse, a pixelated blur. </p><p>But a new documentary premiering Tuesday on HBO has, with the aid of advanced digital technology, gone to greater lengths to preserve the secrecy of its sources while still conveying their humanity.</p><p>
<a href="https://www.hbo.com/documentaries/welcome-to-chechnya">“Welcome to Chechnya,”</a> directed by David France, is about an underground pipeline created to rescue LGBTQ Chechens from the Russian republic where the government has for several years <a href="https://apnews.com/63a15d4aa08247c5b9115f7b5db91eb2">waged a crackdown on gays</a>. In the predominantly Muslim region in southern Russia ruled by strongman Ramzan Kadyrov, LGBTQ Chechens have been detained, tortured and killed.</p><p>France, the filmmaker behind “How to Survive a Plague” and “The Death and Life of Marsha P. Johnson,” worked in secrecy with the Russian LGBT Network, a group formed to help save gay Chechens and find them asylum abroad. But France had a dilemma. He couldn’t reveal the identities, or the faces, of his main characters. Their lives depended on staying anonymous.</p><p>Yet France still wanted to faithfully show the trials they were enduring. This was a tragedy that needed a face. That meant none of the old methods of cloaking anonymous sources would work.</p><p>“They were dehumanizing,” France said in an interview. “I believe one of the reasons we haven’t been hearing about this ongoing crime against humanity in the south of Russia is because we haven’t been able to hear from the people and see the people who have suffered this unspeakable torture. When the only testimony of a crime of this magnitude comes from people who are behind a curtain, it lacks the empathy of the public that this story truly deserves.”</p><p>France didn’t know how he would resolve the issue, but he promised those he shot that he would somehow disguise them. After searching and testing a range of approaches, France settled on a novel one: In “Welcome to Chechnya,” the faces of all the LGBTQ Chechens have been replaced using artificial intelligence. It’s a little like the documentary answer to “The Irishman” or a more altruistic version of a <a href="https://apnews.com/21fa207a1254401197fd1e0d7ecd14cb/I-never-said-that!-High-tech-deception-of-'deepfake'-videos">“deepfake.”</a></p><p>The faces seen in “Welcome to Chechnya” belong, in fact, to 22 volunteers whose faces were superimposed on the people in the film. Most of them are LGBTQ activists in New York. The “face doubles” were shot on a blue screen stage and converted into algorithms that, with machine learning, could digitally mask the subjects of the film. Different voices were substituted, too.</p><p>“Nobody had ever really attempted this before,” said France. “And most people said it was impossible. It turned out it was pretty close to impossible but not impossible.”</p><p>The technology was developed by software architect Ryan Laney. And its implementation was decided through a study organized by Dartmouth College professor Thalia Wheatley, an expert in brain sciences. She showed 109 students different visual effects options of “Welcome to Chechnya” to determine which one conveyed empathy the best and avoided an “uncanny valley” effect. (Another less successful option was using filters to render the film’s individuals cartoon-like caricatures.)</p><p>Still, adding the face doubles throughout the film was a grueling, months-long process that only concluded a week before the premiere of “Welcome to Chechnya” at the Sundance Film Festival in January. “The Irishman,” by comparison, altered its actors’ faces in highly planned scenes with carefully orchestrated camera movement. France’s documentary was full of erratic movements of both camera and people.</p><p>Every step of the way, France and his editors worked on encryption drives, and never let their original footage with real faces touch the internet or even a computer that had previously been connected to the internet. They edited in what France calls a windowless bunker in Los Angeles.</p><p>“It added a lot of time to our work,” said France, “But it reminded us everyday what the stakes were and what it meant to be the people whose lives were shared with us and entrusted us in sharing their lives with a wider audience.”</p><p>___</p><p>Follow AP Film Writer Jake Coyle on Twitter at <a href="http://twitter.com/jakecoyleAP">http://twitter.com/jakecoyleAP</a></p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/V6mYybV4HJdCLHJKfw9lcDhM-uU=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/RENGVTCIAJGRPERYHVLZBWJD44.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[This undated photo provided by HBO Documentary Films shows a scene from "Welcome to Chechnya," about an underground pipeline created to rescue LGBTQ Chechens from the Russian republic where the government has waged a crackdown of gays. (HBO Documentary Films via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Uncredited]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/1ySGS9hL8JcBumB7O14Lj_6GmqY=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/JTT2MAU7FRDB7JKTROSLY3PQJ4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[This undated photo provided by HBO Documentary Films shows a scene from "Welcome to Chechnya," about an underground pipeline created to rescue LGBTQ Chechens from the Russian republic where the government has waged a crackdown of gays. (HBO Documentary Films via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Uncredited]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/FZCSEGn7mxh8tmSw9WlFtxIoOGw=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/E25C23RB6RFXPPEL4H5W7CFNXM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Jan. 26, 2020 file photo director David France poses for a portrait to promote the film "Welcome to Chechnya" during the Sundance Film Festival in Park City, Utah. The documentary is about an underground pipeline created to rescue LGBTQ Chechens from the Russian republic where the government has waged a crackdown of gays. (Photo by Taylor Jewell/Invision/AP, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Taylor Jewell]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/DGIPu6Ya0ebJ6o2G9NYgXgIiJkc=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/XS4WJOW7R5AHFDNHLE6TBCJDAY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Jan. 26, 2020 file photo, Olga Baranova, from left, David Isteev, director David France, and Maxim Lapunov pose for a portrait to promote the film "Welcome to Chechnya" during the Sundance Film Festival in Park City, Utah. The documentary is about an underground pipeline created to rescue LGBTQ Chechens from the Russian republic where the government has waged a crackdown of gays. (Photo by Taylor Jewell/Invision/AP, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Taylor Jewell]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/qcwXyUGrQlN7lGOMsUfXg8dSb2Q=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/JMQGQOPNWBHULH7UE35EEXWEKI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Jan. 26, 2020 file photo, Olga Baranova, from left, Maxim Lapunov, and David Isteev pose for a portrait to promote the film "Welcome to Chechnya" during the Sundance Film Festival in Park City, Utah. The documentary is about an underground pipeline created to rescue LGBTQ Chechens from the Russian republic where the government has waged a crackdown of gays. (Photo by Taylor Jewell/Invision/AP File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Taylor Jewell]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Supreme Court: Booking.com can trademark its name</title><link>https://www.local10.com/business/2020/06/30/supreme-court-bookingcom-can-trademark-its-name/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/business/2020/06/30/supreme-court-bookingcom-can-trademark-its-name/</guid><dc:creator>Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 15:45:09 +0000</pubDate><description>The Supreme Court says travel website Booking.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Supreme Court says travel website Booking.com can trademark its name, a ruling that also impacts other companies whose name is a generic word followed by “.com.”</p><p>The high court issued its 8-1 ruling Tuesday. Lower courts had sided with Booking.com, but the Trump administration had appealed to the Supreme Court. </p><p>“We have no cause to deny Booking.com the same benefits Congress accorded other marks qualifying as nongeneric,” Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/19pdf/19-46_8n59.pdf">wrote </a> for the majority of the court. </p><p>Justice Stephen Breyer dissented.</p><p>Other businesses including Cars.com, Dictionary.com, Newspapers.com and Wine.com had said the outcome in the case would affect their ability to trademark their names too.</p><p>The case was the <a href="https://apnews.com/fe767ffb8833bb059f8eabfd529365a0">first of 10 cases</a> argued by telephone in May because of the coronavirus pandemic. It was also the first time audio of arguments was available live. </p><p>The case is United States Patent and Trademark Office v. Booking.com B.V., 19-46.</p><p>___</p><p>Follow AP’s Supreme Court Twitter feed at https://twitter.com/AP_Courtside. </p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/M0668kjJV9cm1vWEbE6nojEGkXE=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/GW2YTCDWQNDNNEKYE67K5KU2LQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The Supreme Court is seen on Capitol Hill in Washington, Monday, June 29, 2020. (AP Photo/Patrick Semansky)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Patrick Semansky]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>An eventful year for Pulitzer Prize winner Colson Whitehead</title><link>https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/30/an-eventful-year-for-pulitzer-prize-winner-colson-whitehead/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/entertainment/2020/06/30/an-eventful-year-for-pulitzer-prize-winner-colson-whitehead/</guid><dc:creator>Hillel Italie, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 12:48:30 +0000</pubDate><description>Even sheltering in place, Colson Whitehead has had an eventful year.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Even sheltering in place, Colson Whitehead has had an eventful year. </p><p>Whitehead became the first fiction writer to win Pulitzers for back to back novels, “Underground Railroad” and “The Nickel Boys,” which won the Pulitzer in May and comes out in paperback this week. He also managed to finish a crime novel, with the working title “Harlem Shuffle,” that he had begun more than a year ago.</p><p>"I was on the downward slope of the book when the quarantine started," said Whitehead during a recent telephone interview. “For the first eight weeks, most of the time was spent looking after the kids, making sure the Wi-Fi was on so they could do their schooling. Then I finished the draft of the book — not sure how it happened. You just have to find the time and not get too distracted to do the final leg of the book.”</p><p>Whitehead, 50, who has been staying in Long Island with his wife and two children. He has been a published author since his acclaimed debut novel, “The Intuitionist,” came out in 1999, and he has well established himself for his vivid prose style and imagination. “Zone One,” published in 2011, is speculative fiction that depicts a pandemic-stricken New York City, a narrative which became painfully timely during the coronavirus outbreak. “Underground Railroad” combined historical detail from the 19th century and a unique twist: Whitehead imagined the network for bringing runaway slaves North to their freedom as a literal railroad. </p><p>“The Nickel Boys” stays closer to the facts: It's based on a notorious Florida boarding school from the Jim Crow era that brutalized and sometimes murdered the kids sent there. One protagonist is a promising teenager who lands in the Nickel school after being accused of a crime he didn't commit. </p><p>“In ‘Underground Railroad,' I felt I needed a fantastic device to move Cora (the main character) to her freedom. With ‘The Nickel Boys,’ there was no need for any kind of fantastic flourish. The situation speaks for itself," Whitehead said. </p><p>During his interview, Whitehead also discussed the Black Lives Matter protests, early influences and how each book reflects the person he was while writing it. </p><p>Here are highlights:</p><p>CHILDHOOD READING: “I wanted to write from a very early age, just from reading Marvel Comics and Stephen King, and Arthur C. Clarke and Ray Bradbury. I consumed fantastic fiction and loved how you could make possible whatever weird idea you had in your head. Your taking your eccentric ideas and trying to convince the reader that they're plausible.”</p><p>HOW REAL LIFE SOMETIMES REMINDS HIM OF ‘ZONE ONE’: “I have tried not to think about that book because things turn out pretty terribly. I was terrified those first couple of weeks (of the pandemic) and I felt the same thing after the hurricane (Sunday) a few years ago, when lower Manhattan was blacked out. It was like walking through ‘Zone One.' And now it's real and it's more scary than I thought." </p><p>HOW LIFE HAS CHANGED SINCE DESCRIBING HIMSELF AS INCAPABLE OF JOY IN THE 2014 NONFICTION BOOK ON POKER “THE NOBLE HUSTLE": “I was this depressed guy going through this midlife crisis and having this wonderful writing assignment (to write about the World Series of Poker) fall into my lap. It's really who I was in 2011, and in order to keep that inner voice, I had to impersonate who I had been two years before. When I look back through all my work .... I think who I was at the time is always determining how the book turns out. </p><p>"For ‘The Nickel Boys,’ I was someone trying to figure out where the country was going. It was during the first months of the Trump administration and in Elwood and Turner (the book's two main characters), I had Elwood being the optimist and Turner being the pessimist."</p><p>ON THE BLACK LIVES MATTER PROTESTS: "I grew up in New York and in the early ‘80s and every other day it seemed there was a case of police brutality and we’d have this conversation about how that has to change and nothing happened. My whole life has been me seeing these documented cases that result in zero change. </p><p>“But I've been surprised how far reaching and involved the protests have been. You're seeing people in white, tony towns in the South and the Midwest and you're seeing protesters in New York and on Fifth Avenue and in Union Square and at the Barclay Center. I've been delighted and surprised how people have seized the moment. It feels like we're moving somewhere in the country. I'm usually pessimistic about where things are going, but the protests have made me feel a little different.”</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/96aUB69LX-TUe-ZHicswNZqNNrc=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/DXYN2PGINVAPHKNQLB3KOGB2EM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[This combination photo shows the cover of the Pulitzer Prize winning novel "The Nickel Boys," left, and a portrait of author Colson Whitehead. Whitehead became the first fiction writer to win Pulitzer Prizes for back to back novels. The Nickel Boys,  his followup to Underground Railroad, won the Pulitzer in April and comes out in paperback this week. He also managed to finish a crime novel, with the working title Harlem Shuffle, that he began more than a year ago.  (Doubleday, left, and Madeline Whitehead/Doubleday via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Uncredited]]></media:credit></media:content></item></channel></rss>