<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"><channel><title>WPLG Local 10</title><link>https://www.local10.com</link><atom:link href="https://www.local10.com/arcio/rss/category/news/national/?size=10" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>WPLG Local 10 News Feed</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:57:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><ttl>1</ttl><sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod><sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency><item><title>US Rep Horn easily captures Democratic nod in 5th District</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/oklahoma-city-voters-to-pare-down-crowded-5th-district-field/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/oklahoma-city-voters-to-pare-down-crowded-5th-district-field/</guid><dc:creator>Associated Press, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:47:48 +0000</pubDate><description>Voters in Oklahoma will pare down a crowded field of congressional hopefuls seeking to represent the state's 5th District in Washington.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. Rep. Kendra Horn easily dispatched her lone opponent Tuesday to capture the Democratic nomination in Oklahoma's 5th Congressional District, while Republicans were paring down a crowded field of congressional hopefuls looking to replace her.</p><p>In the race for Oklahoma’s U.S. Senate seat, incumbent U.S. Sen. Jim Inhofe defeated three GOP challengers and will face Democrat Abby Broyles, an attorney and former television reporter from Oklahoma City who also bested three primary challengers. </p><p>The real challenge for Horn, the only Democrat in Oklahoma's congressional delegation, comes in November. Nine Republicans are vying to replace her. The 44-year-old attorney pulled one of the nation’s biggest congressional upsets in 2018 when she won a seat that had been in Republican hands for four decades. Tuesday she defeated perennial candidate Tom Guild, a retired college professor from Edmond</p><p>Horn is considered one of the most vulnerable Democratic incumbents in the nation because she represents a district President Donald Trump won by nearly 14 points in 2016.</p><p>“I like her and think she's doing a great job," said Darla Ryan, 59, a Democrat who cast her ballot for Horn Tuesday at Life Church in Edmond, Oklahoma. “I voted for her last time, too."</p><p>Four of the GOP challengers have raised more than $500,000, including businesswoman Terry Neese, state Sen. Stephanie Bice, former state education superintendent Janet Barresi and businessman David Hill. The crowded field makes a primary runoff likely.</p><p>Horn has raised more than $3.3 million this cycle, the most of anyone in the state’s delegation.</p><p>While a record number of Oklahomans cast absentee ballots by mail this year, turnout was steady Tuesday at several polling places in the Oklahoma City metro area. At Life Church, most voters were wearing masks and maintaining social distancing in a line that stretched into the parking lot.</p><p>Savannah Steele, 19, a college student from Edmond who was voting for the first time, said the coronavirus pandemic made her uneasy.</p><p>“In Oklahoma, with (the number of reported cases) spiking, that was a concern, but with people staying six feet apart and wearing masks, it was fine," Steele said.</p><p>Two other Republican incumbents, U.S. Reps. Markwayne Mullin and Tom Cole, also won their primaries Tuesday. Republican U.S. Reps. Kevin Hern and Frank Lucas do not have primary opponents. </p><p>Also on the ballot Tuesday is a proposal to amend the Oklahoma Constitution to extend Medicaid health coverage to tens of thousands of low-income residents. Oklahoma is one of 14 states that have not expanded Medicaid — along with neighboring states Texas and Kansas—as part of the 2010 federal Affordable Care Act.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/bryJaTVxu8PudcLhL8kL3GiiK2o=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/MB3BBURLYNG4RDFFFM2FN5XAZQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[File-This May 10, 2018, file photo shows Kendra Horn speaking during a forum for Oklahoma 5th congressional district seat Democratic candidates for the group Edmond Democratic Women in Edmond, Okla. Nine Republicans are vying for the seat held by first-term U.S. Rep. Horn, the only Democrat in the states delegation. The 44-year-old attorney pulled one of the nations biggest congressional upsets in 2018 when she won a seat that had been in Republican hands for four decades. Horn herself also faces a primary opponent in perennial candidate Tom Guild, a retired professor from Edmond. (AP Photo/Sue Ogrocki, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Sue Ogrocki]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/lV6WE016NQVDl6XROHhRZwDbhEg=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/4MROQ25HW5AQPGVJMNGC525JRA.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Hand cleaner for voters after voting at precinct 61 in Edmond, Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Doug Hoke/The Oklahoman via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Doug Hoke]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/I8ZVUGOUt4nXTtG6rmthwFjHkyw=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/JWLWFBD7CNFDDB5LYW5FS6JRQQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Pole worker Bob Tipton hands a ballot to a voter during voting at precinct 61 in Edmond, Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Doug Hoke/The Oklahoman via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Doug Hoke]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/mR7j8vkHXDHG0VE4FpELFRpMAco=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/7KZ5BOWKTFDZLKJ3IH2O4RCRCY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Social distancing for voting at precinct 61 in Edmond, Okla., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Doug Hoke/The Oklahoman via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Doug Hoke]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/SLHqdfAkQVYe1lQICmvrmo-Ndp8=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/UV3NTQQS2NCCHI44GVUGRBPXGU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Jo Shepard collects her ballot at Bixby North Elementary School in Bixby, Okla., on Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Matt Barnard/Tulsa World via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Matt Barnard]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/IUM7I9B-6kzWzUwZobp6Cimnp5I=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/QQPTJHDSIFFZDHGMNB6EOYD2IQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A voter signs in to cast a voting ballot at Canadian Hills Church of the Nazarene on Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Oklahoma City, Okla. (Chris Landsberger/The Oklahoman, via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Chris Landsberger]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/lDPrm-BKGQxXHXybBPqSxE6GieI=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/X2C4RVGNAVHXRLS3BTUZAKPU6E.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Jame Loe, right, signs in voter John Parker at Canadian Hills Church of the Nazarene on Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Oklahoma City, Okla. (Chris Landsberger/The Oklahoman, via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Chris Landsberger]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/YsRQRHuak9qLdDlYgjL1MnbwfoA=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/SG5THQ6YXZBOPMJDDYIM3PWI54.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Precinct worker Carol Monlux signs in Jennifer Blankenship before voting at Wright Elementary School in Tulsa, Okla., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Stephen Pingry/Tulsa World via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Stephen Pingry]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/fhJ-fphR5El6CUBy0Zv3L51OLvI=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/HFO6RDUTL5FNVMCLQYALSZBRYE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Voters collect their ballots at Bixby North Elementary School in Bixby, Okla., on Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (Matt Barnard/Tulsa World/Tulsa World via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Matt Barnard]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Oklahoma voters to decide whether to expand Medicaid</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/oklahoma-voters-to-decide-whether-to-expand-medicaid/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/politics/2020/06/30/oklahoma-voters-to-decide-whether-to-expand-medicaid/</guid><dc:creator>Associated Press, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:42:11 +0000</pubDate><description>Oklahoma voters are deciding whether to amend the state Constitution to expand Mediciad health coverage to tens of thousands of low-income residents.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oklahoma voters are deciding Tuesday whether to expand Medicaid to tens of thousands of low-income residents and become the first state to amend their Constitution to do so.</p><p>Though an increasing number of Oklahoma voters took advantage of mail-in voting for Tuesday's primary, polls are open from 7 a.m. to 7 p.m. statewide.</p><p>Idaho, Maine, Nebraska and Utah have all expanded Medicaid through ballot questions, but did so by amending state statutes, according to the nonpartisan Kaiser Family Foundation. </p><p>Amending the Oklahoma Constitution would prevent the Republican-controlled Legislature, which has resisted Medicaid expansion for a decade, from tinkering with the program or rolling back coverage. Missouri voters also will decide on a constitutional amendment on Aug. 4.</p><p>State Question 802 would extend Medicaid health insurance to those earning up to 138% of the federal poverty level, which is about $17,200 for an individual or $35,500 for a family of four.</p><p>Oklahoma is one of 14 states, along with neighboring Texas and Kansas, that have not expanded Medicaid under the 2010 federal Affordable Care Act. Republican Gov. Kevin Stitt and his predecessor, Mary Fallin, have opposed expansion, citing uncertainty about future costs for the state.</p><p>“We have a billion-dollar shortfall next year," Stitt said recently at a forum hosted by Americans for Prosperity, a conservative political advocacy group that opposes the measure. The state would have to “either raise taxes or to cut services somewhere else like education, first responders, or roads and bridges” to cut additional Medicaid costs, he said.</p><p>After years of legislative inaction on health insurance proposals, supporters of Medicaid expansion <a href="https://apnews.com/abb64dda7de84544b66d679852aff8a9">launched an initiative petition</a> last year to get the measure on the ballot, and collected a <a href="https://apnews.com/0c5081af1cc44a2bb6282fdb714bf350">record number</a> of signatures. The plan was endorsed by several politically powerful groups, including chambers of commerce, medical trade groups, the Oklahoma Education Association and the Oklahoma Conference of Churches.</p><p>Some Republican opposition to Medicaid expansion has eroded in recent years, particularly in rural areas where hospitals have suffered financial problems or closed. </p><p>Kevin Penry, a Republican and retired pastor from Edmond, said that before going on Medicare last month he had to buy expensive insurance on the federal marketplace, which “really made me feel for folks who are in a difficult financial situation." He said he voted for the expansion.</p><p>The Oklahoma Health Care Authority has projected that about 215,000 residents would qualify for a Medicaid expansion, for a total annual cost of about $1.3 billion. The estimated state share would be about $164 million. But those numbers could be considerably higher given the number of Oklahomans who have lost their jobs and work-related health insurance because of the economic shutdown amid the coronavirus pandemic.</p><p>If the proposal passes, the Legislature is expected to increase a fee that hospitals pay from 2.5% to 4%, which would generate about $134 million annually. Stitt vetoed such a measure earlier this year.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/HiFzJ9xG9bobLba8V-JXNWCeGzQ=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/MCJP67ET7RA7JN7WX5LVIB6PBY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Oct. 24, 2019, file photo, supporters of Yes on 802 Oklahomans Decide Healthcare, calling for Medicaid expansion to be put on the ballot, carry boxes of petitions into the office of the Oklahoma Secretary of State in Oklahoma City. Oklahoma voters will decide Tuesday, June 30, 2020, whether to expand Medicaid to tens of thousands of low-income residents and become the first state to amend their Constitution to do so. (AP Photo/Sue Ogrocki, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Sue Ogrocki]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/EjhHpy5cWME2L69qZ2BDXYJ8eSw=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/NTUM6D72C5HIFFLCYVEZVDOHU4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Amber England, left, campaign manager, Yes on 802, and Russell Griffin, right, campaign field director, check results online after the polls closed Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Oklahoma City, in a vote in which Oklahoma voters are deciding whether to amend the state Constitution to expand Medicaid health coverage to tens of thousands of low-income residents. (AP Photo/Sue Ogrocki)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Sue Ogrocki]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Jdppsjc87isOv1dQU-yVyK20-1Q=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/PFA7BX47L5FLFEW62HWL4BNNBE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Amber England, campaign manager for Yes on 802, addresses supporters via the internet Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Oklahoma City. Supporter awaited results in a virtual watch party as Oklahoma voters decided whether to amend the state Constitution to expand Medicaid health coverage to tens of thousands of low-income residents. (AP Photo/Sue Ogrocki)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Sue Ogrocki]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/pVeKJtTseG48FkkOVFBCehU3jOo=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/ES4I3PVSGZH4NC6NOYJQUDK36Y.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Amber England, campaign manager, Yes on 802, addresses supporters via the internet Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Oklahoma City, as due to Covid-19 concerns, a virtual watch party replaces the normal watch party, as they await results in a vote in which Oklahoma voters are deciding whether to amend the state Constitution to expand Medicaid health coverage to tens of thousands of low-income residents. (AP Photo/Sue Ogrocki)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Sue Ogrocki]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Arizona faces new closures as hospitals prep for virus surge</title><link>https://www.local10.com/health/2020/06/30/arizona-faces-new-closures-as-hospitals-prep-for-virus-surge/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/health/2020/06/30/arizona-faces-new-closures-as-hospitals-prep-for-virus-surge/</guid><dc:creator>Jonathan J. Cooper And Jacques Billeaud, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:23:47 +0000</pubDate><description>Arizona hospitals are hiring out-of-state nurses, squeezing in more beds and preparing for the possibility of making life-and-death decisions about how to ration care as they get ready for an expected surge of coronavirus patients.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Arizona hospitals are hiring out-of-state nurses, squeezing in more beds and preparing for the possibility of making life-and-death decisions about how to ration care as they get ready for an expected surge of coronavirus patients in one of the nation's worst hot spots.</p><p>Parents, teachers, businesses and their customers also are hunkering down for at least a month of new <a href="https://apnews.com/b42fb52eaa5ba19956cca0c7aabd9a52"> closures</a> imposed by the state in a belated effort to slow the <a href="https://apnews.com/8e2b3b7ca3bb2475b9ae901dad4e09ee">spread of the virus</a> and limit overcrowding at hospitals. </p><p>
<a href="https://apnews.com/7aa2fcf7955333834e01a7f9217c77d2">Arizona and several other states</a> that were reopening their economies have clamped back down over the past week as they eclipsed records for infections and hospitalizations. Republican Gov. Doug Ducey, however, went further than others by ordering gyms and movie theaters to close and postponing the start of school until mid-August.</p><p>Texas shut down bars and reduced restaurant capacity, while Florida, where some beaches have been closed, banned alcohol consumption at bars. In contrast, Ducey shut down all bars for 30 days, including in Scottsdale, where employees and young customers crammed into nightclubs without wearing masks or practicing social distancing. </p><p>Like Texas Gov. Greg Abbott, Ducey ordered tubing businesses to close after images over the weekend showed large numbers of tubers on the Salt River without masks. While Texas limited the number of people at water parks, Arizona closed them altogether for 30 days.</p><p>Tom Hatten, founder and chief executive of Mountainside Fitness, a chain of about 20 gyms across metro Phoenix, said Tuesday that he has no plans to shut down. He has filed court paperwork seeking an injunction against Ducey's closure order, calling it arbitrary and irrational.</p><p>Hatten also said several of his health club’s facilities were cited by police Tuesday for being open.</p><p>Under Ducey's order, the citations carry a fine up to $2,500 if convicted.</p><p>Hatten said it doesn’t make sense that casinos, restaurants and big-box stores can stay open, while gyms are forced to close. </p><p>“We are just as concerned about this virus as everyone. But singling out and closing health clubs, after we sat closed for two months, is not going to keep the virus from spreading,” Hatten said. </p><p>Ducey’s executive order allows local police to enforce closures and government agencies to revoke business licenses. </p><p>In another sign of upheaval, cities are canceling Fourth of July fireworks shows, among them Peoria, Chandler and Marana. Others had already made plans to cancel.</p><p>Vice President Mike Pence is scheduled to visit Phoenix on Wednesday and meet with Ducey at the airport before speaking to reporters. It wasn't clear if he had other plans before returning to Washington. Pence’s last-minute trip replaces a planned campaign event in Tucson and meeting with Ducey in Yuma.</p><p>An additional 44 people have died from COVID-19, bringing the total since the beginning of the outbreak to 1,632, health officials said. They reported nearly 4,700 new coronavirus cases Tuesday, an inflated number because of an undercount Monday.</p><p>Arizona has seen skyrocketing infections this month after Ducey allowed his stay-at-home order to expire on May 15. Over the past seven days, nearly one in four coronavirus tests has been positive, a rate far higher than any other state. The positivity rate is a measure of how widespread the disease is in the community. </p><p>Preparing for an influx of patients, hospitals are activating plans to add more beds and staff. State officials have authorized “crisis standards of care,” which tell hospitals which patients should get a ventilator or other scarce resources if there is a shortage. </p><p>If there are more patients than can be cared for at ideal levels, patients are given a score based on their life expectancy and the likelihood their organs will fail. Hospitals are told not to consider factors like race, gender, sexual orientation or disabilities. </p><p>Emergency rooms are not yet overwhelmed, but COVID-19 is taking its toll, said Dr. Frank DelVecchio, who works in emergency rooms at several Phoenix-area hospitals, including Valleywise Health. Nurses caring for coronavirus patients take a significant amount of time suiting up to protect themselves and can't quickly jump from room to room, he said. </p><p>“This is just off the charts, sick patients. We’re letting people go home that we'd never let go home if they were this sick,” including patients with low oxygen, DelVecchio said. “We're trying to get you home oxygen. We’re trying to tell you to come back if worse. Because there's not much we can do for you." </p><p>People who have attempted or considered suicide are getting stuck for a day or more in emergency rooms because psychiatric facilities won't accept them until they have COVID-19 test results. Because suicidal patients require constant monitoring, they are sometimes placed in hallways or less private areas while awaiting results, DelVecchio said. </p><p>Dignity Health, which operates several hospitals in the Phoenix area, is converting more areas to treat COVID-19 patients and preparing to put multiple patients in private rooms, spokeswoman Carmelle Malkovich said. It’s bringing nurses from underutilized hospitals in its system to Arizona and hiring traveling nurses and respiratory therapists throughout July. </p><p>HonorHealth, another big hospital chain in the Phoenix area, is prepared to implement the first phase of its surge plan as soon as this week, officials said in a statement. They did not explain what that means. </p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/aI9mq0oaNoRk7JMlpDVwMHeEW6g=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/U4RD64B2NNCINLNRDY7CMHVCVI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Bottled Blonde, one of the many restaurant bars closed for the next 30 days due to the surge in coronavirus cases, is padlocked shut Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Scottsdale, Ariz. (AP Photo/Ross D. Franklin)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ross D. Franklin]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/8wF15K0lbQhqhFSOxrhyHalT1sM=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/CX4ZHGDEGBBMXNSOFMQLCMLE7E.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A parking lot is empty at a local high school Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Tempe, Ariz. Schools will remain vacant two weeks longer this summer after Arizona Gov. Doug Ducey re-shut down bars, movie theaters, gyms, water parks and his delayed the start of school amid a dramatic resurgence of coronavirus cases. (AP Photo/Matt York)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Matt York]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/I5_n7TMFdASHAnyIfJeH8Wbo_ho=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/NYNOIIQ25BBJLENVJFTPHUKGSU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A pedestrian with a takeout lunch in hand walks through an area of Scottsdale, Ariz., known for busy restaurants, bars and nightlife Tuesday, June 30, 2020, with most businesses closed for the next 30 days due to the surge in coronavirus cases in Arizona. (AP Photo/Ross D. Franklin)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ross D. Franklin]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/QxUJpOpTQMQsRYYd4ajIF4G9H6M=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/OEHXGSP5EBFJHDA5FNAZNOFMAE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Bottled Blonde, one of the restaurant bars closed for the next 30 days due to the surge in coronavirus cases, has a posted rules sign but also has a padlocked front door Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Scottsdale, Ariz. (AP Photo/Ross D. Franklin)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ross D. Franklin]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/4ggXQ1e0V872s1zQOGBfh9Geb48=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/7LOS4IRV4NE6ZEKHUOJ2VNSXDI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Temporary signs set up in front of main services building at Kiwanis Park lets patrons know what is open and what is closed as new rules have shut down many activities due to the surge in coronavirus cases Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Tempe, Ariz. (AP Photo/Ross D. Franklin)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ross D. Franklin]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/RyQDECmLnhOSOCwOfDBXiY_DfSU=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/7B6PSATTD5BGBF4KDG6TCLLAGU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The Riot House, one of the restaurant bars closed for the next 30 days due to the surge in coronavirus cases, even as the social distancing sign is placed in a window Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Scottsdale, Ariz. (AP Photo/Ross D. Franklin)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ross D. Franklin]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/asKLjxxioabBZf_PIE0Y0K5SaXI=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/O33TLBWFLVGGVPM2CG3FOGZIZM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Social distancing signs are posted at one of the bars closed for the next 30 days due to the surge in coronavirus cases Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Scottsdale, Ariz. (AP Photo/Ross D. Franklin)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ross D. Franklin]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/cNXqnEwYx-PYWWh6_DogU-NYNgo=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/SG4MYE4LF5D6NFV5BFHYSMNIKY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The closed El Hefe restaurant and bar is one of the many establishments closed for the next 30 days due to the surge in coronavirus cases, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Scottsdale, Ariz. (AP Photo/Ross D. Franklin)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ross D. Franklin]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/V-ZoQe8T7SpvlnexFiarLl6ciOA=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/FF7SV3PRCNGXFLNKIIMZGWIOHI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A vehicle drives past a temporary sign set up at an entrance at Kiwanis Park lets patrons know what is closed as new rules have shut down many activities due to the surge in coronavirus cases Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Tempe, Ariz. (AP Photo/Ross D. Franklin)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ross D. Franklin]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/sL7leC0k71bERcylrr3GMPPUXTU=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/COJ7CJLZ5BBCXHKFSZKS2ST2UE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A water park sits idle despite temperatures over 100 degrees Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in Chandler, Ariz. Arizona Gov. Doug Ducey has shut down bars, movie theaters, gyms and water parks amid a dramatic resurgence of coronavirus cases. (AP Photo/Matt York)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Matt York]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>City crews remove some barriers from Seattle protest zone</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/national/2020/06/30/city-crews-remove-some-barriers-from-seattle-protest-zone/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/national/2020/06/30/city-crews-remove-some-barriers-from-seattle-protest-zone/</guid><dc:creator>Lisa Baumann, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:11:19 +0000</pubDate><description>Seattle city crews used heavy equipment to remove makeshift barriers around the city’s “occupied” protest zone following two fatal shootings in the area.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Seattle city crews used heavy equipment Tuesday to remove makeshift barriers around the city’s “occupied” protest zone following two fatal shootings in the area.</p><p>Demonstrators dragged couches and other items to replace the structures. But those were largely gone later Tuesday. </p><p>People have occupied several blocks around a park and the Seattle Police Department’s East Precinct for about two weeks after police abandoned the building following standoffs and clashes with protesters calling for racial justice and an end to police brutality.</p><p>Seattle police Assistant Chief Adrian Diaz said the large, makeshift barriers would be removed in incremental steps to allow traffic to move through portions of a road that had been closed off.</p><p>“So far, you know, everything is peaceful this morning, so that’s a good sign,” Diaz <a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/seattle-removes-some-barriers-at-chop/">told</a> The Seattle Times.</p><p>Cement barricades that remained in front of the Seattle Police Department East Precinct building Tuesday were fortified by protesters with chunks of concrete and tarps. </p><p>There have been increasing calls by critics, including President Donald Trump, to remove protesters from the “Capitol Hill Occupied Protest” area east of downtown following the fatal shooting Monday of a 16-year-old boy and the June 20 killing of a 19-year-old man. </p><p>Protesters say they should not be blamed for the violence in the area. People continued to add artwork, flowers and candles at a memorial for the 16-year-old on Tuesday. </p><p>Police Chief Carmen Best has said the shootings are obscuring the message of racial justice promoted by protesters.</p><p>Nearby businesses and property owners filed a federal lawsuit against the city last week, saying officials have been too tolerant of those who created the zone and that officials have deprived property owners of their property rights by allowing the zone to continue existing.</p><p>Also Tuesday, Mayor Jenny Durkan asked the City Council to investigate council member Kshama Sawant, accusing her of opening City Hall to protesters on June 9 and participating in a protest march to Durkan’s home on Sunday. </p><p>“She and organizers knew that my address was protected under the state confidentiality program because of threats against me due largely to my work as U.S. attorney,” Durkan wrote.</p><p>Sawant said she had not organized the march and wasn't taking Durkan's words personally, The Seattle Times <a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/politics/durkan-asks-seattle-city-council-to-investigate-sawant-for-contemptuous-behavior/">reported</a>. </p><p>“In reality, this is an attack on working people’s movements, and everything we are fighting for, by a corporate politician desperately looking to distract from her failures of leadership and politically bankrupt administration,” Sawant said in a statement.</p><p>Earlier this month Sawant and other council members called on the mayor to resign over what they called the Police Department’s militaristic response to protests. Durkan has said she will not resign.</p><p>___</p><p>Associated Press photographer Ted Warren contributed to this report. </p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/onGbcz-5cOfz3fztK8AGmbhxrRE=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/I74GOAERWJBMDONLB4MWOLIFMI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Seattle Police, at right, look on as Department of Transportation workers remove barricades at the intersection of 10th Ave. and Pine St., Tuesday, June 30, 2020 at the CHOP (Capitol Hill Occupied Protest) zone in Seattle. Protesters quickly moved couches, trash cans and other materials in to replace the cleared barricades. The area has been occupied by protesters since Seattle Police pulled back from their East Precinct building following violent clashes with demonstrators earlier in the month. (AP Photo/Ted S. Warren)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ted S. Warren]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/KnwruEMnVgpH525x7R2RCR_PdW4=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/3N6IVYMBANGIFPEHGOIQ2X6YMY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A cyclist rides past what remains of makeshift barricades that were put in place by protesters at the intersection of 10th Ave. and Pine St., Tuesday, June 30, 2020 after Seattle Department of Transportation workers removed concrete barricades from the intersection at the CHOP (Capitol Hill Occupied Protest) zone in Seattle. The area has been occupied by protesters since Seattle Police pulled back from their East Precinct building following violent clashes with demonstrators earlier in the month. (AP Photo/Ted S. Warren)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ted S. Warren]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/RbUL7M-dj72iJSyCGY1_p1XC8AI=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/EF2LXHTGFRED3PWADMJH5NHXOI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Rick Hearns, part of the volunteer security team at the CHOP (Capitol Hill Occupied Protest) zone, is shown with a handgun in the waistband of his pants, and personal protection spray and a mobile phone in his pockets, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, as he stands outside the Seattle Police Department East Precinct building, which police abandoned earlier in the month after clashes with protesters. (AP Photo/Ted S. Warren)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ted S. Warren]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/IBu-B7Px3_gZyV6UYaMqshGZXx8=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/3XMYREGJQVBXRPVURMXG5ZFFYQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Cement barricades are fortified with chunks of concrete and tarps in front of the Seattle Police Department East Precinct building, Tuesday, June 30, 2020 at the CHOP (Capitol Hill Occupied Protest) zone in Seattle. Earlier Tuesday, Seattle Department of Transportation workers removed barricades two blocks away at the intersection of 10th Ave. and Pine St. The area has been occupied by protesters since Seattle Police pulled back from their East Precinct building following violent clashes with demonstrators earlier in the month. (AP Photo/Ted S. Warren)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ted S. Warren]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/XRBpg6GUXh2S2o3RbLxJv76OvkU=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/F6PADIWIYVCKJCQC4J75AK4HSU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A sign that indicates Cal Anderson Park will be closed at noon lies in the street, Tuesday, June 30, 2020 at the CHOP (Capitol Hill Occupied Protest) zone in Seattle. Earlier in the day, workers removed concrete barricades at one intersection, but protesters quickly moved couches, trash cans and other materials to replace the barricades. The area has been occupied by protesters since Seattle Police pulled back from their East Precinct building following violent clashes with demonstrators earlier in the month. (AP Photo/Ted S. Warren)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ted S. Warren]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/azU37ienq2Yd7T1rzFIsZSIFrFg=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/E4PTNP6DQNHNPNPJ7JUE7DTWVY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Seattle Department of Transportation workers remove barricades at the intersection of 10th Ave. and Pine St., Tuesday, June 30, 2020 at the CHOP (Capitol Hill Occupied Protest) zone in Seattle. Protesters quickly moved couches, trash cans and other materials in to replace the cleared barricades. The area has been occupied by protesters since Seattle Police pulled back from their East Precinct building following violent clashes with demonstrators earlier in the month. (AP Photo/Ted S. Warren)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ted S. Warren]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/rjVm1NP2bf3opElvqU8QSqQe_Tc=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/Z7PNRF5JENBTDKBOBPPPT2K3QQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters move items in place to block the street after Seattle Department of Transportation workers removed concrete barricades at the intersection of 10th Ave. and Pine St., Tuesday, June 30, 2020 at the CHOP (Capitol Hill Occupied Protest) zone in Seattle. The area has been occupied by protesters since Seattle Police pulled back from their East Precinct building following violent clashes with demonstrators earlier in the month. (AP Photo/Ted S. Warren)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ted S. Warren]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/a0hEBQjl9zthsIz8Ugz4nfbej5E=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/Y5BTEYSTTBAANCQVZWP3NZLUAI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A protester raises his fist as he wears a Guy Fawkes mask near the Seattle Police Department East Precinct building, Tuesday, June 30, 2020 at the CHOP (Capitol Hill Occupied Protest) zone in Seattle. Earlier Tuesday, Seattle Department of Transportation workers removed barricades at the intersection of 10th Ave. and Pine St., but protesters quickly moved couches, trash cans and other materials in to replace them. The area has been occupied by protesters since Seattle Police pulled back from their East Precinct building following violent clashes with demonstrators earlier in the month. (AP Photo/Ted S. Warren)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ted S. Warren]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/gMD-GG5DoeA2mu9O5b84SZQooBg=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/Q64L6J2UO5HSXGRTPNSQWFXS3I.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters stand on barricades a block away as Seattle Department of Transportation workers remove other barricades at the intersection of 10th Ave. and Pine St., Tuesday, June 30, 2020 at the CHOP (Capitol Hill Occupied Protest) zone in Seattle. Protesters quickly moved couches, trash cans and other materials in to replace the cleared barricades. The area has been occupied by protesters since Seattle Police pulled back from their East Precinct building following violent clashes with demonstrators earlier in the month. (AP Photo/Ted S. Warren)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ted S. Warren]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/8hlDvAosmxk6u5x4ETZZhYjvebY=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/OGKFRKQ7O5AGPK7JDZMSU6M4ZQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A sign on the street reads "Welcome to the CHOP" as protesters stand near barricades, Tuesday, June 30, 2020 at the CHOP (Capitol Hill Occupied Protest) zone in Seattle. Seattle Department of Transportation workers removed barricades about a block away Tuesday at the intersection of 10th Ave. and Pine St., but protesters quickly moved couches, trash cans and other materials in to replace the cleared barricades. The area has been occupied by protesters since Seattle Police pulled back from their East Precinct building following violent clashes with demonstrators earlier in the month. (AP Photo/Ted S. Warren)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ted S. Warren]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/VebCUisYnDsfE1VER2iXx7Yfx-E=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/FQDGJXKI4FHJRHZYMNVXSVZUHA.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters move a couch and other items to replace concrete barricades cleared by Seattle Department of Transportation workers at the intersection of 10th Ave. and Pine St., Tuesday, June 30, 2020 at the CHOP (Capitol Hill Occupied Protest) zone in Seattle. The area has been occupied by protesters since Seattle Police pulled back from their East Precinct building following violent clashes with demonstrators earlier in the month. (AP Photo/Ted S. Warren)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ted S. Warren]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/5Z6IVknnAPLfQ7_95zxLzD1olDE=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/FJRWCO6V6FEBTOHGYE3WH6TMRI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A protester moves a recycling container next to a sign listing demands after Seattle Department of Transportation workers removed concrete barricades at the intersection of 10th Ave. and Pine St., Tuesday, June 30, 2020 at the CHOP (Capitol Hill Occupied Protest) zone in Seattle. The area has been occupied by protesters since Seattle Police pulled back from their East Precinct building following violent clashes with demonstrators earlier in the month. (AP Photo/Ted S. Warren)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ted S. Warren]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/ReQL77SG7re7gHCWR0HzTgmY-XI=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/NT7EGGLMFNCH7O6YHR5O7ECBV4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A truck is loaded with concrete barricades after Seattle Department of Transportation workers removed them at the intersection of 10th Ave. and Pine St., Tuesday, June 30, 2020 at the CHOP (Capitol Hill Occupied Protest) zone in Seattle. Protesters quickly moved couches, trash cans and other materials in to replace the cleared barricades. The area has been occupied by protesters since Seattle Police pulled back from their East Precinct building following violent clashes with demonstrators earlier in the month. (AP Photo/Ted S. Warren)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ted S. Warren]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Officers put on leave over photos tied to Elijah McClain</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/national/2020/06/30/officers-put-on-leave-over-photos-tied-to-elijah-mcclain/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/national/2020/06/30/officers-put-on-leave-over-photos-tied-to-elijah-mcclain/</guid><dc:creator>Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:01:39 +0000</pubDate><description>Suburban Denver police say multiple officers are on paid leave during an investigation into photos that emerged of them near where Elijah McClain died last summer.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Multiple police officers in suburban Denver have been placed on paid leave during an investigation into photos that emerged of them near where Elijah McClain died last summer after three white officers stopped the Black man as he walked down the street and one put him into a chokehold. </p><p>Meanwhile, federal authorities announced Tuesday that they have been reviewing McClain's death to see if a civil rights investigation is warranted and will also look at whether one is needed in the case of the photos. </p><p>In a joint statement, the Colorado U.S. Attorney's Office, the U.S. Justice Department's Civil Rights Division and the FBI said the review began last year and was ongoing. The Justice Department usually does not comment on investigations until they are complete, but the announcement noted that “there are specific cases in which doing so is warranted if such information is in the best interest of the public and public safety."</p><p>The interim police chief of the city of Aurora, Vanessa Wilson, announced the internal police investigation into the photos Monday night. In a statement, she said the suspended officers were “depicted in photographs near the site where Elijah McClain died.” She did not provide more details about what the images show or how many officers were on leave. </p><p>The two photos were taken near where police stopped the 23-year-old on Aug. 24, 2019, as they responded to a report of a suspicious person walking down the street wearing a face mask, said Officer Matthew Longshore, an Aurora police spokesman. The pictures were not taken during the fatal run-in, Longshore said.</p><p>McClain’s death generated new attention after the death of George Floyd stirred worldwide protests over racial injustice and police brutality. Floyd died on May 25 after a white Minneapolis police officer pressed his knee into the handcuffed Black man's neck for nearly eight minutes.</p><p>In McClain's case, police body-camera video shows an Aurora officer getting out of his car, approaching McClain and saying, “Stop right there. Stop. Stop. ... I have a right to stop you because you’re being suspicious.”</p><p>In the video, the officer turns McClain around and repeats, “Stop tensing up.” As McClain tries to escape the officer’s grip, the officer says, “Relax, or I’m going to have to change this situation.”</p><p>As other officers join to restrain McClain, he begs them to let go and says, “You guys started to arrest me, and I was stopping my music to listen.”</p><p>Aurora police have said McClain refused to stop walking and fought back when officers tried to take him into custody. The officers used a chokehold that cuts off blood to the brain — a tactic recently banned in several places following Floyd’s death. </p><p>In the video, McClain tells officers: “Let go of me. I am an introvert. Please respect the boundaries that I am speaking.”</p><p>Paramedics administered 500 milligrams of a sedative to calm him down, police have said. He was on the ground for 15 minutes as several officers and paramedics stood by. McClain, a massage therapist and self-taught violinist, suffered cardiac arrest and was later declared brain dead and taken off life support.</p><p>A forensic pathologist could not determine what exactly led to his death but said physical exertion during the confrontation likely contributed. </p><p>An officer reported the photos to the department's internal affairs division Thursday. Wilson said she learned of the investigation that day and ordered investigators to make it their top priority.</p><p>The investigation was completed Monday and the results, including the photos, will be made public after police officials give a review and Wilson makes a decision on how to respond, Longshore said. The chief's decision could be appealed by the officers under investigation, which would delay the results being released, he said. </p><p>McClain's family said the photos were a “new low” for the department.</p><p>“This is a department where officers tackled an innocent young black man for no reason, inflicted outrageous force — including two carotid chokeholds — for fifteen minutes as he pled for his life, joked when he vomited, and threatened to sic a dog on him for not lying still enough as he was dying,” the family said in a statement. </p><p>The three officers who stopped McClain did not face any criminal charges after an investigation by the district attorney, but Democratic Gov. Jared Polis directed Colorado Attorney General Phil Weiser last week to reopen the investigation and possibly prosecute them.</p><p>Police have been criticized for wearing riot gear and using pepper spray against some people at a protest Saturday over McClain's death, which included a violin vigil, but have denied allegations of using tear gas. Wilson defended her officers' response to what she described as a group of agitators at an otherwise peaceful protest.</p><p>“Who didn't do it the right way were those agitators who were arming themselves, that were putting on helmets and gas masks and throwing rocks at my officers,” Wilson <a href="https://www.9news.com/article/news/local/local-politics/qa-apd-interim-chief-stands-behind-police-response-to-weekend-protesters/73-cffac9c9-a864-4dc9-aa9a-54b6886899ef">told</a> KUSA-TV. </p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/h7w1CfTYUlH8ft_XFCAv5OP3T4g=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/VELE6HOGGVBEJEFI657CWFCDJY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this June 27, 2020, file photo, demonstrators carry a giant placard during a rally and march over the death of 23-year-old Elijah McClain outside the police department in Aurora, Colo. Multiple suburban Denver police officers have been placed on paid administrative leave amid an investigation into photos of them related to the case of a Black man who died last summer after he was stopped and restrained, police said Monday, June 29, 2020. The interim police chief of the city of Aurora, Vanessa Wilson, said in a statement that the suspended officers were "depicted in photographs near the site where Elijah McClain died." But her statement did not provide more details about what the images show. (AP Photo/David Zalubowski, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[David Zalubowski]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/iVjq7cvWV75FP46zbaSRvoYdaGw=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/3WUP77X75VEELFSC5TSIKGGMB4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this June 2, 2020, file photo, interim Aurora Police Chief Vanessa Wilson and Jay B. confer as protesters march north on South Chambers Road during a peaceful protest against police brutality following the death of George Floyd in Aurora, Colo. Multiple suburban Denver police officers have been placed on paid administrative leave amid an investigation into photos of them related to the case of a Black man who died last summer after he was stopped and restrained, police said Monday, June 29. Wilson said in a statement that the suspended officers were "depicted in photographs near the site where Elijah McClain died." But her statement did not provide more details about what the images show. (Philip B. Poston/The Aurora Sentinel via AP, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Philip B. Poston]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/nyHXOq9Nf1m_EPHZzLJFivYWCMg=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/DAY54GORSFBIPGTLR2KK3DK65M.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this June 27, 2020, file photo, Sheneen McClain speaks during a rally and march over the death of her 23-year-old son, Elijah McClain, outside the police department in Aurora, Colo. Multiple suburban Denver police officers have been placed on paid administrative leave amid an investigation into photos of them related to the case of a Black man who died last summer after he was stopped and restrained, police said Monday, June 29, 2020. The interim police chief of the city of Aurora, Vanessa Wilson, said in a statement that the suspended officers were "depicted in photographs near the site where Elijah McClain died." But her statement did not provide more details about what the images show. (AP Photo/David Zalubowski, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[David Zalubowski]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Pf8I-F6-VIKXfAzCcCSF4CWjiVQ=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/YNWZDFGN3BDS3AKX3QSRHYNLGA.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A placard is displayed on a bicycle during a rally and march over the death of 23-year-old Elijah McClain, Saturday, June 27, 2020, outside the police department in Aurora, Colo. McClain died in late August 2019, after he was stopped while walking to his apartment by three Aurora Police Department officers. (AP Photo/David Zalubowski)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[David Zalubowski]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/ihYVFQd9KJNrWGDH-yLKa6BqnQE=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/E6AW45VXIFEJ7IAKPG5E2EY24U.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Officers in riot gear guard the police department Saturday, June 27, 2020, in Aurora, Colo., during a rally and march over the death of Elijah McClain. McClain was a 23-year-old Black man put into a chokehold by police last year. He suffered cardiac arrest on the way to the hospital and was later declared brain dead and removed from life support. (AP Photo/David Zalubowski)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[David Zalubowski]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Council leader: Plan to cut $1B from NYPD expected to pass</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/national/2020/06/30/nyc-budget-vote-looms-as-protests-push-for-cuts-to-police/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/national/2020/06/30/nyc-budget-vote-looms-as-protests-push-for-cuts-to-police/</guid><dc:creator>Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:28:20 +0000</pubDate><description>New York City lawmakers are holding a high-stakes debate on the city budget as activists demand a $1 billion shift from policing to social services and the city grapples with multibillion-dollar losses because of the coronavirus pandemic.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New York City lawmakers were expected Tuesday to approve shifting $1 billion from policing to education and social services in the coming year, acknowledging protesters' demands to cut police spending — but falling short of what activists sought.</p><p>City Council members were due to debate and vote on the plan Tuesday night, with time running short ahead of the budget year that begins Wednesday. Mayor Bill de Blasio supports the $88.2 billion spending plan and Council Speaker Corey Johnson said he was confident it would pass the council, but he expected a lot of “no” votes from members who want to cut more from police.</p><p>The vote comes at an extraordinary moment when the nation's biggest city is grappling with a $9 billion revenue loss due to the coronavirus pandemic and simultaneously with pressure to cut back on policing and invest more in community and social programs.</p><p>Protesters have been <a href="https://apnews.com/14b30e7c03e1d0ee1b8a1604eaa2f923">camped outside City Hall</a>, insisting that the city slash $1 billion from the New York Police Department’s budget amid a nationwide campaign to “defund” police — a movement animated by outrage over the deaths of George Floyd and other Black Americans at the hands of police.</p><p>The proposal did little to assuage the demonstrators. Many said they intended to stay outside City Hall indefinitely.</p><p>“We are being gaslit," said activist Jawanza James Williams. “This movement is about so much more than the $1 billion, and this means they don’t understand what we’re saying.”</p><p>Activists say the budget needs to make a substantial, not symbolic, difference in advancing racial justice and curbing the size and power of the nation's largest police force.</p><p>Five years ago, the City Council — then as now, overwhelmingly Democratic — added nearly 1,300 additional officers to the NYPD. Now, Johnson has said he was wrong to support the expansion, and he lamented Tuesday that he had been unable to negotiate a bigger police budget cut.</p><p>“I am disappointed,” Johnson said at a news conference. “I did my best."</p><p>Council budget leaders said they needed to balance calls to cut policing with residents' concerns about safety.</p><p>“Many in my community have supported police and want police. They just want families and young people to be treated fairly,” said Councilwoman Vanessa Gibson, who represents a Bronx district where over half of residents are Hispanic and about 40% are Black. Gibson said she'd met Tuesday with relatives of a Bronx 17-year-old who was shot and killed Sunday, days after his high school graduation.</p><p>“I don’t want anyone to misunderstand and think that we don’t care and that we have not been working our behinds off to get to a place of equity," while ensuring communities "are not left behind with crime, violence, illegal guns in our communities, no programs, no activities, and no hope for a better tomorrow," Gibson said.</p><p>But some other members said the budget proposal didn't dig deep enough into police spending. Councilman Brad Lander, who planned to vote no, called it “more budget-dancing than meaningful reductions.” </p><p>Cuts would come from canceling a nearly 1,200-person police recruiting class set for next month — though another class in October is scheduled to go forward — as well as halving overtime spending, redeploying officers from administrative functions to patrol and ending police responsibility for school crossing guards and homeless outreach.</p><p>The police department also would give up control over public school security, which the NYPD took over from the Department of Education in 1998. The city has about 5,300 civilian school safety agents. De Blasio said details were being worked out, but the Education Department would train the agents.</p><p>Money would go instead to education, social services in communities hit hard by the virus, and summer youth programs for over 100,000 people.</p><p>Other cuts are being made to the NYPD’s capital budget, including cancelling plans to build a new police precinct in Queens and instead using the money to build a community center. </p><p>“We all understand that we have to answer the concerns of this moment, that people want to see our society progress,” de Blasio, a Democrat, said at a news conference. He vowed the changes would not compromise public safety.</p><p>Police officials didn’t comment Tuesday. Commissioner Dermot Shea has said he was open to giving up school safety and other cuts, as long as the amount of officers on patrol doesn’t shrink.</p><p>The NYPD budget is now around $6 billion, plus several billion dollars more in shared city expenses such as pensions.</p><p>The new plan calls for an ambitious, nearly $300 million cut in police overtime. The department paid out $115 million in overtime just during recent protests over Floyd's May 25 death in Minneapolis.</p><p>The city budget totaled nearly $93 billion when passed last June. Before the virus hit, de Blasio proposed a more than $95 billion spending plan for the budget year that starts Wednesday.</p><p>___</p><p>Associated Press writer Jim Mustian contributed to this report.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Og6-RXqtPD_iSiK-XHJ9xvszeow=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/SOZBUN4IOVCSXGQNS5ME3XH5HM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A protester stands on the steps of a government building near an encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. City Council members were due to debate and vote Tuesday night on a plan to shift $1 billion from policing to education and social services, with time running short ahead of the fiscal year that begins Wednesday. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/dx4D0UVdqwk7ZO4prtxP30uiHA4=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/SACDK7YZPZCLPH2GO4TB2QIQXU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters learn defensive tactics during a demonstration at an encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. New York City lawmakers are holding a high-stakes debate on the city budget as activists demand a $1 billion shift from policing to social services and the city grapples with multibillion-dollar losses because of the coronavirus pandemic. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/HqQyXuP9_wtQSfEmVLsyCzLknwo=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/EFDTTLJ5ZZHNDFNTUX6U7BR26A.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters gather beside a subway station entrance at an encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. New York City lawmakers are holding a high-stakes debate on the city budget as activists demand a $1 billion shift from policing to social services and the city grapples with multibillion-dollar losses because of the coronavirus pandemic. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/LjGkZpE15emIBgsFFzBMaHmksfk=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/YDQF6K5TLJHLNBP7KGWPNPC42I.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Statues are defaced outside government buildings as protesters gather at an encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. New York City lawmakers are holding a high-stakes debate on the city budget as activists demand a $1 billion shift from policing to social services and the city grapples with multibillion-dollar losses because of the coronavirus pandemic. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/fVladpYCh6k_f551YPargf-HNHA=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/X3CD6VYJQZDPVDHYEFB4AJGR6A.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters gather at an encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. New York City lawmakers are holding a high-stakes debate on the city budget as activists demand a $1 billion shift from policing to social services and the city grapples with multibillion-dollar losses because of the coronavirus pandemic. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Jm17FHJ6UECBANhf7eq6DcYgrMw=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/BUS6VHHMONBDBPW3ZBFRW6YCNQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters gather under a sign reading "DEFUND" at an encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. City Council members were due to debate and vote Tuesday night on a plan to shift $1 billion from policing to education and social services, with time running short ahead of the fiscal year that begins Wednesday. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/oiR9fVPh65jD3VYkzv2puDLDC7A=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/46HTUEU2XZHLNHSTLU2VJWOGDM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters gather at an encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. City Council members were due to debate and vote Tuesday night on a plan to shift $1 billion from policing to education and social services, with time running short ahead of the fiscal year that begins Wednesday. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/xcfg7h6mhXVjrLRLebF5Ze48joE=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/AJGYW6BYHRBDTHNND67KOQVBZA.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters rest on the pavement outside a subway station entrance at an encampment outside City Hall, Friday, June 26, 2020, in New York. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/OMXBydlpuDkV53labbdkJEm8SME=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/2ZGE3FIJMFGDXLW45SRNWIYI4I.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters gather at an encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. New York City lawmakers are holding a high-stakes debate on the city budget as activists demand a $1 billion shift from policing to social services and the city grapples with multibillion-dollar losses because of the coronavirus pandemic. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/fzHrWDAfz4_GpCDLqs_XWLkw3GQ=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/LIEZO35LEJHGJGG6F4DPIO43FU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters gather at an encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. New York City lawmakers are holding a high-stakes debate on the city budget as activists demand a $1 billion shift from policing to social services and the city grapples with multibillion-dollar losses because of the coronavirus pandemic. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/pwuXOq51kxAutgTQKWeCEncws3c=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/5WU5KNRHKBH5ZO4JSIBZ3RCA4Q.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters gather at an encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. City Council members were due to debate and vote Tuesday night on a plan to shift $1 billion from policing to education and social services, with time running short ahead of the fiscal year that begins Wednesday. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/BBDzDaoMpxBbr1zXdTstmOsYzjc=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/4UZAAJNSW5GHBIMEMTPMUG2B64.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A display listing important dates in the Black American historical experience rests on the sidewalk at a protest encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. New York City lawmakers are holding a high-stakes debate on the city budget as activists demand a $1 billion shift from policing to social services and the city grapples with multibillion-dollar losses because of the coronavirus pandemic. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/8p6eorYM6nwFTudq06Vvdqu9Ib0=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/IJNYPITELJCKVPND6VECZO2WZU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters gather near an encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. New York City lawmakers are holding a high-stakes debate on the city budget as activists demand a $1 billion shift from policing to social services and the city grapples with multibillion-dollar losses because of the coronavirus pandemic. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/xn6Lf7ZQlPCEHfPrU3sQ4T8P35c=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/UKNHOMB64VFEFMU2MSUICQZHIU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters gather at an encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. New York City lawmakers are holding a high-stakes debate on the city budget as activists demand a $1 billion shift from policing to social services and the city grapples with multibillion-dollar losses because of the coronavirus pandemic. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/znw74pBbdigAINnDapXdMgZR59g=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/NTQR6JUPVBFSXG7GF7ZLWI66H4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters gather at an encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. New York City lawmakers are holding a high-stakes debate on the city budget as activists demand a $1 billion shift from policing to social services and the city grapples with multibillion-dollar losses because of the coronavirus pandemic. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/rXuISFGQh9CcdfmsWa5mzjZ4HWM=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/MM6QZS7JXVCNXBG3XGGBT2WWLE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Protesters block traffic as they gather at an encampment outside City Hall, Tuesday, June 30, 2020, in New York. New York City lawmakers are holding a high-stakes debate on the city budget as activists demand a $1 billion shift from policing to social services and the city grapples with multibillion-dollar losses because of the coronavirus pandemic. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Minchillo]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Regulators deny quick approval of new Great Lakes pipeline</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/national/2020/06/30/regulators-deny-quick-approval-of-new-great-lakes-pipeline/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/national/2020/06/30/regulators-deny-quick-approval-of-new-great-lakes-pipeline/</guid><dc:creator>John Flesher, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:13:59 +0000</pubDate><description>A Michigan regulatory agency has denied Enbridge's request for quick approval of its plan to put a replacement oil pipeline beneath a Great Lakes channel.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Michigan regulatory panel on Tuesday refused to grant quick permission to run a new oil pipeline beneath a channel that connects two of the Great Lakes, deciding instead to conduct a full review.</p><p>The state Public Service Commission's decision involved a proposed replacement for a segment of Enbridge's Line 5 that extends beneath the Straits of Mackinac, which links Lakes Huron and Michigan.</p><p>The Canadian energy transport company wants to replace dual pipelines that rest on the lake floor with a new pipe that would be placed in a 4-mile-long (6.4-kilometer-long) tunnel to be drilled in bedrock beneath the waterway.</p><p>Also Tuesday, a state judge heard arguments on whether to extend an order he issued June 25 to shut down the existing underwater segment after damage was discovered on a support piece at the lake bottom. Circuit Judge James Jamo promised to move quickly but made no immediate ruling.</p><p>That means <a href="https://apnews.com/6cc3ab37b6b8a06db1189ab62cedb318">Line 5 </a> — which carries 23 million gallons of crude oil and natural gas liquids daily between Superior, Wisconsin, and Sarnia, Ontario — will remain closed for now.</p><p>The 645-mile-long (1,038-kilometer-long) pipeline supplies refineries in Michigan, Ohio and Pennsylvania, as well as the Canadian provinces of Ontario and Quebec.</p><p>Enbridge said halting its flow even temporarily threatens fuel supplies in those areas, while the state of Michigan and environmental groups contend a major spill would do considerably worse economic damage.</p><p>“There is a serious risk of harm ... to many communities that potentially endangers the livelihood of many people and businesses as well as the natural resources,” Robert Reichel, representing state Attorney General Dana Nessel's office, said during the online court hearing.</p><p>Enbridge filed an application in April with the Public Service Commission to relocate the underwater section of Line 5 into the proposed tunnel.</p><p>The company asked the commission to approve the plan immediately, arguing that the agency in effect had already given permission by allowing the original Line 5 in 1953. But during an online meeting, the panel disagreed on a 3-0 vote.</p><p>Members concluded that the proposed tunnel pipe “differs substantially” from the twin pipes that were laid 67 years ago, requiring a new easement and a 99-year lease of public trust property.</p><p>The project "involves important factual, policy and legal issues best resolved through a proceeding that includes discovery, comprehensive testimony and evidence to provide a robust record,” the commission said in a statement. It scheduled a public hearing for Aug. 24.</p><p>Enbridge's argument that the commission didn't need to conduct an extensive study of the plan drew opposition from Nessel and numerous members of the public who submitted written comments and spoke during the meeting.</p><p>“Enbridge has already shown that they cannot be trusted,” said Sean McBrearty of the environmental coalition Oil &amp; Water Don't Mix. The public service commission, he said, “must thoroughly study this proposal and its potential impacts on our water and climate before making their final ruling.”</p><p>Enbridge spokesman Ryan Duffy said the company “respects the Michigan Public Service Commission's decision and we look forward to the next steps in the regulatory process.”</p><p>During the court hearing, Enbridge urged Jamo to let Line 5 reopen, saying state governments have no authority to regulate interstate pipelines. That power rests with the federal Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, which has concluded that one of the dual pipes can operate safely, attorney David Coburn said.</p><p>Nessel's case “is based on fear, not facts,” Coburn said. “And her fear is not warranted by the facts here.”</p><p>Enbridge agrees one of the underwater pipes should remain closed temporarily as it investigates why a support that holds it in place was recently found bent. It likely was struck by an anchor or other object pulled by a “moderate-sized vessel," attorney William Hassler said, adding that the pipe itself was not damaged.</p><p>The second pipe, which lies about 1,200 feet (366 meters) away, was not harmed and can carry oil safely, Hassler said.</p><p>Reichel countered that the easement Michigan granted Enbridge to place the pipelines on the bottom of the straits authorizes the state to ensure the company is operating them in a “reasonably prudent” manner.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/lCv1CW_Gxz2bfLiOAGxsXflJ_Ro=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/CKDJY2VSEJCD3I5DY6AUYEVFL4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[This June 2020 photo, shot from a television screen provided by the Michigan Department of Environment, Great Lakes, and Energy shows damage to anchor support EP-17-1 on the east leg of the Enbridge Line 5 pipeline within the Straits of Mackinac in Michigan. Enbridge who provided the photos to the state of Michigan, last week said an anchor support on the east leg of the pipeline, right, had shifted.  A Michigan regulatory panel refused Tuesday, June 30, 2020, to grant quick permission to run a new oil pipeline beneath a channel that connects two of the Great Lakes, deciding instead to conduct a full review. Enbridge filed an application in April with the Michigan Public Service Commission to relocate a segment of its Line 5 that extends beneath the Straits of Mackinac, which links Lakes Huron and Michigan. (Michigan Department of Environment, Great Lakes, and Energy via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Uncredited]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/nwt6rKQhUwkma7uHXgtvhrgGyt4=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/HI7AOT7FSRH3VJ3ATJXWZGHCHA.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this June 8, 2017, file photo, fresh nuts, bolts and fittings are ready to be added to the east leg of the Enbridge Line 5 pipeline near St. Ignace, Mich., as Enbridge prepares to test the east and west sides of the Line 5 pipeline under the Straits of Mackinac in Mackinaw City, Mich. A Michigan regulatory panel refused Tuesday, June 30, 2020, to grant quick permission to run a new oil pipeline beneath a channel that connects two of the Great Lakes, deciding instead to conduct a full review.Enbridge filed an application in April with the Michigan Public Service Commission to relocate a segment of its Line 5 that extends beneath the Straits of Mackinac, which links Lakes Huron and Michigan.(Dale G. Young/Detroit News via AP, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Dale G. Young]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>With a pen stroke, Mississippi drops Confederate-themed flag</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/national/2020/06/30/governor-to-retire-mississippis-confederate-themed-flag/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/national/2020/06/30/governor-to-retire-mississippis-confederate-themed-flag/</guid><dc:creator>Emily Wagster Pettus, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:09:09 +0000</pubDate><description>Mississippi Gov. Tate Reeves has announced a ceremony to sign a bill retiring the last state flag with the Confederate battle emblem.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With a stroke of the governor’s pen, Mississippi is retiring the last state flag in the U.S. with the Confederate battle emblem — a symbol that’s widely condemned as racist.</p><p>Republican Gov. Tate Reeves signed the historic <a href="http://billstatus.ls.state.ms.us/2020/pdf/history/HB/HB1796.xml"> bill</a> Tuesday at the Governor's Mansion, immediately removing official status for the 126-year-old banner that has been a source of division for generations.</p><p>“This is not a political moment to me but a solemn occasion to lead our Mississippi family to come together, to be reconciled and to move on," Reeves said on live TV just before the signing. “We are a resilient people defined by our hospitality. We are a people of great faith. Now, more than ever, we must lean on that faith, put our divisions behind us, and unite for a greater good.”</p><p>Mississippi has faced increasing pressure to change its flag since protests against racial injustice have focused attention on Confederate symbols in recent weeks.</p><p>A <a href="https://apnews.com/1d4969cb533fb6ab7fe381fb5855c256">broad coalition of legislators</a> on Sunday passed the landmark legislation to change the flag, capping a weekend of emotional debate and decades of effort by Black lawmakers and others who see the rebel emblem as a symbol of hatred.</p><p>Among the small group of dignitaries witnessing the bill signing were Reuben Anderson, who was the first African American justice on the Mississippi Supreme Court, serving from 1985 to 1991; Willie Simmons, a current state Transportation Commissioner who is the first African American elected to that job; and Reena Evers-Everette, daughter of civil rights icons Medgar and Myrlie Evers.</p><p>Medgar Evers, a Mississippi NAACP leader, was assassinated in the family's driveway in 1963. Myrlie Evers was national chairwoman of the NAACP in the mid-1990s and is still living. </p><p>“That Confederate symbol is not who Mississippi is now. It’s not what it was in 1894, either, inclusive of all Mississippians,” Evers-Everette said after the ceremony. "But now we’re going to a place of total inclusion and unity with our hearts along with our thoughts and in our actions.”</p><p>Reeves used several pens to sign the bill. As he completed the process, a cheer could be heard from people outside the Governor's Mansion who were watching the livestream broadcast on their phones. Reeves handed the pens to lawmakers and others who had worked on the issue.</p><p>The Confederate battle emblem has a red field topped by a blue X with 13 white stars. White supremacist legislators put it on the upper-left corner of the Mississippi flag in 1894, as white people were squelching political power that African Americans had gained after the Civil War.</p><p>Critics have said for generations that it’s wrong for a state where 38% of the people are Black to have a flag marked by the Confederacy, particularly since the Ku Klux Klan and other hate groups have used the symbol to promote racist agendas. </p><p>Mississippi voters chose to keep the flag in a 2001 statewide election, with supporters saying they saw it as a symbol of Southern heritage. But since then, a growing number of cities and all the state’s public universities have abandoned it.</p><p>Several Black legislators, and a few white ones, kept pushing for years to change it. After a white gunman who had posed with the Confederate flag killed Black worshipers at a South Carolina church in 2015, Mississippi’s Republican speaker of the House, Philip Gunn, said his religious faith compelled him to say that Mississippi must purge the symbol from its flag.</p><p>The issue was still broadly considered too volatile for legislators to touch, until the police custody death of an African American man in Minneapolis, George Floyd, set off weeks of sustained protests against racial injustice, followed by calls to take down Confederate symbols.</p><p>A groundswell of young activists, college athletes and leaders from business, religion, education and sports called on Mississippi to make this change, finally providing the momentum for legislators to vote.</p><p>Before the bill signing Tuesday, state employees raised and lowered several of the flags on a pole outside the Capitol. The secretary of state's office sells flags for $20 each, and a spokeswoman said there has been a recent increase in requests.</p><p>During recent news conferences, Reeves refused to say whether he thought the Confederate-themed flag properly represents present-day Mississippi, sticking to a position he ran on last year, when he promised that if the flag design was going to be reconsidered, it would be done in another statewide election.</p><p>Now, a commission will design a new flag that cannot include the Confederate symbol and must have the words “In God We Trust.” Voters will be asked to approve it in the Nov. 3 election. If they reject it, the commission will draft a different design using the same guidelines, to be sent to voters later.</p><p>Reeves said before signing over the flag's demise, “We are all Mississippians and we must all come together. What better way to do that than include ‘In God We Trust’ on our new state banner."</p><p>He added: “The people of Mississippi, black and white, and young and old, can be proud of a banner that puts our faith front and center. We can unite under it. We can move forward — together." </p><p>___</p><p>Follow Emily Wagster Pettus on Twitter: <a href="http://twitter.com/EWagsterPettus">http://twitter.com/EWagsterPettus</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/QyGoRsWO8-vUqcM1rMDtID3el-Q=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/YAWDXKRJ7ZAEPH7WAHP6ATCBL4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mississippi Republican Gov. Tate Reeves signs the bill retiring the last state flag in the United States with the Confederate battle emblem, at the Governor's Mansion in Jackson, Miss., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. Family members are at left. Applauding are, from fifth from left, Sen. Angela Turner Ford, D-West Point; House Speaker Philip Gunn, R-Clinton; Reuben Anderson, former Mississippi Supreme Court Justice; Lt. Gov. Delbert Hosemann; and Transportation Commissioner for the Central District Willie Simmons. (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis, Pool)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rogelio V. Solis]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/rzP7uSlpexDq5xFYSXGG8y7jpuU=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/LHTVO2IDWFD33ECEWMGFXVEG2A.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mississippi Republican Gov. Tate Reeves delivers a televised address prior to signing a bill retiring the last state flag in the United States with the Confederate battle emblem, at the Governor's Mansion in Jackson, Miss., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. The legislation passed both chambers of the Legislature on Sunday. (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis, Pool)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rogelio V. Solis]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/jx9CWOfwhRrR4VOCp1KIaogE828=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/EQQAGD7T45CT5OEN443BNNASOM.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mississippi Republican Gov. Tate Reeves delivers a televised address prior to signing a bill retiring the last state flag in the United States with the Confederate battle emblem, at the Governor's Mansion in Jackson, Miss., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis, Pool)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rogelio V. Solis]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/lBLbCqvme74eUhLLB1tp-OcvBpg=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/E4FDMJNXVRCJZIP2N4H6UD46ZI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mississippi Republican Gov. Tate Reeves delivers a televised address prior to signing a bill retiring the last state flag in the United States with the Confederate battle emblem, at the Governor's Mansion in Jackson, Miss., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis, Pool)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rogelio V. Solis]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/BCQACDK8vj9DCRwHZaUlYlWM_6E=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/GASSKEH2RNGH5FMKZ7HWLI3EAY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mississippi Department of Finance and Administration employees Willie Townsend, left, and Joe Brown, raise a couple of Mississippi state flags over the Capitol grounds in Jackson, Miss., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. The two men raised and lowered about 100 flags, provided by the Secretary of State's office, for people or organizations that purchased a state flag that flew over the grounds. Gov. Tate Reeves will sign a bill Tuesday evening retiring the last state flag with the Confederate battle emblem during a ceremony at the Governor's Mansion. Upon the governor signing the bill, the flag will lose its official status. (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rogelio V. Solis]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/bHr8Qkxfo4qDVyBACMRhBaIwpfs=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/2ZAQ6SXW3NFVRIFMD5TVOWIKTQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mississippi Department of Finance and Administration employees Willie Townsend, left, and Joe Brown, attach a couple of Mississippi state flags to the harness before raising them over the Capitol grounds in Jackson, Miss., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. The two men raised about 100 flags, provided by the Secretary of State's office, for people or organizations that purchased a state flag that flew over the grounds. Gov. Tate Reeves will sign a bill that evening retiring the last state flag with the Confederate battle emblem during a ceremony at the Governor's Mansion. Upon the governor signing the bill, the flag will lose its official status. (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rogelio V. Solis]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/FLUyzM45dObs8ZmT2CUWjA_C_5I=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/7CZTIZMBJZCFVJASG4WG5PRBKI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mississippi Department of Finance and Administration employees Willie Townsend, left, and Joe Brown, attach a Mississippi state flag to the harness before raising it over the Capitol grounds in Jackson, Miss., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. The two men raised about 100 flags, provided by the Secretary of State's office, for people or organizations that purchased a state flag that flew over the grounds. Gov. Tate Reeves will sign a bill Tuesday evening retiring the last state flag with the Confederate battle emblem during a ceremony at the Governor's Mansion. Upon the governor signing the bill, the flag will lose its official status. (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rogelio V. Solis]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/vIYv3XbNtVPFzVe88Wpc8pjt_NM=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/UKRHINBVYBHKLEU452GUTAR77M.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mississippi Gov. Tate Reeves signs the bill retiring the last state flag in the United States with the Confederate battle emblem, during a ceremony at the Governor's Mansion in Jackson, Miss., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. Upon the bill's signing, the flag lost its official status. (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis, Pool)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rogelio V. Solis]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/YaZCo6oDLZ-R1EitayOYx-2cOHw=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/TAPX45L3ZFBWDOWI24CPLJSOYU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mississippi Republican Gov. Tate Reeves signs the bill retiring the last state flag in the United States with the Confederate battle emblem, at the Governor's Mansion in Jackson, Miss., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. Standing behind Reeves are, from left, Sen. Angela Turner Ford, D-West Point; House Speaker Philip Gunn, R-Clinton; Reuben Anderson, former Mississippi Supreme Court Justice; Lt. Gov. Delbert Hosemann; and Transportation Commissioner for the Central District Willie Simmons. After Reeves signed the bill, the flag lost its official status. (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis, Pool)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rogelio V. Solis]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/DdveDuT6o_xuuOrALTiydzAkNvc=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/V2XPMYQWK5HQVLDF6Q42R3TDOQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mississippi Republican Gov. Tate Reeves signs the bill retiring the last state flag in the United States with the Confederate battle emblem, at the Governor's Mansion in Jackson, Miss., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. The signature removes official status for the banner that has been a source of division for generations. (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis, Pool)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rogelio V. Solis]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/xwNMLpsnGEilNeX28fsFil8SnqQ=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/7HEK7KAM4RHCVGDHSCC3KLQUM4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mississippi Republican Gov. Tate Reeves gathers the pens he used in signing the bill retiring the last state flag in the United States with the Confederate battle emblem, at the Governor's Mansion in Jackson, Miss., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. Applauding are, from left, Sen. Angela Turner Ford, D-West Point; House Speaker Philip Gunn, R-Clinton;, Reuben Anderson, former Mississippi Supreme Court Justice; Lt. Gov. Delbert Hosemann; and Transportation Commissioner for the Central District Willie Simmons, (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis, Pool)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rogelio V. Solis]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/TeceRfCEtwprv_RlqdrbfzaKjPw=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/64IFEG5TSNAFDCA2TV7IMMYOF4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mississippi Republican Gov. Tate Reeves, left, speaks with Reena Evers, daughter of the slain civil rights activist Medgar Evers and Myrlie Evers-Williams, after signing a bill to retire the last state flag in the United States with the Confederate battle emblem, at the Governor's Mansion in Jackson, Miss., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. With the bill's signature, the flag lost its official status. (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis, Pool)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rogelio V. Solis]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/RA-taipqjaxon_BbZfw8xjPnlEg=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/DR4W2KKSKNDPHAQEY325AKETTE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mississippi Gov. Tate Reeves delivers a televised address prior to signing a bill retiring the last state flag in the United States with the Confederate battle emblem, during a ceremony at the Governor's Mansion in Jackson, Miss., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. The legislation passed both chambers of the Legislature on Sunday. (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis, Pool)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rogelio V. Solis]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/W6vYW4vbd0ZHknXvwsvPPBB97rk=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/FBGGXOAI3BGRJANV3ORGA7Y7RQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mississippi Republican Gov. Tate Reeves delivers a televised address prior to signing a bill retiring the last state flag in the United States with the Confederate battle emblem, at the Governor's Mansion in Jackson, Miss., Tuesday, June 30, 2020. (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis, Pool)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Rogelio V. Solis]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Police say missing kids' mom helped keep their bodies hidden</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/national/2020/06/30/police-say-missing-kids-mom-helped-keep-their-bodies-hidden/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/national/2020/06/30/police-say-missing-kids-mom-helped-keep-their-bodies-hidden/</guid><dc:creator>Rebecca Boone, Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 23:43:31 +0000</pubDate><description>Prosecutors say the mother of two children who were found dead in rural Idaho months after they vanished had conspired with her new husband to hide or destroy the kids’ bodies.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prosecutors say the mother of two children who were found dead in rural Idaho months after they vanished in a bizarre case that captured worldwide attention had conspired with her new husband to hide or destroy the kids' bodies. </p><p>The new felony charges against Lori Vallow Daybell came late Monday, the latest twist in a case tied to the mysterious deaths of the couple's former spouses and their beliefs about zombies and the apocalypse that may have affected their actions. </p><p>A judge set Daybell’s bail at $1 million during her first court appearance on the new felony charges Tuesday. The judge asked if she understood the allegations and that if convicted she could be sentenced to up to 10 years behind bars. Daybell, who wiped her eyes occasionally with a tissue, answered “yes.” </p><p>Daybell is already charged with abandoning or deserting 7-year-old Joshua “JJ” Vallow and 17-year-old Tylee Ryan, but because police found their remains buried in her husband's yard, it's not clear if those allegations will stand. She's also charged with obstructing a police investigation, asking a friend to lie to police on her behalf and contempt of court for failing to follow a order to produce the kids.</p><p>Daybell’s attorney has indicated that she intends to defend herself against the charges, but she hasn't yet had a chance to enter a plea.</p><p>Her husband, Chad Daybell, was charged this month with concealing evidence by destroying or hiding the children's bodies. He's pleaded not guilty. </p><p>Prosecutors are using the same behavior alleged in Lori Daybell’s older charges to support the conspiracy charge, saying she aided Chad Daybell’s efforts to hide the bodies by asking her friend to lie to police about JJ’s whereabouts and lying to police herself when she told them JJ was in Arizona and Tylee was attending college. </p><p>Authorities have not yet said how exactly the children died or who caused their deaths. Court documents suggest JJ was buried in a pet cemetery on Chad Daybell's property and that Tylee's remains were dismembered and burned. Investigators found the remains by tracking the movements of Lori Daybell's brother, Alex Cox, using cellphone data. Authorities searched Chad Daybell's home again Monday but haven't said what they were looking for. </p><p>Cox is also dead, succumbing to an apparent blood clot in his lung at his home in Arizona last December. In the newest court documents filed in Lori Daybell's conspiracy case, Rexburg police Lt. Ron Ball wrote that Cox also was involved in the conspiracy to hide the kids' remains by taking JJ to Chad Daybell's property the day the child was buried and by later telling police the boy was visiting his grandparents in Louisiana. </p><p>The documents also reference claims that the Daybells believed dark spirits, or “zombies,” would possess people. Lori Daybell reportedly told her friend Melanie Gibb at different times in 2019 that both JJ and Tylee had become zombies. Gibb said the Daybells also believed the only way to rid a person of a dark spirit was by killing them so the person could be at rest in the afterlife.</p><p>“Gibb was informed by Vallow that when a person became a ‘zombie,’ their original spirit left their body and entered ‘limbo’ and is trapped and cannot progress to ‘paradise,’” Ball wrote in an affidavit. “Vallow then informed Gibb that for the person’s original spirit to be freed from limbo the person’s physical body had to die. Despite the teaching that a physical body needed to die, Gibb reports she was never told by Vallow or Daybell that they planned to carry out a physical killing themselves.”</p><p>The complex case began last summer with Cox shooting and killing Lori's estranged husband, Charles Vallow, in suburban Phoenix in what he asserted was self-defense. Vallow was seeking a divorce, saying Lori believed she had become a god-like figure who was responsible for ushering in the biblical end times. </p><p>Shortly after Vallow’s death, Lori and the children moved to Idaho, where Chad Daybell lived. He ran a small publishing company, putting out many fiction books he wrote about apocalyptic scenarios loosely based on the theology of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. He also recorded podcasts about preparing for the apocalypse, and friends said he claimed to be able to receive visions from “beyond the veil.”</p><p>He had been married to Tammy Daybell, who died in her sleep last October of what her obituary said were natural causes. Authorities grew suspicious when Chad Daybell married Lori just two weeks later, and they had Tammy Daybell’s body exhumed in Utah in December. The results of that autopsy have not been released.</p><p>Police began searching for Tylee and JJ in November after relatives raised concerns. Police say the Daybells lied to investigators about the children’s whereabouts before quietly leaving Idaho. They were found in Hawaii months later.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Clh-XnzfscG6zqzomKqcZVNYuB8=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/KGJYOSED5NAR7H555LEQ2G7E3U.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this March 6, 2020, file photo, Lori Vallow Daybell glances at the camera during her hearing, with her defense attorney, Edwina Elcox, right, in Rexburg, Idaho. Prosecutors say the mother of two children who were found dead in rural Idaho months after they vanished in a bizarre case that captured worldwide attention had conspired with her new husband to hide or destroy the kids' bodies. The new felony charges against Lori Vallow Daybell came late Monday, June 29, 2020, the latest twist in a case tied to the mysterious deaths of both of the couple's former spouses and their beliefs about zombies and the apocalypse. (John Roark/The Idaho Post-Register via AP, Pool, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Roark]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/WNJTA2vY9C43m9niXfXChfaN0cA=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/6JSIWYKRJBDR7MSA25FMJ4OJ6I.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this June 11, 2020, file photo, a boy looks at a memorial for Tylee Ryan, 17, and Joshua "JJ" Vallow, 7, at Porter Park in Rexburg, Idaho. Prosecutors say the mother of the two children who were found dead in rural Idaho months after they vanished had conspired with her new husband to hide or destroy the kids bodies. The new felony charges against Lori Vallow Daybell came late Monday, June 29. (John Roark/The Idaho Post-Register via AP, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Roark]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/0at-5HRaEbc6tyrAaZ1YRZVNYZc=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/6DWLPDPGVZA2ZO2F5MCKSXYFMU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - In this Tuesday, June 9, 2020, file aerial photo, investigators search for human remains at Chad Daybell's residence in the 200 block of 1900 east, in Salem, Idaho. Court documents say authorities used cellphone information from the now-deceased uncle of two missing Idaho children to find the youths' bodies on Daybell's rural property. Daybell and the children's mother, Lori Vallow Daybell, are in custody. (John Roark/The Idaho Post-Register via AP, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[John Roark]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/jofGqEpvafNJJj2NyawZfMqBU2o=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/IPZIWMPM2VAB5GANKAC26ZR5NE.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[FILE - This file booking photo provided by the Rexburg (Idaho) Police Department shows Chad Daybell, who was arrested June 9, 2020. Daybell, of Idaho, who is charged with destroying evidence after police said the bodies of two missing kids were found on his Idaho property has pleaded not guilty. Daybell's attorney, John Prior, filed documents notifying the court of Daybell's not-guilty plea late last week. He said Daybell requested a preliminary hearing and a jury trial. (Rexburg Police Department via AP, File)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Uncredited]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>1 of 2 Oklahoma officers shot during traffic stop dies</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/national/2020/06/30/1-of-2-oklahoma-officers-shot-during-traffic-stop-dies/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/national/2020/06/30/1-of-2-oklahoma-officers-shot-during-traffic-stop-dies/</guid><dc:creator>Associated Press</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 23:14:58 +0000</pubDate><description>The police chief in Tulsa, Oklahoma, says one of the two officers who were shot during a traffic stop has died.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the two Tulsa, Oklahoma, police officers who were shot during a traffic stop has died, authorities said Tuesday.</p><p>Police Chief Wendell Franklin said Sgt. Craig Johnson died Tuesday. He said Johnson was shot multiple times during the Monday attack, including one shot that was “critical.”</p><p>Franklin described Johnson's death as a “tremendous loss” to the police department.</p><p>“His sacrifice will not go unremembered,” he said.</p><p>A patrol car at the division where the officers worked has been covered in flowers, balloons, American flags and handmade signs as a tribute.</p><p>Johnson and rookie officer Aurash Zarkeshan were shot at about 3:30 a.m. Monday during a traffic stop. The suspected gunman, 32-year-old David Anthony Ware, was arrested following a search that lasted more than seven hours.</p><p>The officers were trying to get Ware out of the vehicle, and one officer had already deployed a Taser and pepper spray in an attempt to remove him. Once out, Ware pulled a handgun and fired multiple rounds, Franklin said.</p><p>Zarkeshan had been on patrol for less than six weeks since graduating from the police academy in the spring, the chief said.</p><p>Johnson had joined Tulsa police in 2005 and was promoted to sergeant in 2015, Franklin said.</p><p>“Sgt. Johnson was a good man who made our lives better, who trained his fellow officers to be better,” said Tulsa Mayor G.T. Bynum.</p><p>Franklin said Johnson was survived by his wife, two young sons and parents. He said Johnson's family had decided to donate his organs.</p><p>A motive for the shooting was unclear. Tulsa police Capt. Richard Meulenberg said Ware had no known bias against the police.</p><p>While Ware was being stopped, police said, he called an “accomplice” who arrived in a separate vehicle and picked him up. Police said that man, Matthew Hall, was arrested later Tuesday in Broken Arrow.</p><p>Ware faces murder and weapons charges, and Hall a faces count of being an accessory murder and a related charge. Both are being held without bond at the Tulsa jail. Court records don’t list an attorney to speak for either of them.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/HZ9WODg8bAI7hO0rA_ccaiQ-vu0=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/W3XT4CEEGRG7XGKJ2X4M4OYIYQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Anna Hok, left, and Terrie Dyer embrace and pray at a makeshift memorial for Tulsa Police Officers Craig Johnson and Aurash Zarkeshan at Mingo Valley Division in Tulsa Tuesday, June 30, 2020. The officers were shot early Monday morning during a traffic stop.  (Mike Simons/Tulsa World via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Mike Simons]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/PJku21Gp4KY8jvB-cCH9K21Nzc4=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/MOKUVE7MLRCDDKMSFSRYASFEYA.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[This undated photo released by the Tulsa Police Department shows David Ware, who police say shot two Tulsa Police officers following a scuffle on Monday, June 29, 2020. Ware fled the scene on foot and police searching for him described him as armed and dangerous. (Tulsa Police Department via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Uncredited]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/eMcyodfqNFEjwkbTimenAq5qlqo=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/DD5E6R5JCVEK7PDX4IC7PX745Y.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Melanie Dickey, a registered nurse for over 40 years, places an item on a makeshift memorial for Tulsa Police Officers Craig Johnson and Aurash Zarkeshan at Mingo Valley Division Tuesday, June 30, 2020. The officers were shot early Monday morning during a traffic stop. (Mike Simons/Tulsa World via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Mike Simons]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/AFSb7UBA7pg2veu2x2SN1iiO7vE=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/M5CQV2SVBNCB3AKDP2B4SSXIGA.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Off duty Tulsa Police Officer Aaron Myers adjusts items on a makeshift memorial for Tulsa Police Officers Craig Johnson and Aurash Zarkeshan at Mingo Valley Division in Tulsa Tuesday, June 30, 2020. The officers were shot early Monday morning during a traffic stop. Myers works at the Mingo Valley Division. (Mike Simons/Tulsa World via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Mike Simons]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/e7KxTlT0Fh4cPkOFixm9cJKPi3E=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/VMFGOPWKHZDDHNYOED4EYJAMUA.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Terrie Dyer wipes a tear as she prays at a makeshift memorial for Tulsa Police Officers Craig Johnson and Aurash Zarkeshan at Mingo Valley Division Tuesday, June 30, 2020. The officers were shot early Monday morning during a traffic stop.  (Mike Simons/Tulsa World via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Mike Simons]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Zy1u6xLe5If7KuPUMW1l66syNyI=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/U5U2KWRSWJGFFNVQYRIWHG3YK4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Officers investigate the scene of a shooting where two Tulsa Police Officers were shot Monday, June 29, 2020, in in Tulsa, Okla. (Mike Simons/Tulsa World via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Mike Simons]]></media:credit></media:content><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/c2ZMju3ZfMgSdIgGnmhz0zG99fs=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/IWMADQ7FIRFDRMUHGB22ULRLIY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Tulsa police gather where two officers were shot near 21st Street and Memorial Drive in Tulsa, Okla., on Monday, June 29, 2020. (Matt Barnard/Tulsa World via AP)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Matt Barnard]]></media:credit></media:content></item></channel></rss>