<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"><channel><title>WPLG Local 10</title><link>https://www.local10.com</link><atom:link href="https://www.local10.com/arcio/rss/tags/heat/?size=10" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>WPLG Local 10 News Feed</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 01:58:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><ttl>1</ttl><sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod><sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency><item><title>Heat’s Derrick Jones tests positive for coronavirus, source confirms</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/25/heats-derrick-jones-tests-positive-for-coronavirus/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/06/25/heats-derrick-jones-tests-positive-for-coronavirus/</guid><dc:creator>David Selig</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 18:15:42 +0000</pubDate><description>Miami Heat forward Derrick Jones Jr. has tested positive for COVID-19, Local 10 Sports has confirmed with a source. The NBA began testing players for the coronavirus this week as it prepares to return to play late next month at Disney’s Wide World of Sports.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Miami Heat forward Derrick Jones Jr. has tested positive for COVID-19, Local 10 Sports has confirmed with a source.</p><p>The news was first reported by the Sun Sentinel and Miami Herald.</p><p>The NBA began testing players for the coronavirus this week as it prepares to return to play late next month at Disney’s Wide World of Sports complex near Orlando.</p><p>Jones, the reigning NBA slam dunk contest champion, still plans to play next month, according to the Associated Press.</p><p>The team has yet to comment.</p><p>Jones, 23, is averaging a career-best 8.9 points and 4.2 rebounds this season and enters free agency after this year.</p><p>A number of other NBA players have reportedly tested positive for COVID-19 this week, including the Denver Nuggets’ Nikola Jokic, Indiana Pacers’ Malcolm Brogdon and Sacramento Kings’ Buddy Hield, Jabari Parker and Alex Len.</p><p>League officials have expected that positive tests would be inevitable, and believed that starting a testing regimen now — roughly five weeks before games begin at Disney — will give players with positive results time to recover and get back with their teams before games start July 30.</p><p>The season resumes with 22 teams heading to Central Florida to conclude the regular season and then playoffs. The Heat have already clinched a playoff berth.</p><p>The NBA has been on hiatus since March 11, when Utah Jazz center Rudy Gobert tested positive for COVID-19.</p><p><i>Local 10 Sports Director Will Manso and the Associated Press contributed to this report.</i></p><p><a href="https://www.local10.com/account/newsletters/" target="_blank"><i><b>CLICK HERE</b></i></a><i><b> to get breaking news sent straight to your email inbox. </b></i></p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/ArSMai3LBcvHgJWvl9S0op52dOE=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/MKTGK5TMC5F4NEQGXHY3RDLKZU.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Miami Heat forward Derrick Jones Jr. has tested positive for COVID-19, reports say.]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Mark J. Terrill]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Heat hosting virtual town hall about racial injustice</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/19/heat-hosting-virtual-town-hall-about-racial-injustice/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/19/heat-hosting-virtual-town-hall-about-racial-injustice/</guid><dc:creator>David Lang</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 02:09:24 +0000</pubDate><description>The Miami Heat are joining the voices speaking out against racial injustice.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Miami Heat are hosting a virtual town hall on Juneteenth, the holiday celebrating the end of slavery in the United States.</p><p>On Thursday night, the Heat released a 4:43 second video on their social media platforms.</p><p>In it, players share their experiences and reactions to the racial injustice in the United States.</p><p>Jimmy Butler said, “I hear and talk a lot about fear.  In the sense that you may not make it home.  Your son may not make it home.  Your daughter may not make it home.”</p><p>Derrick Jones Jr. said, “I have children, 3 boys, just knowing that they have to grow up and seeing all the things that are going on right now, it’s just, it just breaks our hearts.”</p><p>Meyers Leonard said that recent events in the country have left him wondering: “Should I speak up?  What do I say?  How do I say it?”</p><p>Veteran Udonis Haslem said it’s his role to educate people on racism, injustice, and the importance of voting.</p><p>People are being encouraged to register on the Heat’s website <a href="http://www.miamiheat.com/" target="_blank">www.miamiheat.com</a>.</p><p>Space is limited for the town hall and will be given on a first come, first served basis.</p><p>The town hall will be at 4 p.m. Friday.</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/5RgY9352sMyRN8lF_oYqtMH8pXc=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/FVX4ZL4O3RCB7AH5LLTSVWQBPQ.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Somber evening at Miami Heat game as players, coaches remember Kobe Bryant]]></media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Heat guard Goran Dragic discusses resuming NBA season, playing in Orlando bubble</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/15/heat-guard-goran-dragic-discusses-resuming-nba-season-playing-in-orlando-bubble/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/15/heat-guard-goran-dragic-discusses-resuming-nba-season-playing-in-orlando-bubble/</guid><dc:creator>Will Manso</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 04:56:11 +0000</pubDate><description></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Heat guard Goran Dragic wants to finish the NBA season, but he also makes clear safety has to be the priority in the league’s return-to-play plan in Orlando.</p><p>“The main concern is safety,” Dragic explained during his appearance on Local 10 Sports Sunday.</p><p>Miami’s point guard also made it a point that he and his teammates are fine with the idea of playing in the bubble set up because they feel there’s unfinished business with this Heat team.</p><p>“We are basketball players, so we want to compete. As long as it’s gonna be safe and everything for everyone who’s gonna be in that bubble, then I’m okay with it,” Dragic said.</p><p>The team has been having zoom calls since the start of the pandemic, and now players have been going individually to the arena to practice.</p><p>Dragic described it as one player on each side of the court but never together.That could soon change with the move forward by the NBA to try and resume the season next month. </p><p>Dragic said he doesn’t think it’ll take too long for Heat players to find a rhythm because they played over 60 games with each other, and they’re ready to make a run.</p><p>“We have a lot of young guys who are not afraid. We have a nice mix of young guys and veterans. I think we have everything,” Dragic said.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Impressive mural of Udonis Haslem shows up in Wynwood on Heat star’s 40th birthday</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/09/impressive-mural-of-udonis-haslem-shows-up-in-wynwood-on-heat-stars-40th-birthday/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/09/impressive-mural-of-udonis-haslem-shows-up-in-wynwood-on-heat-stars-40th-birthday/</guid><dc:creator>David Dwork</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 19:34:52 +0000</pubDate><description>A beautiful mural has been painted in Miami's Wynwood neighborhood, dedicated to a homegrown South Florida sports hero on his birthday.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Throughout South Florida’s history, a way that many locals have expressed themselves, during both good times and bad, is through their art. </p><p>A beautiful mural has popped up in Miami’s Wynwood neighborhood, and it’s clearly dedicated to a homegrown sports hero on his birthday. </p><p>Miami Heat legend Udonis Haslem, who has become as known and beloved for his work off the court as for what he's done on it, turned 40 years old on Tuesday. </p><p>Local artist Disem decided to use his talents to honor Haslem on his special day. </p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Finally got a chance to see the great work by <a href="https://twitter.com/Disem305?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@disem305</a> of Udonis Haslem over in Wynwood.  It’s at 591 NW 27th St, if you’re around the area and want to check in out. <a href="https://t.co/TqW0vEstmn">pic.twitter.com/TqW0vEstmn</a></p>— Will Manso (@WillManso) <a href="https://twitter.com/WillManso/status/1270422416855105539?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 9, 2020</a></blockquote><p>Haslem has played his entire 17-year NBA career with the Heat; he and Dwayne Wade were rookies together in 2003. </p><p>A product of Miami High after growing up in Liberty City, Haslem’s local roots run about as deep as they could go. He has spent countless hours during the COVID-19 pandemic helping his fellow South Floridians and feeding families in need. </p><p>He’s also been involved in the community during the incredibly tense and racially charged times following the death of George Floyd at the hands of Minneapolis police.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">"There's got to be a better way. I stand here confused, torn, frustrated. I wasn't even supposed to be here. I just wanna be part of the solution." ~ <a href="https://twitter.com/ThisIsUD?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ThisIsUD</a> just now in front of Miami PD headquarters. <a href="https://t.co/tPewcHug0D">pic.twitter.com/tPewcHug0D</a></p>— David Dwork (@DavidDwork) <a href="https://twitter.com/DavidDwork/status/1267169053216514053?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 31, 2020</a></blockquote>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/1lvCmM9HvdVNqYdKbrHR3jD-iZI=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/OKO636YIWFCXTBRSGWZZF7DIXY.jpg"></media:content></item><item><title>South Florida’s professional sports teams speak out following George Floyd death, protests </title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/01/south-floridas-sports-teams-speak-out-following-george-floyd-death-protests/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/06/01/south-floridas-sports-teams-speak-out-following-george-floyd-death-protests/</guid><dc:creator>David Dwork</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 20:26:16 +0000</pubDate><description>South Floridians, like many others in regions across United States, have been holding protests following the death of George Floyd at the hands of Minneapolis police officers.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Floridians, like many others in regions across the United States, have been holding protests following the death of George Floyd at the hands of Minneapolis police officers.</p><p>Peaceful protests in Miami turned violent Saturday night, though officials believe the instigating parties may have been from out of state and specifically in town to start trouble.</p><p>Demonstrations continued Sunday evening, and were almost entirely peaceful; in one instance in Downtown Miami, protestors formed a human chain to stop others from breaking the windows of a CVS pharmacy.</p><p>Several statements have been released by South Florida’s sports teams and, in some cases, their respective owners over the past few days, and instead of trying to paraphrase those words, here they are as intended:</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Statement from Head Coach Brian Flores. <a href="https://t.co/dJOdHHSvNT">pic.twitter.com/dJOdHHSvNT</a></p>— Miami Dolphins (@MiamiDolphins) <a href="https://twitter.com/MiamiDolphins/status/1266472470871183361?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 29, 2020</a></blockquote><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="und"><a href="https://t.co/IX61igEIPO">pic.twitter.com/IX61igEIPO</a></p>— Miami HEAT (@MiamiHEAT) <a href="https://twitter.com/MiamiHEAT/status/1267467188799242242?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2020</a></blockquote><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="und"><a href="https://t.co/rObsemS29n">pic.twitter.com/rObsemS29n</a></p>— Miami Marlins (@Marlins) <a href="https://twitter.com/Marlins/status/1267488248626139137?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2020</a></blockquote><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="und"><a href="https://t.co/tyosRG9MYl">pic.twitter.com/tyosRG9MYl</a></p>— Inter Miami CF (@InterMiamiCF) <a href="https://twitter.com/InterMiamiCF/status/1267499934812643329?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2020</a></blockquote><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Dolphins head coach Brian Flores speaking this morning at the team’s meal distribution at Hard Rock stadium.  On leadership and bringing change.  (Via <a href="https://twitter.com/MiamiDolphins?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MiamiDolphins</a>) <a href="https://t.co/tl8XOnCfDz">pic.twitter.com/tl8XOnCfDz</a></p>— Will Manso (@WillManso) <a href="https://twitter.com/WillManso/status/1267501658206019584?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2020</a></blockquote><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">I am deeply impacted by the death of George Floyd and share the outrage over his senseless death. We have seen, for too long, how the ills of prejudice have sought to divide us. There is no room for racism and hatred in our world yet here we are. Let us stand together and condemn</p>— Jorge Mas (@Jorge__Mas) <a href="https://twitter.com/Jorge__Mas/status/1267503996694134787?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2020</a></blockquote><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="und"><a href="https://t.co/0qgVq8UYMr">pic.twitter.com/0qgVq8UYMr</a></p>— Florida Panthers (@FlaPanthers) <a href="https://twitter.com/FlaPanthers/status/1267531267664379904?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2020</a></blockquote>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/6lgM-dvGYX6MOPD4kDHwAHnGx2s=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/2XCFPFQR5VBQXLDPGVE2VS52G4.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[A protester of the death of George Floyd stands on his car as he and others demonstrate Sunday, May 31, 2020, in Miami. Floyd died May 25 after he was pinned at the neck by a Minneapolis police officer. (AP Photo/Wilfredo Lee)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Wilfredo Lee]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Miami Heat will honor 2020 graduates on big screen in front of arena</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/05/28/miami-heat-will-honor-2020-graduates-on-big-screen-in-front-of-arena/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/05/28/miami-heat-will-honor-2020-graduates-on-big-screen-in-front-of-arena/</guid><dc:creator>Will Manso</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 22:25:31 +0000</pubDate><description>The Miami Heat will recognize 2020 high school and college graduates from the state of Florida on the giant media mesh in front of AmericanAirlines Arena starting June 8.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How would it feel to be spotlighted on the same screen that has shown Dwyane Wade, LeBron James and other great Miami Heat players throughout the years?</p><p>The Heat are going to recognize 2020 high school and college graduates from the state of Florida on the giant media mesh in front of AmericanAirlines Arena starting June 8. </p><p>With physical commencement activities halted throughout the state, the team wants to give a special honor to the thousands of students graduating this year.</p><p>The deadline to submit photos of graduates is 11:59 p.m. on June 4. People can submit them to <a href="http://HEAT.com/SeniorSpotlight" target="_blank">HEAT.com/SeniorSpotlight</a>. </p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/Nx10ThaOvpDYHtfwAWROVXuenPo=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/KLGG4PKY25BW7DABZOLHGIQLQY.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Want to see your name in lights outside the Miami Heat's arena? It could happen if you're graduating in the Class of 2020.]]></media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Haslem looks to set example at individual Heat workouts</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/05/13/haslem-looks-to-set-example-at-individual-heat-workouts/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/05/13/haslem-looks-to-set-example-at-individual-heat-workouts/</guid><dc:creator>David Lang</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 18:58:29 +0000</pubDate><description>Heat captain Udonis Haslem is looking to take the lead once again.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Heat captain Udonis Haslem is looking to lead by example.</p><p>On Wednesday, Haslem helped hand out food in Miami, something the veteran has done several times during the pandemic.</p><p>After that, Haslem said he planned to work out at the American Airlines Arena.</p><p>Wednesday was the first day that Heat players were allowed to use the facility, if they followed strict social distancing protocols.</p><p>Haslem said, “I don’t have to be there. This is first. This is most important. Secondly, set an example for the younger guys on how we’re doing things now. Things are going to be a little different moving forward, but guys have to get their time in the gym.”</p><p>Haslem said he wants to set the tone for the young guys in how things will be done.</p><p>As for the negotiations between the NBA and the Players Association, the veteran said, “If we have to play with no fans than so be it. You put an alpha male in a competitive setting and they start to compete.”</p><p>Haslem added, “The aspect of being away from our families and all those different things like that, those are things we have to work through. There’s a mental health part of things. Can’t just stick guys in a cage, let them out to play and lock them back up again, don’t work like that either. I’m sure we’ll all work together to kinda figure it out."</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/GplJ2JBdPglBZERWUqM1vzGJeeY=/cloudfront-us-east-1.images.arcpublishing.com/gmg/JH5U7KNJXVCGTBAFLLSHMUNG5A.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Udonis Haslem talks to reporters on Wednesday]]></media:description></media:content></item><item><title>NBA, WNBA release team masks for sale for charities battling coronavirus pandemic</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/04/17/nba-wnba-release-team-masks-for-sale-for-charities-battling-coronavirus-pandemic/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/04/17/nba-wnba-release-team-masks-for-sale-for-charities-battling-coronavirus-pandemic/</guid><dc:creator>Will Manso</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 17:22:43 +0000</pubDate><description></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The NBA and WNBA have announced the sale of new cloth face coverings featuring team logos, and all proceeds will go to benefit Feeding America in the U.S. and Second Harvest of Canada.</p><p>The league says it wants fans to follow the CDC recommendation that cloth face coverings should be worn in public settings to help slow the spread of COVID-19.</p><p>The league has partnered with apparel company, Fanatics, to launch the project and have the masks on sale at <a href="http://NBAstore.com" target="_blank">NBAstore.com</a> and <a href="http://WNBAstore.com" target="_blank">WNBAstore.com</a>.</p><p>“As a global community, we can all play a role in reducing the impact of the <a href="https://www.local10.com/topic/coronavirus/" target="_blank">coronavirus</a> pandemic by following the CDC’s recommendation to cover our nose and mouth while in public,” said Kathy Behrens, NBA President, Social Responsibility and Player Programs. “Through this new product offering, NBA and WNBA fans can adhere to these guidelines while joining in the league’s efforts to aid those who have been directly affected by COVID-19.”</p><p>Offered in adult and youth sizes, designs are available individually or in packs of three and range from $14.99 for one specific type to a pack of three for $24.99.</p><p>Just last week, the Miami Heat used $100,000 worth of unsold jerseys and T-shirts to create over 7,000 masks to donate to frontline medical workers in South Florida.</p><p><iframe allowfullscreen="" data-original-height="2000" data-original-width="1280" frameborder="0" height="1500" mozallowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" src="    https://www.thinglink.com/card/1291074429790453762" type="text/html" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="960"></iframe></p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/ijILBC7H-XoQ_ZhECDndun_y6gQ=/arc-anglerfish-arc2-prod-gmg.s3.amazonaws.com/public/GSXNAED7LZA4LDO5UNJG2T37TI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Miami Heat face mask.]]></media:description></media:content></item><item><title>Dwyane Wade joins All-In Challenge to help feed those in need during coronavirus pandemic</title><link>https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/04/15/dwyane-wade-joins-all-in-challenge-to-help-feed-those-in-need-during-coronavirus-pandemic/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/sports/2020/04/15/dwyane-wade-joins-all-in-challenge-to-help-feed-those-in-need-during-coronavirus-pandemic/</guid><dc:creator>David Dwork</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 20:32:45 +0000</pubDate><description>Dwyane Wade is joining countless celebrities and athletes taking part in the All-In Challenge.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dwyane Wade is joining countless celebrities and athletes taking part in the All-In Challenge.</p><p>Wade joins Leonardo DiCaprio, Tom Brady, Ellen DeGeneres, Magic Johnson and so many others who are donating items and amazing experiences in order to feed those in need during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p><p>The All-In Challenge, which is operated by the All-In Challenge Foundation, benefits Meals on Wheels, No Kid Hungry and America's Food Fund.</p><p>The challenge, which offers once-in-a-lifetime experiences and items to fans, was the idea of Fanatics founder Michael Rubin.</p><p>Wade, who has become extremely passionate about wine and <a href="https://dwadecellars.com/" target="_blank">owns his own wine making company</a>, is offering a chance to join him during harvest time, which comes during October, in Napa Valley, and experience the entire process of creating wine, as well as hanging out, drinking the wine and enjoying a meal with the future Hall of Famer.</p><p>To check out the amazing items and experiences being offered, <a href="https://www.fanatics.com/all-in-challenge/x-23571039+z-9103744-3838082054" target="_blank">click here</a>.</p><p><iframe allowfullscreen="" data-original-height="2000" data-original-width="1280" frameborder="0" height="1500" mozallowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" src="    https://www.thinglink.com/card/1291074429790453762" type="text/html" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="960"></iframe>
</p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/tJseAjTyQH4qRiNov3FiShpshgw=/arc-anglerfish-arc2-prod-gmg.s3.amazonaws.com/public/P46VOV4HUNGLHOY4IK5OIIXA3M.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Wade Wine introduced in the US at Ocean Drive Magazine Celebrates its October Men's Issue with Dwyane Wade at Fontainebleau in Miami Beach October 9, 2015 in Miami Beach, Florida. (insert) Dwyane Wade attends Variety and Women In Film's 2017 pre-Emmy celebration at Gracias Madre on September 15, 2017 in West Hollywood, California.]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Jason LaVeris/FilmMagic Bobby Metelus/Getty Images]]></media:credit></media:content></item><item><title>Heat center Meyers Leonard using social media to interact with fans during coronavirus pandemic</title><link>https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/04/02/heat-center-meyers-leonard-using-social-media-to-interact-with-fans-during-coronavirus-pandemic/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.local10.com/news/local/2020/04/02/heat-center-meyers-leonard-using-social-media-to-interact-with-fans-during-coronavirus-pandemic/</guid><dc:creator>Will Manso</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 19:01:16 +0000</pubDate><description>Heat center Meyers Leonard and his wife, Elle, have always been very active on social media.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Heat center Meyers Leonard and his wife, Elle, have always been very active on social media. They normally aim to send positive messages and show how they’re just regular people, despite Meyers being an NBA player.</p><p>During the coronavirus pandemic, the Leonard’s have taken the accessibility a step further.</p><p>From making silly videos and tik tok's to even giving out their cell phone numbers for fans to text them while at home, the pair has kept busy. Meyers says he is flattered by the feedback they get from fans.</p><p>“I can truly say from the heart that my wife and I are ultimately trying to impact people in a positive way,” Leonard said. “It’s a very humbling compliment, by the way, that Elle and I are very relatable and people enjoy the content we put out.”</p><p>Meyers says he has concentrated on getting fans involved with playing ‘Call of Duty’ via twitch. “I have a passion for gaming and streaming on twitch,” Meyers explained. He’s done that to interact with fans and raise money for charity.</p><p>And he’s announced a big step in that charitable work. Leonard will be streaming for 24 hours this Sunday starting at 1 p.m. The event will be on ESPN Esports’ Twitch channel and is called the Hammer Classic. He will be donating $25,000, which will be matched by the NBPA. Other celebrities and athletes will take part.</p><p>The Leonard’s also have their own protein bar company, Level Foods, and they’re working hard behind the scenes to see it grow. Elle Leonard is the founder of the company.</p><p>Of course, Meyers says they’re keeping active and staying in shape. One of the Heat’s personal trainers has been coming to the house two to three times a week to work with Leonard, who had missed significant time with an ankle injury before the coronavirus league hiatus.</p><p>Leonard says he’s almost 100% and would absolutely play when and if the playoffs come.</p><p>As for a season returning? He has this message for fans.</p><p>“Everyone needs to understand that basketball will resume when the time is right. When we are certain that everyone can be protected and healthy,” Meyers said.</p><p>He makes clear, “the priority is everyone’s, whether it’s staff, the players, fans, whomever it is, the ultimate reality we all need to come to is that everyone needs to be safe first.”</p><p>For now, the Leonard’s will just keep interacting with fans and letting them know everyone is in this together, one laugh, trick shot or game at a time.</p><p><iframe allowfullscreen="" data-original-height="2000" data-original-width="1280" frameborder="0" height="1500" mozallowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" src="    https://www.thinglink.com/card/1291074429790453762" type="text/html" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="960"></iframe></p>]]></content:encoded><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.local10.com/resizer/N24RwTjXKynvW3e9s7POm7DdDGA=/arc-anglerfish-arc2-prod-gmg.s3.amazonaws.com/public/EP4Z2Q5SAJBUHADRH4ALOD6AHI.jpg"><media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Miami Heat forward Meyers Leonard (0) dunks on Dallas Mavericks forward Kristaps Porzingis (6) during the first half of an NBA basketball game in Dallas, Saturday, Dec 14, 2019. (AP Photo/Michael Ainsworth)]]></media:description><media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Michael Ainsworth]]></media:credit></media:content></item></channel></rss>